Krish Naik: Okay, sorry guys, so there was some Zoom issue that we have just found out, but I think now everybody's able to connect, right? Yes?
Krish Naik: Yeah?
Krish Naik: Yes, yes, yes. But don't worry, I think there were some Zoom issues, but, now it is fixed. I've also sent the link in the chat. Each and everything looks fine, right? No? Okay, just give me a quick yes, if everybody's able to…
Krish Naik: See my face, at least.
Krish Naik: Each and everything, right, over here.
Krish Naik: Anybody who's facing problem… anyhow, we have also done the induction session live in YouTube, so I don't think so you should be facing any problem.
Krish Naik: Yeah?
Krish Naik: Okay Just give me a quick yes?
Krish Naik: Yeah.
Krish Naik: So we'll just start in another 2 minutes. I think there were some link issues.
Krish Naik: Yep.
Krish Naik: Okay.
Krish Naik: So, how are you all, everyone?
Krish Naik: All good?
Krish Naik: Yep.
Krish Naik: Okay, so welcome to this amazing Ultimate Rag Bootcamp.
Krish Naik: And,
Krish Naik: You know, we… in this particular session, we are just going to have an indexing session to make you understand what all things we are going to learn, how we are going to learn, and how we are going to cover each and every topics.
Krish Naik: We also have, Paul with us. We'll be talking about our dashboard, we'll be talking… I'll be showing you each and everything in the dashboard itself.
Krish Naik: And, making sure to make you understand that how, you will be able to get the mails, how… when the recordings will be available, about the badge details, each and everything. Okay? Make sense, everybody?
Krish Naik: Yep.
Krish Naik: Okay.
Krish Naik: So, perfect, welcome to this new batch. Again, we're also live in YouTube for this induction session. We were facing some Zoom issues in the last moment, related to some links and all, but anyhow, I've updated in the group itself, okay? So, let me go ahead and share my screen quickly.
Krish Naik: And, first of all, we will start with our, you know, dashboard access, like, how does our dashboard looks like, each and everything. Okay?
Krish Naik: Okay, just give me a quick confirmation if you are able to see the dashboard quickly.
Krish Naik: Okay.
Krish Naik: Yep.
Krish Naik: If you are able to see my dashboard. Now, in your dashboard, first of all, I'll talk about which course we are talking about, so if you go to Krishnahag.in.
Krish Naik: So, this is the last bootcamp of 2025, so if you go ahead and see that, we are talking about this Ultimate RAG Bootcamp, wherein we are going to build
Krish Naik: traditional to agentic system with cloud deployment. Each and everything, we will talk about it over here, okay? And then,
Krish Naik: We will be talking about the syllabus, each and everything, what we have actually… what we are going to cover, okay? So if you just go ahead and click on enroll now, so here you will be able to get all this information, and now, here, you will be able to get the
Krish Naik: the entire syllabus. Okay, so this is the Ultimate RAC Bootcamp. Here, our learning objectives is basically mentioned. If you see step-by-step all the modules, this is going to probably take somewhere around 4 to 5 months to get completed.
Krish Naik: What all modules we are going to specifically cover? Foundation of RAG, Langchain.
Krish Naik: Traditional rack implementation, working with document parser, Llama Index will be a new module out there, advanced Llama Index Techniques, Haystack, you know, Lang Graph.
Krish Naik: Along with this, enhanced rack techniques.
Krish Naik: And then here you'll be able to see multi-model and structured RAG, conversational and contextual RAG, Agentic rag fundamentals, advanced agentic RAG, Production RAG systems, cutting-edge RAG techniques.
Krish Naik: Model context protocol, MCP, end-to-end projects, a lot of end-to-end projects we'll be discussing, along with the deployment, okay?
Krish Naik: So, according to this syllabus here, the clear idea is that our focus is more towards agentic AI with specific rags.
Krish Naik: RAG is one of the most popular techniques which we are going to specifically use. As we go ahead, because nowadays, every companies have started implementing RAG products, okay? And RAG products is really, really important for any kind of use case.
Krish Naik: So there are a couple of things that we are going to do with respect to RAG. One is focus on implementing agentic AI agentic AI applications.
Krish Naik: Along with that, what we are going to do is that we are going to cover different types of RAG. At the end of the day, we are going to develop something like a production-grade applications. Here, the focus is more on coding, more on developing production-grade applications. Agree, everyone? Does it make sense?
Krish Naik: Yes?
Krish Naik: I hope it makes sense.
Krish Naik: Okay? So this is the syllabus that we have, okay? Now, related to prerequisites, so for prerequisites, what we have is that you need to have good Python programming language knowledge, because
Krish Naik: Without Python programming language, it will be not possible to cover this particular batch. Python programming languages must, because there we'll be talking about modular coding, we'll be talking about advanced coding in Python.
Krish Naik: We'll be making sure that we use VS Code, we'll be talking about how we can actually use Jupyter Notebooks here itself, and that, we will start from the next session, wherein we'll start with the installation of all the softwares.
Krish Naik: That is actually required for this particular batch.
Krish Naik: Okay?
Krish Naik: The other thing is that you need to have basic knowledge of generative AI. Along with that, you need to have some cloud knowledge that is more than sufficient to get started.
Krish Naik: Clear? Clear with respect to the prerequisites? Yeah?
Krish Naik: Can I get a quick yes?
Krish Naik: If everybody's clear, yeah?
Krish Naik: Okay, perfect. Now, the next step, with respect to the learning that you will be seeing over here, is that let's go back and talk about your dashboard, because this dashboard is very much important, okay?
Krish Naik: So, if you go ahead and log in into learn.krishnakacademy.com, is everybody able to see this specific batch with these four fields?
Krish Naik: Yeah?
Krish Naik: Yes, we also have a mobile app of Krishnak Academy, so if you go ahead and search for Krishnak Academy in Android.
Krish Naik: or in…
Krish Naik: iOS, you'll be able to see these two apps. So if you go to Play Store, here is the app which you will be able to see it, okay? So you can also go ahead and install the app in your mobile phones, okay?
Krish Naik: So, both in iOS, both in this, you have this specific app where you'll be able to see this kind of stuff, wherein, even though when you're traveling, even though wherever you're going, you should be able to see anything, all the recordings along with your entire dashboard access and all. Yeah, you'll also be able to access the recordings. Clear?
Krish Naik: Now, from your dashboard, do you see all the specific options?
Krish Naik: Yeah?
Krish Naik: Do you see this?
Krish Naik: Okay, forget about these affiliates, because I'm the admin, I'm able to see this, but here, you should be able to see feed, workshop, courses, and message. Don't worry about these affiliates. These affiliates will… will not be visible to you, since I am the admin over here, so it is visible for me.
Krish Naik: So, first of all, let me talk about this particular dashboard, because this is really important with respect to the dashboard itself, okay? Now, I will just go ahead and write, hello all.
Krish Naik: Welcome!
Krish Naik: To the… welcome to the… ultimate Goodbye.
Krish Naik: bootcamp, okay?
Krish Naik: So this is my message in your group, and I will go ahead and select this particular group. I'll save the changes, and I'll publish it.
Krish Naik: Now, do you see that you will be able to see this particular message? Just reload the page.
Krish Naik: Everyone?
Krish Naik: So this is the community feed. Let's say that you want to announce something to the group, you want to share your learnings.
Krish Naik: You can go ahead and just post it over here. So if you go ahead and see on down, you'll be able to see that many people make sure to, upload many things over here. Is the workshop started? Okay, this is the problem that many people was facing, but anyhow, we have fixed it, okay?
Krish Naik: So here you can see your AI chatbot. People keeps on sharing the knowledge over here, okay? They keep on sharing the knowledge over here, and here you will be able to see that
Krish Naik: All the new things that they learn, anything that they do, they keep on doing this within your community group. It is just like a LinkedIn feed, okay? And this LinkedIn feed, you'll be able to see that. Everything looks clearly. Whatever you want to post with respect to your group, any new things, you'll be able to do it, okay?
Krish Naik: So if you just reload this.
Krish Naik: You should be able to see, you can just give a heart sign to this particular message.
Krish Naik: Over here
Krish Naik: So if you go ahead and see it over here, welcome to the, Ultimate Rack Bootcamp. So, 23 people have given the engagement. So, any engagement over here, you can reshare, you can repost, like how we specifically do in LinkedIn, that all things are available over here. Clear?
Krish Naik: Clear? Everybody?
Krish Naik: Yep.
Krish Naik: I hope everybody's clear, everybody, guys. Just give me a confirmation if things are clear for you. You're able to understand
Krish Naik: Just a second
Krish Naik: Okay?
Krish Naik: Perfect. Now… Okay. Now, once this is done, these feeds are basically just to share the knowledge, okay?
Krish Naik: Then, the next section, you'll be able to see Workshop, okay? So, do you see this entire workshop?
Krish Naik: So this workshop actually gives you the entire sessions that you are having on Saturdays and Sundays.
Krish Naik: I think, for me, I have excess of 3 batches, so you'll be able to see 9.30 to 12.30, this particular batch access is there. Okay?
Krish Naik: 2PM, 6pm, another batch is there. 8pm, 2 AM, another batch is there. Tomorrow, probably, at night, 8pm to a.m, another batch is there. Okay? So for you also, I think you should be able to see this particular batch. Yes?
Krish Naik: Yes or no?
Krish Naik: For November 2nd, right?
Krish Naik: So, 9… to 12…
Krish Naik: you know, you should be able to see the specific batch details. Okay? Got it, everybody?
Krish Naik: Yeah?
Krish Naik: Yes?
Krish Naik: Perfect. So, at any point of time.
Krish Naik: I think everybody has also received the mail about the class, yeah? So, there should be an email ID from support at the ratekrishnakacademy.com, and you should be able to receive the mail and all the links and all out there also.
Krish Naik: So at any point of time, if you really want to know what sessions are there, even from your mobile app, you can go ahead and check it out over here.
Krish Naik: And, even in the desktop also, you should be… or in the laptop also, you should be able to do it, okay?
Krish Naik: The next important session is about the course section. Now, in the course section, whatever courses you have specifically joined, that all courses will be visible over here with respect to the course dashboard. Okay?
Krish Naik: So, if you go ahead and see over here, I will go ahead and click for one of the previous batches that we are doing, LLM Ops, okay? So, if you go ahead and see, I'll click on continue. So, here.
Krish Naik: As soon as, right now, let's say this session is going on.
Krish Naik: This session is also getting recorded, okay? This session is also getting recorded. Now.
Krish Naik: after… now, you may be… you may be asking, Krish, when we will be getting the recordings, okay? So, usually, after the session gets over.
Krish Naik: Like, usually the session goes for 3-4 hours, okay? It goes for 3 to 4 hours. And in that 3-4 hours, what we specifically do is that
Krish Naik: We cover the entire live session, and then we have doubt clearing session after that. So let's say, right now is 9.20 a.m. IST. Once we cover the class till 12… 12 PM, then we start the doubt clearing. Doubt clearing basically means we ask all the questions, we allow you to.
Krish Naik: Unmute yourself, talk with respect to any queries that you have. We try to answer them.
Krish Naik: And for that, we come on first-come, first-served basis, because we need to cater all the doubts. And each and every doubt is important, because if somebody's asking a specific doubt, that same doubt can be for the other person also.
Krish Naik: So we are making sure that the doubts are answered in a much proper way, so that everybody's doubts are clarified. And don't worry, until and until and unless we don't clear all the doubts, we are not going to stop the session.
Krish Naik: Clear?
Krish Naik: Everybody clear? Yeah?
Krish Naik: As said, when the class gets over, within 24 hours, you will be able to see the recordings in the dashboard. So, in your case.
Krish Naik: If I probably go to the course section.
Krish Naik: If I click on Start Learning, right now, on the induction session, nothing is there. But after this session gets over.
Krish Naik: We will upload the recording over here within 24 hours. Clear?
Krish Naik: I know 24 hours is a one-day time, right? But why we are saying 24 hours? Because Zoom also takes some time to process it. But we always try to do before 6 hours to upload the video. Clear?
Krish Naik: Yep.
Krish Naik: Clear? So this induction session right now is also available in the YouTube, it is also live in the YouTube. The reason is that if somebody's not able to join, so we are making sure to livestream it, so to talk about, like, the entire thing. So as soon as this session gets recorded.
Krish Naik: As soon as the session gets over, we will be uploading the session over here in the dashboard. Clear?
Krish Naik: Yeah?
Krish Naik: Perfect. Now, after this, you have this messages section.
Krish Naik: Okay.
Krish Naik: After this, you have this messaging section.
Krish Naik: In the messages section, do you see this very important message group? So this is the community chat, like, you want to talk with your peer-to-peer.
Krish Naik: This is where, like, a WhatsApp group, okay, don't make a separate WhatsApp group.
Krish Naik: There is a group over here, you'll be able to see for your Ultimate Rack Bootcamp, everybody should be able to communicate with each other. So let's say if I say, hi team, over here.
Krish Naik: So this message, I think everybody should be able to get. Don't write the message right now, I'm just testing it to talk about it, right? So for every batches in Krishnak Academy, we have separate, separate…
Krish Naik: chat rooms, so that any discussions that you really want to talk about, you should be able to talk about. Okay? Ha, one very important thing is that
Krish Naik: Whenever…
Krish Naik: the sessions are uploaded, okay? In the resources section, you should see all the materials that is uploaded, okay? So let's say this was one of the sessions that I was taking, okay?
Krish Naik: Now, for all the handwritten notes, all the materials, everything will be uploaded in this resources section, which you can download, okay? There is also a Q&A section, which you can go ahead and communicate it over here.
Krish Naik: Okay? Any kind of chat that you really want to do, that will also available over here. Clear, everybody.
Krish Naik: Can I get a quick yes?
Krish Naik: Yeah?
Krish Naik: It's a good dashboard, because I'm not showing you unnecessary courses and all. What you have enrolled for, that only you should see in the dashboard. That is the reason why I like this particular thing. See over here.
Krish Naik: You should be able to see feed, what communication is going on, you should be able to see your courses only.
Krish Naik: Right?
Krish Naik: And here, you should see only your messages within the group. If you are joined in multiple batches, you should be able to see join multiple batches. Do you see anywhere that I'm showing you any other courses over here?
Krish Naik: Just check it out.
Krish Naik: Is this a dashboard good or bad?
Krish Naik: No, not a single course is visible over here to you, right? So, all these things is there, okay? Now, once this is done, now we need to probably go ahead and talk about
Krish Naik: how we are going to take the session, like this. It'll be a live session over here.
Krish Naik: And we are going to probably teach each and everything with handwritten notes, each and everything that will be visible in front of you.
Krish Naik: We don't prepare PPTs, I don't like preparing PPTs, we write each and everything, so our notes will look something like this. See?
Krish Naik: Our notes will look something like this. We'll write each and everything in front of you. We will draw each and every diagrams in front of you, so that your learning should be very much good.
Krish Naik: Clear?
Krish Naik: Everybody clear?
Krish Naik: Yes?
Krish Naik: Okay, now let me introduce you to one more mentor.
Krish Naik: Within your, within our circle right now. So, Paul, do you want to show your face?
Krish Naik: Oh, you're muted.
PAUL: Yes, yes. I think I moduled everyone.
Krish Naik: Yeah.
PAUL: Yes, guys, please leave your response in the chat, yeah.
PAUL: Hello, everyone. So, my name is Sarankal. So, I've been working with RAG and agentic-based systems, and I think a few people might know me from the previous batches that I have taken.
PAUL: So, in this batch, I'll be taking a lot of classes, I can say, majorly, with respect to RAG, what are the recent research that is going on in 2025 with respect to RAG. Okay, so all those important things we'll be talking about. So, I hope that it will be a very interesting journey for the next 4 months.
PAUL: A lot of new things that you will be learning to research with respect to even production, how to finally make a product.
PAUL: We will try to make things much more easier, I will try to make things much more simpler for you, so that at the end of the day, in your organizations, you can implement such systems.
PAUL: Yes, we'll be covering metrics rest, don't worry, I'll be looking into the chats, a lot of chats are coming, okay, I'll be taking the questions personally, so… yes, don't worry about that.
Krish Naik: Okay. Now, one more thing, guys,
Krish Naik: Many people have also asked me related to prerequisites, yes?
Krish Naik: Yeah? Prerequisites, yes? Yes or no?
Krish Naik: So, for prerequisites, what we specifically do for people who have, specifically for our students, right, whenever
Krish Naik: Now, see, you know that, parallelly, we also make sure that we upload, Udemy courses, okay?
Krish Naik: Now, in Udemy courses, you will be able to see… can you see my screen? Can you give me a quick confirmation?
Krish Naik: Like, what are the basic prerequisites? Many people may want Python, many people may want different, different things. So, over here, you'll be able to see most of our courses that we have, right? Let's say this generative AI course with Langchain and Hugging Face, okay? So, here.
Krish Naik: this will be the course for the prerequisite, and specifically for your batch, whenever I get a free coupon, I make sure to share courses to you all, right? So this time, I will be sharing this entire course, so everybody can go ahead and use this coupon.
Krish Naik: I have given the link in the chat, okay? Just go ahead, use those, and that is for a first-come, first-served basis, okay?
Krish Naik: You can use this course for your prerequisites. I've given the link in the chat, not in the YouTube chat, only for our students who have joined.
Krish Naik: Okay?
Krish Naik: Happy, everyone?
Krish Naik: Yes? Again, it is first-come, first-served basis.
Krish Naik: Yeah, are you partnered with corporate companies? Yes, I think this course is also available in more than 200 plus companies, okay?
Krish Naik: So this is the thing that I can do it from my side for you all. And don't worry, as we go ahead, you know, I will be providing you more courses, okay? More courses whenever we got one, we get one, okay?
Krish Naik: So, the main aim is that any prerequisites that you require, we provide it through this. And, you know, it is always a good practice that we do. Like, every month we distribute a lot of coupons to our students who have joined the live batches, so that you don't need to probably take the Udemy,
Krish Naik: Out there, okay? So just use the link. Yes, Harsh Navin, it is available for you.
Krish Naik: Just use this particular coupon that I've given in the chat, okay?
Krish Naik: I know, sorry for the YouTube folks, guys, it is for our students first. If it is remaining, we'll also send it to you, okay?
Krish Naik: Clear? Everyone? Is everybody able to access the course? Yeah?
Krish Naik: And please, don't forget to put your ratings.
Krish Naik: See, all our batches are really amazing, like, this one also, we have crossed 111K.
Krish Naik: You know, 111K throughout 180 plus countries.
Krish Naik: This is just a recorded. Here, we have covered Python, we have covered all the prerequisites for NLP, you know, generative AI, each and everything.
Krish Naik: What is the prerequisite that is required, you can probably go ahead and access it. This is just from our side to you all, and whenever we get more free coupons, we should be able to share it to you.
Krish Naik: Okay?
Krish Naik: No, you don't need to pay VPN.
Krish Naik: Yeah.
Krish Naik: Amito esoque.
Krish Naik: If you have bought it, no worries, I'll share more coupons as I get.
Krish Naik: Okay?
Krish Naik: Okay, perfect. See, just use the free coupons, guys.
Krish Naik: It's okay, Uma Pathati. And again, I'm telling you, whatever new batches I come up with, I give a lot of free coupons to our students.
Krish Naik: Okay, so this is the… just see the coupon code out there, and you should be able to use it.
Krish Naik: Clear? Let's go to the next step now.
Krish Naik: Yeah?
Krish Naik: Let's go to the next step.
Krish Naik: Okay. Paul, anything that you want to cover related to dashboard, anything pending? I think I've covered almost everything.
PAUL: Yes, I think the dashboard part is their prerequisite. Also, we have covered…
PAUL: And I think we can go a deep dive into syllabus, little bit, step by step.
Krish Naik: Please, please share your screen and go through the syllabus once again.
PAUL: Alright.
PAUL: Alright, everyone, so I think you guys can see my screen. Please provide a confirmation in the chat.
PAUL: Yes? Alright.
PAUL: Alright guys, so, as we know that, this particular batch will be focusing on RAG, okay? So, with respect to RAG, when I'm speaking, okay, so we will take a journey, a long time, like, when the first concept of RAG came.
PAUL: Okay, so initially, like, we will start with the traditional RAG implementation, like the foundations of RAG.
PAUL: So, we will be talking with respect to implementations as well as research. Okay, so for example, the first paper or rag that came around.
PAUL: Okay, so, like, we'll be talking about research papers in this course, what are the different things? Okay, so I'll be talking what are the mean highlighted points in every paper, so we'll be taking a journey. As you can see, this is 2021.
PAUL: So, from 2021 to, till now, I can say, what are the major papers that are coming around RAG we'll be talking, okay? So, like, a long journey of 4 years, what are the major papers, like, more than 20 to 25 major papers that we'll be talking about?
PAUL: Okay, so I hope the audio is fine, guys, please let me know, because somebody is telling that the audio is breaking, so please let me know.
PAUL: All good? Alright, fine.
PAUL: Okay, so we will start with the basic RAG implementation, what is RAG, the core components, okay? Setting up the RAG, try to do a Pythonic implementation, because the idea is that you guys should be familiar with Python.
PAUL: Okay, we'll be doing a lot of modular coding here, okay? So, the idea is you have to be good in Python. So, if you're not good in Python, please try to, like, see the lectures which are provided, okay? And just try to cope up.
PAUL: Because at the end of the day, the implementations slowly, slowly… I will start with Jupyter notebooks, then from Jupyter notebooks to IDs that will move, where completely it will be, like, object-oriented programming, okay?
PAUL: Alright, now coming to the major frameworks for RAG. So, like,
PAUL: Langcheng, one of the major, I can say, dominating frameworks in the
PAUL: AI ecosystem right now. Okay, so if you go to the GitHub, you will be seeing a lot of stars, like LanChan. Everybody knows about LanChan, I think. Yes or no?
PAUL: from somewhere, yes? Because, simply if you look into the major ones, so Langshan, GitHub.
PAUL: Okay, so everybody is using Langshan, one of the major ones, and if you look into the stars of this particular project, okay, so simply.
PAUL: Always follow the project styles, so based on that, you know that the community has accepted it, so more than
PAUL: 120K. So, yes, we'll be doing a deep dive, with respect to RAG implementations in Langgen.
PAUL: Okay, so here, what are the new things, and even the latest things that are coming from Langchen in the experimental module.
PAUL: We'll be talking about those things step by step, okay.
PAUL: Now, initially we'll start with the basic, text processing. Okay, so, like, different type of character splitters are there. Okay, then comes embeddings, very, very important. How to make good embeddings. We'll be talking about these things in detail. What are the different type of embedding providers?
PAUL: like, OpenAI embeddings is there, Gemini is there, Ullama, your local, okay? Then, Hugging Face embeddings are there, like in Hugging Face. I'll be telling you what are the top models right now, embedding models that you have, according to the benchmark.
PAUL: it's always about the benchmark that we'll be talking about, okay? So, for example, if I show you the MTB leaderboard. So, from here, you know that what are the best models right now. So, in this particular course, we'll be using those best models.
PAUL: Okay? So, some things can be paid, guys, okay? But,
PAUL: like, right now, if you look into, a new model came, the Llama Embed Nemo drone, okay? Now, like, this is right now the best, and which is 8 billion. Now, 8 billion models, we cannot run it in our local system, so probably we can go with Gemini, which is API-based.
PAUL: from Google, and based on this particular, I can say, details, okay, according to the latest research that we have, we'll be doing all those implementations. The idea is to use state-of-the-art.
PAUL: Okay? So, we will be always selecting the top 10 right now, okay? According to the standard right now, which is being followed in November 2025 for this course. Yes, we'll be using APIs Watcher, OpenAI, Gemini, okay? So I can say, see, guys, at least, most of the things will be free.
PAUL: But sometimes, at least having a $5 credit helps you. Because few things in the course, because, like, after 2 months or 3 months, when we will deep dive into some advanced stuff. Okay, so there. It's not about a huge amount you need.
PAUL: Probably the charges, because I think within $5, the entire thing that can be done in this course.
PAUL: Okay? And very specifically, most of the stuff we will try to use Gemini, as it is completely free.
PAUL: But yes, I hope you guys get the idea, everyone, what I'm trying to say. We'll be using the latest research, and what is the best right now in 2025. Okay?
PAUL: Alright, so embedding site tool, then comes vectors too. Very, very important, like,
PAUL: So many vector stores are there, okay? So, we'll be talking about at least 5 to 6 in detail in this course, so I think SuperLink vector databases are there.
PAUL: Okay, so medially in the market which is being used.
PAUL: we'll be talking about. Okay, so a very long list right now that I am showing you. Okay, so out of this, at least I can say 5 to 10 different.
PAUL: We'll be using open source, as well as a few paid ones, like Quadrant, very specifically, Viviate, that we'll be using. And open source is there, like, FIS is there.
PAUL: Now, how to optimize vector databases? Okay, how to do batch uploads, those things also we'll be talking about in this course, because when you try to build a production-based rack system, okay, how to upload your data.
PAUL: Okay, so in different types of batches, how to handle GBs of data, so those things also we'll be talking about.
PAUL: So, this was all about the VectorDB part.
PAUL: Now, coming to the next part, okay, the traditional, so this part, like, the using pure Python, building, with LangChain, these things, evaluation and testing, as few people are. Yes, we'll be talking about RAG evaluation metrics.
PAUL: As well as frameworks.
PAUL: Okay, it's not about only… I will be telling you about the metrics, what are the major one FEMAs right now in the market, like, we'll be talking with respect to Ragas.
PAUL: Okay, very, very important.
PAUL: Okay, so… this particular framework, like, it's being adopted widely, as you can see, the number of stars here, so it's widely being used. So, in this course, we'll be using radars a lot.
PAUL: Okay? So, with respect to evaluating.
PAUL: Then, once we have started, then the most important passes, the most important part that I feel is document passes.
PAUL: So here, right now, as you can see, dock lens, okay, so this is a minor mistake, it will be dock link.
PAUL: Okay? So, let me just show you.
PAUL: Doclink GitHub.
PAUL: Okay, so this is open source completely, okay, and even we'll be talking about a few proprietary, projects, so, like, using this, how to parse data. As you can see, like, this is GitHub Trending, okay, the number one repository of the day. So, widely being used, I can say.
PAUL: Then this is completely open source, then we'll be talking about a little bit Llama parts, okay, because Llama parts, there are limits. This is a paid one, then we have unstructured, again, unstructured has a open source version, and then the paid one then comes vectorized for 4 different type of major document parsers.
PAUL: Now, I cannot say that, out of this 4, this is the best.
PAUL: It totally depends upon your data, okay? But I will tell you, yes, always test with this food.
PAUL: Okay, and out of this, you will see that at least one is working very good, which will give you good passing, at least with a rate of more than 85%.
PAUL: Okay? So, the most important part. How to get data from different type of data sources. So, that's why we have kept a separate module, and I think this module will go for 2 weeks at least, because this is the first step of building a good rack.
PAUL: Alright, so once we have covered, then we will come to a few other major frameworks, in, right now, the community has accepted, like, Llama Index.
PAUL: So, this is another very, very famous project. What are the major fundamentals here? Just like Langchen. First, we'll start with Langchen, then comes Lama Index, how to handle the different type of documents here, different type of sources, indexing, query.
PAUL: Okay, how to perform, two different types of searches that goes around, okay, so, like, vector search.
PAUL: Okay, and then comes your, like, BM25 search. So, those things we'll be talking about. Like, to build a good rack system, you need to have hybrid search systems. Okay? So, those things will be going, then query optimization comes with respect to Llama Index that we'll be talking about.
PAUL: Okay, so a few advanced topics. This is very, very, like, with respect to Llama that we'll be talking. Okay, so custom configurations. Now, these are some advanced parts, so once we'll be covering the basics, I think this will be probably in the second month, okay?
PAUL: So, again, advanced retrievers. So, like, in retrievers, we'll be talking about this particular topic is very, very important, how to make a good retriever.
PAUL: Okay, so different types of retriever. Okay, so right now, like, in the past 3 years, we have seen a lot of research with respect to the retrieval waste systems.
PAUL: So, we'll be talking about that, and most of them are available in Langchen and Lava Index.
PAUL: Then, once we have covered, Llama, then we'll move to Haystack. Okay, so Haystack, again, widely used in production.
PAUL: Okay, so Haystack AI.
PAUL: Okay, so here, you can… you can see here the production-ready open source AI framework, okay? So, another one, I feel you can see the stars right here, 23.2K, and very specifically, I kept this model because till now, in other courses, we have never discussed Haystack.
PAUL: So this is the first course I can say that, okay, where we'll be using Haystack.
PAUL: Okay, so this will be something new, okay? And I know, like, many people have worked with Langchain and others, but I feel that this part will be new for… okay, like, a lot of things which are already implemented in Haystack. So, building pipelines, your production pipelines, is very, very easy using Haystack.
PAUL: Okay, so that's why we'll be talking about this, particular, I can say, project in DTEC.
PAUL: Now, once we go back…
PAUL: Okay, so Haystack fundamentals, how to build a rack using Haystack, then comes advanced techniques. Now, these techniques are very, very important. Working with Heidi, okay, then comes query decomposition. Okay, so if a big query comes, you can break it into multiple queries.
PAUL: Okay, then comes reasoning, how to build React agents, that also we'll be discussing later, when agents will come into the picture, query expansion.
PAUL: Okay, how to enrich your metadata, okay? So, these things in detail. So, you can think about, like, everything, like, if I'm talking about metadata, ID, these topics are, like, everything, like, 30-30 minutes topics. So, like.
PAUL: what are the new things that have been coming? All of this, new implementations with a full pipeline that we'll be talking about.
PAUL: Now, specialized applications, very specifically with respect to multimodal, so that's why vision plus text pipelines, it means that from your document, if you have some type of image, so image plus text, we will try to extract both things, and then we will try to build a rack.
PAUL: Okay? So that's why…
PAUL: this part, once we have covered, then we will start our agent tech journey. Because till now, it… this, like, Haystack, LaMind, Slang Chan, all these frameworks, immediately it's rack-based implementations.
PAUL: But once we start our Module 8, Module 8 is all about your agentic-based systems. So, the best framework right now in the market, which is dominating, which is Langra. In other batches also, we have taught Langra. Okay, so similarly here also, we will start with Langra, because there are so many frameworks in the market.
PAUL: But I feel that, yes, Langdraft is one of the most powerful ones for agent orchestration.
PAUL: Okay, so here we will start with the fundamentals, how to do the setup, what are the core things, the core components, like graphs is there, tools are there, modes are there, all those things that we'll be talking about. Then comes building a chatbot, okay, what are the different types of architectures, like React Agent, okay?
PAUL: Then we will move ahead with, like, production features very specific to Langrap. Okay, so, like, Langra app, streaming, A-Stream events, orchestration worker. So, now these are advanced topics of Langrap.
PAUL: So, we will start with the basics. The idea is to move ahead, like, a bottom-to-top approach. We will start with something easy stuff, and then we will jump into application, because the advanced topic will be a part of application. It's not like I'll be just teaching you the concept, okay? There will be always an application, guys.
PAUL: At the end of the day, the idea is that
PAUL: In this entire course, we'll be building more than, like, 20 to 25 applications, easily.
PAUL: So, once you have covered Langra app, then we'll move to some advanced rack techniques. Very, very important. So, this is very specific to, like, production, if you are really building a system.
PAUL: The first, initially, like, till modulates, it's all about basic stuff. Okay, it means that, okay, you know the core concept, but what about if you want to apply it in production? This is where things comes. You have to do more work. It means that I'll be telling you these things, but you really need to do your hands on.
PAUL: I'll be sharing everything, but this is the part where you do your research according to your own data for your organization, okay? So here, like, advanced chunking and preprocessing, okay, like, parent chunking, child chunking, all those things that will come into the picture, then comes your hybrid search.
PAUL: Combining, different type of searching, like vector search, with text search. Okay, like BM25 is one of the major famous algorithms, which has been widely accepted in LLMs, or very specifically with respect to transformer architecture.
PAUL: Okay, so BM25. So that's why we'll be talking about that. Then comes query enhancement with Heidi. So, like, this will be pure implementations based on a framework, and probably, like, the framework will be with respect to Langchen or Llama.
PAUL: Then the next part, Module 10, so this is where vision comes into the picture. Okay, with structured data, the idea is that to fetch the data from some type of, like, structure sources, like, it can be…
PAUL: Postgres, okay. Or, like, how to fetch the data from some type of unstructure, like, we'll be taking the example with Mongo.
PAUL: Then, multimodal. Now, this is the part
PAUL: where things will become interesting, because at the end of the day, it's not always about text. You have to work with images. Images are very, very important. Like videos, if I'm talking about.
PAUL: Okay, so, like, if you are working with videos, you have to break the videos into frames. Now, from those frames, you have to extract what is the information.
PAUL: Okay, so in this way, we will try to make things for multimodal RAG. Now, this part will be something new, according to the 2025 standards, because the multimodal RAG implementations, majorly, we have seen major research coming from 2024. So, this part will be, like, very, very new. In other courses, although we have not gone,
PAUL: like, in-depth in this one, but here we'll be talking about the major embeddings, like CLIP, okay, the clip embeddings that comes into the picture.
PAUL: Then, working with PDL, different type of data sources, this will be pretty much common. You can see here, audio and video will come into the picture. Working with STT, okay, TTS, like speech-to-text, okay, then text-to-speech, those things will come.
PAUL: Now, here, conversational and contextual track. So, anybody who is building a production system, for them, Module 11 is very, very important.
PAUL: Okay? So, like, user profiling… okay, like, how to give memory. Like, for agentic frameworks, like, you will be using… I'll be talking about a few major, memory ways, like, Memo.
PAUL: Okay, so, like, AI agents forget, but memo remembers. This is just a memory layer. So, that we'll be talking about in this particular course, and this will be integrating with our rack-based systems that we'll be building.
PAUL: I hope everybody is understanding the flow, like, step by step, what are the things. Initially, it will be all the basics still, modulate. But once, after modulate, things will be much more…
PAUL: I can say towards, like, the idea is to make it close to production, because exactly we cannot show this is production, but the idea is make you at least close, like, yes, these are the things which are actually used in production.
PAUL: Yes, everyone?
PAUL: Please let me know you unders… you are getting the flow that we have taken in this particular course.
PAUL: Okay, now, we'll be talking a little bit with respect to prompt engineering and context engineering also, because right now in 2025, context engineering is a very hot topic, so for that, like, how to build contextual rag, how to get better context. At the end of the day, getting better context.
PAUL: Is a very, very important thing when you are building. So, those things that you'll be focusing on.
PAUL: Then comes Agent TRAG. Okay, so, like, here, a lot of new things that will come into the picture, because at the end of the day.
PAUL: RAG is there, but we will be using agentic frameworks on top. Like, Langrap, that's why we have covered it before, because using Langraph, we'll be building agentic RAG. Like, a lot of RAG. SRAG will be there, Adaptic RAG will be there, Hybrid RAG will be there, different types of RAG.
PAUL: Because total number of rack counts, if you ask me by the end of this course, you can simply say that I know more than 20 types of rack.
PAUL: Okay? More than 20 guys, really. Different types of RAG architecture that we'll be talking about.
PAUL: Yes, guardrails we'll be talking about, don't worry. Very specifically, like, we'll be using one of the major open source projects for guardrails, okay? So, like, Guardrills AI.
PAUL: Okay, so this one, let me just show you the…
PAUL: So this is a famous project.
PAUL: You can add gardens.
PAUL: Okay, so this project that we'll be implementing, okay, so in our version. So, if anybody's asking with respect to guardrails, yes.
PAUL: Now, the next one, so once we have completed, okay, then comes advanced agent rack systems, okay, like autonomous agents, multi-agent systems here, like, the idea is to build 5 or 6 different types of agents, then we'll be using some type of orchestration tool, okay, how they will be communicating among each other, that's why the communication protocols comes into the picture.
PAUL: how they will be collaborating, okay? Then, like, how to finally productionize your,
PAUL: Entire orchestration of the agents, Using Landgraph.
PAUL: Now, this is the part where, like, things will be a little bit more interesting, because this is purely for production, like, how to scale up. Now, this is where a little bit of networking comes into the picture. See, guys, now, this part is a little bit less about AI,
PAUL: much more about, like, DevOps with respect to networking, cloud networking, simply. Like, catching strategies. Okay, so here we'll be working with Redis.
PAUL: very, very specifically for catching. In this course, we'll be working with Redis. I think everybody knows about Redis. If you don't know, you'll be learning in this course. Okay? Then comes load balancing. So, with respect to load balancing, it can be a vertical load balancing or a horizontal load balancing.
PAUL: Okay, so, little bit concept about, I can say, system design. So, yes, we'll be talking about these concepts. Very, very important. If you're building any type of AI system, okay, or simple, like, software, okay, SDLC, they also follow these rules.
PAUL: Okay, so for, so load balancing, then comes asynchronous processing, very, very important.
PAUL: Then comes your Docker, that's why container deployment. We'll be working with Docker a lot in this course. Like, the idea is that
PAUL: being an AI engineer or a data scientist, okay, so you should know
PAUL: till, I can say the container part. Okay, so tilt over. The other part can be taken care by the MLOps guys, very specifically, or the AIOps.
PAUL: Okay, or the LLM ops, but you should know how to work with containers, because at the end of the day, very, very important. So, Docker will be talking about, and even, I think, and at this time, I am planning to include Podeman.
PAUL: Okay? Because in other courses, majorly, we have discussed Docker a lot, but this time, in this one, we even will be talking with respect to Boadmap.
PAUL: All right, then comes deployment and monitoring. Okay, so here comes your CI-CD pipelines. We'll be majorly working with GitHub Actions.
PAUL: And now, the main thing, with respect to cloud, which cloud? In the chat, I saw many people, like, which cloud, which cloud, which cloud. We will be using AWS.
PAUL: Okay? AWS.
PAUL: I think everybody, just keep in mind, we won't be working with other clouds, like GCP, probably, like, few things, but majorly this course will be around AWS.
PAUL: Alright, I hope I have made my point clear, so later on, don't ask, why not Azure?
PAUL: Simply. Like, Azure, yes, it is widely used in production, I know, but in this course, we'll be working, because, like, in Azure, I feel that few of the services that I have, and it's better for business. When you are learning something, you can easily switch cloud. If you know one service here, there are similar services in other cloud.
PAUL: So just be good in one cloud. So that's why I always suggest my students from other batches everywhere, just be good in one cloud. If you're good in AWS, yes, easily you can switch to Azure. It's not a big deal, it's not completely different rocket sense. Okay, so you can adopt, because,
PAUL: Every organization, I cannot say that everyone is using Azure, or everyone is using AWS, or everybody is using GCP.
PAUL: Probably some are using a totally different, like, DigitalOcean, or probably they are using, like, Linode. Previously, right now it's DigitalOcean.
PAUL: Okay, Oracle Cloud, so many, Oracle Cloud, so different. So right now, with respect to cloud, we'll be using very specifically AWS in this course.
PAUL: Okay? No, we won't be using, Databricks.
PAUL: Alright, now coming to…
PAUL: cutting-edge rag techniques, so these are the different types of rag, like self-rag, adaptive rag, retrieval, graph rag, okay, so fine-tuning. So, now, this part is something, like, where you need to
PAUL: spend, probably, like, to get a good GPU instance, you need a good GPU, as I hope everybody knows about, if you're working with LLMs, you need good GPUs.
PAUL: Whereas in RAG, it is not required. So that's why many people are adopting, because at the end of the day, when you are having a project, the infrastructure cost
PAUL: It's the most important thing.
PAUL: Okay, so any project, two things, like time and revenue. So, simply, like, GPUs are faster.
PAUL: But at the end of the day, it comes with the cost. So, little bit, we'll be talking with respect to fine-tuning also. Very, very important, because somebody might have some type of domain-specific data. And right now, with respect to… even we'll be talking about a particular concept of Raft. I don't know how many of you know, this is pretty much
PAUL: Now, famous, starting from 2024. Anybody else heard about Raft?
PAUL: Where you mix rack plus fine-tuning?
PAUL: Okay, so if you have notes, who we'll be talking about. So, this is one of the major research papers from UC Berkeley. So, we'll be using, I can say academic institutions majorly. Few, major papers that come from UC Berkeley, Stanford, we'll be talking about those papers.
PAUL: Okay, and their implementations which are available. Okay, so how this is different. So that's why I told, like, this is Rack Plus fine-tuning, guys. Okay, not Rack Plus Agent. Don't get confused.
PAUL: So, then few other research organizations, and very specifically, if I talk about, like, IBM, what are the…
PAUL: major research that is going in IBM, because IBM is really good with respect to RAG, okay? Now, RAG-based papers, that always comes around, like Blended RAG, Metagen Blended RAG, okay, different type of toolkits that comes around.
PAUL: Okay, so… really, guys, see, in this course, we'll be talking about a lot of things. Now you have to understand, entire research paper I cannot discuss. Okay, I'll be telling you, in this research paper, these are the important things. But now, it's your job. Because if I start only discussing research papers, it will take more than 9 months.
PAUL: to complete this course, probably one year. Because everything in a research paper, okay, so, like, if you try to go in-depth with respect to the mathematics behind it, then really, like, it really takes a lot of time to decode, but
PAUL: If you think it from, like, a production point of view, you have to need to understand the applications. Okay, how to get this thing, and how this is better than something.
PAUL: Okay, so, for example, if I talk about this paper, now this is BlenderTrack, you can see 4 hours 2024. After this came.
PAUL: MetaGen, the upgraded version of BlenderTrack. So you have to understand what is the difference between the metagen and the blended track. In this way, always, I will try to make things simpler for you. Okay, now, why this paper is better than this paper.
PAUL: I hope I make my point and everybody get it, because at the end of the… see, after this course completes, like, after 5 months.
PAUL: Okay, then I cannot take classes, so you have to be updated with the research. So, I'll be telling you, okay, now from this place, I get the information. Okay, something new came in track.
PAUL: So that my research team can at least do some type of implementation and show me a POC. So similarly, if you are leaders, simply in your… you are in architect level, okay, or, so simply, you can know that, okay, now, I have to look into the recent research that is going on. Based on the research, I can tell my team, and they can actually present me with a POC.
PAUL: The idea is always look into what is the state-of-the-art research. So that's why, in this, like, a lot of research papers, guys, okay, so more than, like, 20 to 25 papers that I'll be discussing, I'll be telling you, like.
PAUL: that entire journey, okay, starting from 2021 till 2025. That's why I told a long 4 years.
PAUL: Okay, so once we have done, now let's get back.
PAUL: Here, okay, so we'll be talking about MCP. I think many of you have heard about MCP, Model Context Protocol, how to build MCP servers, we'll be talking about that with respect to our RAG,
PAUL: Okay, so, like, a RAG with MCP. Like, first we'll be building a RAG, then that particular RAG will be exposing it to an MCP.
PAUL: MCP is a protocol. If you don't know, we'll be talking about this in detail. Because the common standard of exposing your, I can say, application, your RAG application, it will be, like, API-based, everybody should be familiar with FastAPI,
PAUL: In this course, we'll be using a lot of FastAPI, okay? Then, exposing your application through MCP,
PAUL: Then, exposing your application even through GRPC. Okay? So, few standards according to production, those things, yes, we'll be talking about.
PAUL: Then comes, finally, your project section, so this will probably start from the fourth
PAUL: month, I can say. Okay, so the different types of projects that we have, how to build a basic QN. Now, don't think about all the projects will come at the end. It's not like that. That everything will start. So, probably, like, basic rack QN system.
PAUL: This will be, I think, in your month one only. The idea is that I don't want to be, I don't want to make you directly that on the fourth month, you will learn the deployment.
PAUL: The idea is that every month you learn a little bit of deployment, and then every month we try to increase that level. Okay, how to make it better? How to make it better? The idea is to improve it.
PAUL: Yes, guys, I hope you get it. So, like, Project 1 and Project 2 then comes Project 3, this will be probably in the second month or the third month. Okay, then multimodal rack, like, Project 4 and 5, this will be very specifically to your, like, 4th month end and fifth month.
PAUL: Okay, so I hope everybody gets that what we are trying to deliver here. It's not only just teaching RAG. The idea is that adopting RAG and implementing RAG in your own production systems, in your own organizations.
PAUL: Yes?
PAUL: Yes, Swagoth, so you are telling police teachers from scratch? Yes, guys, see, that's why, initially, the module 1 to Module 8, you have to understand. This is the basics.
PAUL: Okay, so Module 1 to Module 8.
PAUL: After Module 8, things will be advanced.
PAUL: I hope I have made my point clear.
PAUL: Do we build RAG agents? Yes, we'll be building. I told you, we'll be building agents. That's why you have Langra. In this course, we'll be using Langra, the major framework.
PAUL: So, Baz is asking, can you share the research articles? Yeah, I can share today, but really, today's course is not about teaching today. The idea is to interact and give you guys the overview, exactly. What are the things that we are going to do in the next 4 to 5 months.
PAUL: Okay, so during classes, I'll be sharing the research paper link, don't worry about that.
PAUL: Okay.
PAUL: Yes, a little bit about prompt engineering. Yes, it is required, and with respect to context engineering, yes.
PAUL: CAG will be covering, don't worry, I told you more than 20 types of RAG. So, yes, CAG will come.
PAUL: CAG comes before RAFT, much more advanced one. Okay, so don't worry. Okay, so Catcher-based system, yes, we'll be talking about CAG, don't worry.
PAUL: Okay? Yes, GraphRag will also be covered, don't worry, you will be using NeoForge very specifically for that.
PAUL: Fine-tuning, we won't be going a depth with respect to fine-tuning, but I'll be telling you here, these are the major frameworks, and if you have a domain-specific data, you can use a LLM to do. Because, really, guys, if I am showing you fine-tuning, the cost of showing you fine-tuning is very high.
PAUL: Just probably, like, with the amount of data that we'll be having, okay? So, probably, I need to spend more than $1,000.
PAUL: Just to bring the complete infrastructure.
PAUL: Because with one GPU, I cannot do a fine-tuning. I need a system probably with 16 GPUs.
PAUL: Okay.
PAUL: Very new to all those terminologies, okay, don't worry, we'll be…
PAUL: Taking things slow, guys, that's why. Module 1 to modulate, basic stuff. Okay, then comes your advanced stuff.
PAUL: So, don't worry about that.
PAUL: Okay, so it will be a complete journey at any point of time, like, whenever I am taking the classes, or Chris, or okay, we always go with basics. Now, somebody's asking about LoRa, Q LoRa, no. This course is not about LLMs. This course is about RAG.
PAUL: Okay? So that's why those concepts won't be coming.
PAUL: Okay, I'll be showing you, like, with respect to fine-tuning, because in fine-tuning, very specifically, QLORA and LoRa is widely being used with respect to LLMs, so there I'll be… but it's not about in detail that we'll be talking about. The idea is stick to right.
PAUL: what infrastructure required? I'll be talking about you need good, like, GPU instances, very specifically, with respect to fine-tuning. In other places, you don't need.
PAUL: Majorly, with respect to IDs, okay, now, in this particular course, like, probably in the next close, next lecture, next week, Saturday, we'll be talking about all the installations, but, the major IDEs will be, like, VS Code, guys.
PAUL: At the end of the day. I might use, because in my system, I have more than 10 different IDs.
PAUL: But, yes, we'll be using…
PAUL: VS Code, majorly. I use Cursor, I do use Vince Up, I use Kiro. In my system, I have more than 10 different IDs, so don't worry, it doesn't matter. At the end of the day, VS Code does the job.
PAUL: Okay, so this is ultimate for beginner. Yes, I will say that, we start with the basics, because right now, in 2025, if you are really looking for a job, you have to be good with respect to RAG, because majorly all the organizations are implementing RAG in their systems.
PAUL: Okay, because everybody has huge amount of data. The idea is to get the information, or basically, to build a returable system. So that's why RAG, very, very important in every type of domain. If you think about finance, law, everywhere, very specific LLMs are big, like LLM for finance.
PAUL: Those are coming into the picture. LLM for, like, medicine, for pharma.
PAUL: Okay, so yes, we'll be talking about that.
PAUL: Today, no class. Today, it's all about the introduction. The idea is to discuss the journey, okay, for the next 4 to 5 months. And then, I think, what's the time? So, will we start taking the questions one by one?
PAUL: Okay, so I think…
PAUL: Chris, any other thing that needs to be discussed? Because I feel that the curriculum part and other things I have covered…
PAUL: I use SpyCharm, yes, PyCharm is fine.
PAUL: no issues.
Krish Naik: I think…
PAUL: Yeah.
Krish Naik: We are, we are, we are good, I think,
Krish Naik: We're good with all the syllabus. Okay, so guys, let me talk about one thing very important, you know? So here, why we are focusing more on this particular batch.
Krish Naik: And, you know, soon we are also coming up with a product, and I just want to show you that particular product. Please let me know if you are able to see my screen quickly.
Krish Naik: Okay?
Krish Naik: So, if you see over here, this is the product that we are developing, okay?
Krish Naik: The product, still has not been announced, because next, after a couple of weeks, this will be available, okay?
Krish Naik: And, this entire product is, like, one of the important components is RAG over here. So what is the use case that we are trying to solve over here is that you can see that in this world, right, right now, how many open source libraries are available?
Krish Naik: How many… So, open source libraries are available. Do you have a count?
Krish Naik: Do you have a count? Tons and tons, right?
Krish Naik: And what is the problem right now with ChatGPT, if you go and ask any code related to Langchain, LangGraph?
Krish Naik: Or related to open source libraries.
Krish Naik: It basically provides deprecated code. Do you agree? Everyone?
Krish Naik: Yes or no?
Krish Naik: Yeah? So it usually provides deprecated code, because all the ChatGPT models has some specific cut-off training date, right? So this is one of the problems that we are trying to solve. If you really want up-to-date code at any point of time for any kind of open source libraries.
Krish Naik: And if you feel going through the documentation is always a pain.
Krish Naik: we just tried to develop that particular product, and soon we are going to launch this. Let me just show you the working. Over here, right now, we have included so many different frameworks. Our plan is to cover more than 3,000 plus frameworks, okay?
Krish Naik: Here you can see LangChain, Langgraph, each and everything is available over here, right?
Krish Naik: So, two things, I think Context 7 does the same. Context 7 only gives you the context. Like, let's say that if I'm searching for anything over here, like Crew AI, okay?
Krish Naik: And if I just go ahead and select this, and I'll write agents, Using Creo AI.
Krish Naik: So what Context7 does is that it provides a context only, okay?
Krish Naik: But here.
Krish Naik: the context is the most important thing in order to get the response over here, okay? So what we are basically doing is that you can also go ahead and use any of our chat feature over here. You can put your own LLM models, any kind of LLM models, and let's say that if I go ahead and use Creo AI, I want to probably go ahead and start
Krish Naik: Agents with Creo AI.
Krish Naik: So here, we have also created the entire chatbot, okay? And this chatbot is in such a way that you can go ahead and integrate with any kind of LLM models, whatever LLM models you specifically want, and based on that, you should be able to get this.
Krish Naik: the best important part is that we have also… we are also coming up with an MCP server for this, which you can integrate in your VS Code, which is already developed. So once the announcement is already made, we will be showing all that particular use cases. Now, why I'm specifically focusing on this
Krish Naik: Because I really want my product team, because we will be hiring product team, and for them, RAG is one of the fundamental use cases that they should really know about, or skill sets that they should know about.
Krish Naik: So, there will be scenarios that we definitely want to hire some people from this particular batch, whom we are teaching RAG, and who are basically there
Krish Naik: You know, with respect to understanding all the concepts with respect to RAG, because we really need to improve this particular technique. My entire team, me, Paul, Mayank.
Krish Naik: Okay? Everybody has worked in this particular product, and from past couple of months, two to three months, we are making sure to make this particular product much more better.
Krish Naik: Okay? So, that is the reason why I'm showing you this particular product, because there may be, like, if you all do the assignments, do the projects in time, whatever things that we are giving, we would definitely consider your profile also, because we are planning to expand our team, specifically our development and product team. Okay?
Krish Naik: So, good idea altogether? Yes or no?
Krish Naik: No, it will be, coming up with a subscription, it'll be less than ChatGPT, but at least.
Krish Naik: Okay.
Krish Naik: And we are also coming up with the MCP server, which you can integrate in GitHub Copilot, anywhere that you can. Okay?
Krish Naik: Okay, my ink is also over here, so…
Mayank Aggarwal: Hi, sir. Hi, everyone. I hope I'm on a bunch.
Mayank Aggarwal: Great. Hi everyone, I hope my voice is going a lot better now. Hi, sir, good morning, Paul and sir.
Krish Naik: Yep.
Mayank Aggarwal: Great! Yeah, so, sorry I just joined a little late. I was working on something last night.
Mayank Aggarwal: So, yeah, everyone, I hope you're excited about the batch, right?
Mayank Aggarwal: I was seeing those labors being covered, and honestly, many, many things are there, which will be very, very good. And as Sir said, for… regarding the Xenodocs as well, we are using many of these things, and we want that students to get pretty, expert in the same thing, so that we can hire first from our pool of students, the people who we are basically training.
Mayank Aggarwal: And of course, we're learning these things firsthand from us, because I guess no one is teaching AI and all these concepts in this much depth, right? So that's the whole idea.
Mayank Aggarwal: I think, sir, I think we have shared the coupon. Do we need to share one more?
Krish Naik: Yeah, please share, please share.
Mayank Aggarwal: Very cool. So, great everyone. Yeah, so I think Sarah must have already walked you through, and as a overall benefit, like, we do share and we want all of you to learn and get a quick head start. So, I'm sharing course, coupon for another of the course, right? So, let me just quickly…
Mayank Aggarwal: Give you that, right?
Mayank Aggarwal: And before I do that, let me quickly walk you through, like, I think Sir must have already asked, but please make sure that all the coupons which we are
Mayank Aggarwal: A, I hope you're all able to see my screen, right? So this is the kind of UI which all of you will see once you… so this will be the course name once you are getting enrolled.
Mayank Aggarwal: Can I get a quick yes?
Mayank Aggarwal: If this will be the case, great. So, yeah, once you do that, everyone, two things you have to do. First, please make sure that you
Mayank Aggarwal: complete the course, go through everything, right? Udemy provides a very good overall UI, and we have made sure that it is very, very affordable and easily available for everyone.
Mayank Aggarwal: Second, please make sure that you leave a rating. So, there is a leave a rating, button, or basically in the UI. So, when you click leave a rating, easily you can provide us 5-star with your lovely thoughts. That will help us to get, basically.
Mayank Aggarwal: more students, and get all the teaching which we are creating, right, discovered by more of the people, right? So, with that, we are providing a… overall, I'm providing and pasting it in the chat, which is a coupon code for course for Microsoft AutoGen. So, Microsoft AutoGen, for those who are not aware.
Mayank Aggarwal: It's an awesome framework from Microsoft, so…
Mayank Aggarwal: Please make sure that you join the same, and yeah, do provide
Mayank Aggarwal: your lovely feedback to that. So, more than, again, 51 stars, 51K stars, okay? So, please make sure I'm sharing the coupon code. I will do one more thing, so that all of you can get easy access.
Mayank Aggarwal: Just give me a minute.
Mayank Aggarwal: And, meanwhile, I hope all of you are able to use that, so that will be very, very helpful.
Mayank Aggarwal: Let me just create a new…
Mayank Aggarwal: Put her, and drag, and I will provide you Cooper, you know?
Mayank Aggarwal: So, just a minute… because I think you cannot paste the, like, you cannot copy the coupon from there, right?
Mayank Aggarwal: So, just one second…
Mayank Aggarwal: Great. Yeah, so… great, everyone, just, I've shared a link. Just go to that link, and from that, you can easily copy the coupon and apply that.
Mayank Aggarwal: So, do make sure that you provide a lovely rating, right? For that, I think Sir has already shared multiple coupons with you, so that's a very good head start and lots of learning.
Mayank Aggarwal: So, please make sure that you take full advantage of this, and yeah, if you have any doubts, anything, we will always, of course, be there. I think we will be having a very, very great, like, in-depth doubt session now as well. So, yeah, when you will open with this link, the coupon will already be applied, you don't have to pay anything, okay?
Mayank Aggarwal: So, that's the whole benefit. Sir, can you please send me the coupons? I will also add it in the link only.
Mayank Aggarwal: The one which I've shared.
Mayank Aggarwal: So, great everyone. Just a quick, humble request. Please make sure that you cover the same and you provide the ratings, right? That will be a lot helpful. So, the latest one which I have given, they… you are… you can easily just copy the same, and please make sure that you do, like, use it.
Mayank Aggarwal: As you can see, the coupon course will be… a coupon code will be in the end, okay? So do apply the same. It's easy learn AI as the code. You will be seeing the price for free, okay?
Mayank Aggarwal: Great. Yeah, I think that was all, from my end.
Krish Naik: Okay, perfect. I think, Paul, we can start the doubt clearing now. I think we have covered almost everything. From next Saturday's session, guys, we will start the installation, software installation, and then we will also go ahead and start with the RAG, okay?
Krish Naik: Yeah, Paul, you can start unmuting, you can become the host.
Krish Naik: And, start… or do you want to give a break, and then probably start? It's up to you.
PAUL: Yeah, I think we can start from 10.30.
Krish Naik: Yeah. Okay.
PAUL: So let's take a 10 minutes break, guys, and then probably start the doubt clearing.
Krish Naik: Now, doubt clearing will be, like, first-come, first-served basis. We will be allowing one person to talk at a time, and don't worry, we will try to cover everybody's clear doubt, unless or until we don't cover everybody's doubt, we will not stop the session, okay?
Krish Naik: Okay.
Krish Naik: And sessions are on Saturdays and Sundays from 9am, okay, till, I think, 1pm or 2PM, it can go based on the doubt.
Krish Naik: Thank you. Okay, Paul, let's go.
PAUL: Okay, let me start the timer, guys, so we'll start from 10 today.
PAUL: Yeah, everyone, welcome back, okay? So, now I will start taking questions. So, whoever is there, they can raise their hand.
PAUL: Okay, I think everybody can see your raise hand option in your Zoom window. Okay, so simply you can click on raise your hand, and I'll be taking your questions one by one.
PAUL: Now, one important thing, so right now we have, like, more than 180 students here, as I can see. Okay, so simply, like, if 100 people race, like, I will be taking the questions one by one. Okay, so it will take time, so don't think that I won't be taking your question, okay? So…
PAUL: Let me start with… So, right now, I think…
PAUL: Sachin is there. Okay, so I will start with Sachin, then… first, Sachin, you go, then Rajat.
PAUL: Then, Mohammad, Michael, Sharad, I will come to you guys one by one, okay? So, Sachin, I think we can start with you.
Sachin Garg: Yeah, hi, Bon. yeah, thanks for this,
Sachin Garg: Actually, I was just talking about one small thing. I was also going through your RAC bootcamp, the ODEMI course. I just want to understand how it is different from this course, the one which I am just enrolled with. Is it more advanced, or what is the difference in between?
PAUL: Alright, so, like, yes, for sure, as this is a live course, things will be much more advanced, and here we'll be talking much more from the research and the production perspective.
Sachin Garg: Okay, okay.
PAUL: In the Udemy course, Christopher has covered all the important concepts.
PAUL: Now, the idea is to use those concepts and build a full-scale application.
Sachin Garg: Okay, okay.
Sachin Garg: Got it, got it, Paul. Thanks, thank you.
PAUL: Okay, alright, let's check.
PAUL: Next, Rajat.
Rajat Khanna: High boy.
Rajat Khanna: Hope I'm older.
PAUL: Yes, you are.
Rajat Khanna: Yeah, so my question is, related to, first, is the system requirement? So is there any specific system requirement that we need to have when we'll be going to the advanced concepts?
PAUL: I think, see, right now in 2025, if you have a 16GB RAM, okay, Core i5 or a Ryzen 7, it works.
Rajat Khanna: So, mine means my M1…
PAUL: GP.
Rajat Khanna: Yeah, M1 will work, no? M1…
PAUL: Yeah, yeah, even… see, Maya will be teaching you on M1 Pro.
Rajat Khanna: Okay, I have M1 Pro 16GB, so I will be teaching on that one thing.
Rajat Khanna: Okay, and the other question is, related to, technical experience. So, I am overall 10 years of experience into front-end UI.
Rajat Khanna: So, great knowledge in JavaScript and all the oops concept. So, I have been doing Python from past one month, so I have a strong grip on Python, not using any specific
Rajat Khanna: libraries, so I think, hope that that is sufficient.
PAUL: Yes, see, if you are having 10 years, so similar things, the idea, see, in this course, we'll be building APIs.
PAUL: You are good with UI. Okay, so for example, if you are working with React, Next.js, okay, so any type of those frameworks, very specifically, once we build the APIs, even though you have to do the integration.
PAUL: With respect to the UI. Okay, so, like, for other students, because in other courses also, we have seen people building, like, crazy UI. Now the other students think how he has built it. So, simply, like, I know that you can do it with others, because right now, we'll be focusing majorly on APIs here, back-end part.
Rajat Khanna: Yeah, yeah, so means my question was, means I am not a pro in Python, but from past month, I'm learning Python and doing my hands-on and everything. Not specifically used any, libraries related to Python, only the basic programming and functions and all things.
PAUL: If you're good in JavaScript, I know you are good in JavaScript, so it's not a big deal. You have to be just good in any one programming language, then you can… because Python is much easier if I try to compare it with JavaScript, or Java, or Go again, okay? So it won't be a problem.
Rajat Khanna: Okay, that's it. Thank you very much.
PAUL: Alright, Raja.
PAUL: Next, there is Mohammad Michael Sharud, okay?
PAUL: So, yes, 3 people, so one by one, you can go ahead.
Michael Sampath: So let me start, this is Michael.
PAUL: Yeah, my good work.
Michael Sampath: So the question is, I'm interested in the offline LLM,
Michael Sampath: So I've created a small rag, which is uses… doesn't use internet at all.
Michael Sampath: So, do you cover anything similar to that?
PAUL: Yes, we'll be… see, right?
Michael Sampath: Underlying question… underlying question is, I mean, I'm in a different country, and
Michael Sampath: Here, they do not allow AI at all, absolutely not. It should not reach the internet. So I have to create an offline RAG which works strictly offline.
Michael Sampath: So do you cover such… something like that?
PAUL: Yes, we'll be covering. Very specifically right now, for example, with respect to offline, I'll be taking an example with respect to Ulama in this course.
PAUL: Okay, the… right now, not custom LLMs, the available LLMs.
PAUL: through OLAMA, the models. Okay, so that part we'll be talking about, how to create embeddings, local embeddings, nothing, like, without the intent.
PAUL: Yes, we'll be talking about that, Michael.
Michael Sampath: Awesome. And one other last question is, I'm sending a lot of questions, and I don't see anybody reading my question. Am I chatting on the right window?
PAUL: No, no, you are chatting, see, right now, it's more than 100 people right in the chat, one shot, we are only 3 people. Okay, so right now, we're looking into it. So, yes, as Mike mentioned, if you have any question, you can let me know right now. That's why it's a one-to-one discussion.
Michael Sampath: Perfect. Thank you very much.
Mohammed Sahad C P: Hello, son.
PAUL: Yes.
Mohammed Sahad C P: Am I audible?
PAUL: Yes, Mama Diwar.
Mohammed Sahad C P: Thank you, sir, for the opportunity. Sir, my question is, what are the, possible career paths, we can acquire with this course and, course and knowledge, gained from this course?
PAUL: There are… see, now, if you're asking very specifically, like, Gen AI engineer, AI engineer, or the term can be only data scientist also, okay, so many things that comes. Don't just be very specific to a profile.
PAUL: the core part is the things that you are teaching, it is completely applicable to the Gen AI, and very specifically, like, the AI world. So anything, like, for data science and other stuff, that also comes into the picture. Because very specifically, if I say the term data scientist, like, a data scientist can do anything, because at the end of the day, like, you will be working with data.
PAUL: Okay, so, like, majorly, all the major profiles will be open to you. But for data science, there are a few other things, like, you have to know machine learning, deep learning, those stuff also come into the picture, but this is much more highly, I will say, much more towards… aligning towards Gen AI part.
PAUL: Generative AI. I hope you get my point.
Mohammed Sahad C P: Sir, one more question, sir.
PAUL: Yes.
Mohammed Sahad C P: With, from only this, course can be, land on any joke.
PAUL: From this course, we will give you the fundamentals, okay, with respect to applications part and the research part. Now, you have to start applying, simply, okay? But don't think about, see, yeah, like the AI space, there are a lot of things. When you apply in an organization now, what is their requirement?
PAUL: Now, that is the main thing. You have to see your skill set, whether it's matching to this.
PAUL: I can say that from this particular course, if somebody is applying for a Gen AI engineer, I can say that more than 40% of the skill set that we'll be covering. But there are other things also in the Gen AI space, like only working with LLMs. Okay, now that's why I'm thinking. Then, also working with ops, like the LLM ops part, that is that 20%.
PAUL: Okay, so it's not about… I cannot say we are covering the 100% skill set, but the major things we'll be covering. Right now, in 2025, what are the major things that are going… okay, the students, that they are learning for applying a job, there are many people who are looking for a switch, everybody. This will be very, very helpful.
Mohammed Sahad C P: Thank you, son, thank you.
PAUL: Alright, Muhammad.
Sharad Nautiyal: Hi, Paul, this is Sherid.
PAUL: Yeah, Sean.
Sharad Nautiyal: Just wanted to check. So, there are two courses mentioned in Udemy for this course. One is, building AI Agents, Agentic AI system via Microsoft.
Sharad Nautiyal: And then complete generative AI course. So, these are the two, right? That's all.
PAUL: Yes.
Sharad Nautiyal: And these coupons, they make, it at cost 500 rupees, or make… make it at… make it free, of course.
PAUL: So right now, in this particular, like, see, in Udemy, what you get, basically, monthly, like, we can provide you a certain number of coupons for free. So generally, for our paid students who have enrolled to our live batches, we provide them for free.
PAUL: That's the idea. Now, what happens, just think about, okay, now we share the coupon, now some students share it here and there. Okay, now, once they start, sometimes the coupons might get expired. Like, few people are telling it's not working for me, the link, it.
Sharad Nautiyal: I am also… I am also writing it down.
PAUL: That can be, because I know Mayang and Krista just created the coupon.
PAUL: Okay, so just. Now, probably, if somebody is sharing outside this, okay, in some other groups, I know it will be exhausted. Like, every month we do share. It's not about that. We are sharing only right now, today, in the induction.
PAUL: Okay, like, next month also, if we are coming with any new courses in Nigodemi, then also we do share with our students.
Sharad Nautiyal: But I think I tried within seconds, but it didn't work.
PAUL: Which one is not working?
Sharad Nautiyal: So, it didn't work for both the courses.
PAUL: both the courses, just be sure the coupon code at the end of the day, because I think, that matters.
Sharad Nautiyal: I tried from the book, Steve, that link also, and I tried directly also, and .
PAUL: Nicholas?
Sharad Nautiyal: Another case is both.
PAUL: From my chat history, just wait, let me go. One is this one.
Sharad Nautiyal: I checked with one of my friends also, who is there in this course. For him also, it didn't work, so…
Sharad Nautiyal: We both tried immediately, but…
PAUL: Just wait, because with respect to the chat, I'm just sharing, like, last time Carissa shared, Okay…
PAUL: I can't paste it in the chat.
PAUL: Mank, are you there?
PAUL: Okay, because I don't know why I cannot paste it.
PAUL: Because the one with…
PAUL: One, just sweet.
PAUL: I cannot type it in the chat, I don't know why.
PAUL: But, the coupon, which was provided by Chris, sir, okay, so the, the last part was, like, free coupon.
PAUL: Right, free coupons. And the one with Meng, it was Lani Yang, that's why.
Sharad Nautiyal: Great, greatly.
Sharad Nautiyal: So both of them didn't work for me.
PAUL: Okay, probably… just try to check in in cognitive mode. Okay.
Sharad Nautiyal: Okay.
PAUL: Just try to have… because, like, if it's working for others, it should work.
Sharad Nautiyal: No, I checked with…
PAUL: Perfect.
Sharad Nautiyal: League also was there in this course. For him also, he did…
PAUL: Because, see, nothing, like, it comes from Udemy, we share it with the students.
Krish Naik: Okay, which location are you from?
Sharad Nautiyal: I'm from Delhi, and he's from Gurdo.
Krish Naik: Okay, Paul, allow him to share the screen, no, if possible.
PAUL: Okay, yes.
Krish Naik: Okay, just a second, just a second.
Krish Naik: Okay, just again, once again, click the link.
Krish Naik: What is the coupon getting applied? Just let me know.
PAUL: In the URL, just check one.
PAUL: At the end.
Krish Naik: Just click the link.
Krish Naik: And just let me know, like, what is the coupon URL… what is the coupon code that is getting applied? So that is not the coupon code, right? Amrith.
Krish Naik: Did you try?
PAUL: Prashant for you also, that is not the coupon code, ACC, that's not.
Krish Naik: Guys, come on, I've given the coupon code, now you want to publicly announce that coupon code so that you'll not get it then. The people will ally.
Sharad Nautiyal: You want me to share my screen, or… what?
Krish Naik: No, no, just tell me what coupon code is basically getting applied.
Sharad Nautiyal: Free coupons, and Learn AI.
Krish Naik: So free coupons is not working out there?
Sharad Nautiyal: No, no. It, it still says, 500-something, the price.
Krish Naik: What, 500-something means?
Sharad Nautiyal: That cost, cost of the course, it doesn't get applied, it means…
Krish Naik: It should.
Krish Naik: See, some other coupon code is basically getting applied, I'm saying.
Krish Naik: It's not getting applied?
PAUL: Once incident… Okay.
Krish Naik: Just check whether you already have that course or not, first of all.
Krish Naik: You don't have that course?
Sharad Nautiyal: No, I don't have that course.
Krish Naik: Are you sure?
Sharad Nautiyal: Yeah, yeah, I'm sure.
PAUL: Let me add you to panel. Okay, then the coupon code will be exposed, actually.
Krish Naik: Mmm.
PAUL: That's the main thing.
PAUL: What you can do, add to cart, if it's then $5.
Krish Naik: Add to cart, go to checkout, and then you apply the coupon.
PAUL: Then manually you apply the code.
Sharad Nautiyal: Okay.
PAUL: Try that.
Krish Naik: And this is for everyone.
Krish Naik: go… see, there are two things. Either that course may be in your dashboard already.
Sharad Nautiyal: Oh, okay. Okay, when I went to add to cart, then it made it free. Okay.
Krish Naik: So add to the cart, and then it'll make you free, okay? Guys, this is for everyone, okay?
Krish Naik: And I know this problem usually happens, Udemy does not allow that many free coupon codes, but anyhow…
Krish Naik: We're just trying our level best to do something.
Sharad Nautiyal: Thank you.
Krish Naik: Yeah.
PAUL: Alright, Sherald. Now, let's move to… okay, Karthik is there, then comes Arkamal, Krishanu…
PAUL: Yes, Karpik, you can go ahead.
Karthik M: Yeah, hello, am I audible?
PAUL: Dian Prattack.
Karthik M: Yeah, so my question is about, these interview-level things.
Karthik M: So for, only about Gen AI, if you are applying. So, currently, there are a lot of things they're asking. I have attended, like, two to three interviews.
Karthik M: So they're coming… coming up with TensorFlow, PyTarch, everything.
PAUL: Yeah, because the fundamentals are data science.
PAUL: the journey starts from, like, Python, stats, machine learning.
PAUL: Now, okay, deep learning, okay, that's why NLP, computer vision, then the Gen AI journey started. It was, like, starting from 2020 to end. Okay, so that's why, like, if somebody is applying, okay, the idea is that you should know the fundamentals.
Karthik M: Okay, so, but… but is it really needed, or is it okay to have an overall picture on those things, or… because I don't have opportunity… I did not get opportunity to work on TensorFlow or anything. If you will create a project also, it will be like a portfolio project, it is not a product-level,
Karthik M: product-level projects also. So that is the reason I'm just asking, are you guys going to help us in the mock interviews and role?
Karthik M: In this.
PAUL: Absolutely.
Karthik M: vision.
PAUL: with respect to interviews, very specifically the things that are part of this course, because I cannot bring PyTorch, TensorFlow, MXNet, those things right here.
PAUL: That will be totally overwhelming for others. It's a very specific requirement of an organization.
PAUL: Okay, so that's why. Like, probably they might have a product, okay, on top of TensorFlow or PyTorch that is running on top of that, that they want to add some type of agent.
PAUL: Okay, now, very specifically, if I'm working with computer vision, that's what I do. For example, if I build some type of image classification, or a segmentation, or an object detection, so what I will do, I will be wrapping that particular module, okay, to an agent and then. So that's why knowing that core fundamental actually helps you.
PAUL: And how many years of experience you have?
Karthik M: IT industry, I have already 9 years of experience.
PAUL: Then 9 years of experience, the expectation will be there.
PAUL: Nothing we can do. Like, 9 years, like, anyone above 6 years or 7 years, the idea is that you should be comfortable with the fundamentals of data science, because that is still, like, the core fundamentals that people have been applying from 2016.
PAUL: That's like…
Karthik M: Yeah.
Karthik M: So, one more question. So, I'm just creating a bot, chatbot, that will replace the analytics team in my company.
Karthik M: That will text to SQL level with the Llama 2. Is this a good idea to go ahead? I'm just, getting an idea about that, because in my company, they're not allowing us to do this, but I just want to show them.
PAUL: Yes, approach is good, but there are a few frameworks like VANA.A and others that you can use very specifically for tasks like SQL to text and those type of tasks. I don't know exactly what is your tech stack.
PAUL: But, like, yes, you can work with Lama 3, I know Lama 3 is good.
PAUL: Okay, or probably, like…
PAUL: If you want to go with open source, like Maverick is there, and others, yes, those are good, I can say.
PAUL: Yeah, okay, but for the interview level, this is a good one, right? Because I can showcase that this is… Yes, probably. Majorly, most of the organizations are working with SQL-based databases, like Postgres and others, so yes.
Karthik M: Sure.
PAUL: Partial.
Karthik M: Thank you so much. Thanks.
PAUL: Alright, Arctic. Next.
rkamal: Hey, Bon.
PAUL: Yep.
rkamal: So my question is regarding, the project. Are we also covering any medical chatbot kind of project here?
PAUL: The medical chatbot I don't have. That is not very domain-specific. The idea is to make it generic. Now, see, in our use case, we can take some medical data.
PAUL: Okay, that's the thing. The idea is not to keep things domain-specific, rather than to make it generic. You bring your own data, you plug and play.
PAUL: I hope you get my.
rkamal: But we would learn that kind of skill set that is required to create that kind of.
PAUL: Yes, I'll be telling you that, yes, now this is how you build a rack. Now, any guy, probably from law, finance, others, like, telecommunication, they can bring their own data. So, the idea is not to be dominel-specific.
PAUL: Okay, we will try to keep things generic with respect to data.
rkamal: Right, right. And one more thing, like, I do hear the term an automation framework.
rkamal: So, by any chance, that is required to learn, in this course as well?
PAUL: Are you a developer?
rkamal: Not a developer, I'm at an architect level in the organization.
PAUL: Alright, so, like, previously, you have some type of development experience, or you are handling a team.
rkamal: Did I get a kind of profile, my…
PAUL: Okay, like, data engineering profile. NA10 is, pretty much the no-code stuff.
PAUL: Okay, because at a certain point of time, I think that there are certain limitations with respect to notebook.
PAUL: When you are actually building a full-scale product, okay, your entire product cannot be built with respect to no code-based solution.
PAUL: Okay, for customizations and other stuff, you need. So, N10 is really good, if I talk from the no-code point of view. Okay, so really, you can build quickly agency and other stuff. Yes, a lot of customizations, but really, like, if you are building a full-fledged product.
PAUL: then you have to come to some other frameworks, that's why. Anything is good for beginners. If you're building a prototype, I will say thumbs up. Okay, but really, if you're making it into production, okay, so then I will suggest that, okay, probably that might not be a good choice for a long time.
rkamal: Might be creating the MVP, right? Yes.
PAUL: For prototyping MVP, it's really, really good.
rkamal: client presentations, release. In that case, we can go for the init automation.
PAUL: But project onboarding, you can showcase that, yes, really, we can do this later on, like, but behind the scenes.
PAUL: Like, even that pure HDLC thing comes into the picture.
rkamal: But in creating the real-time production grid system, it is not really accurate, right?
PAUL: Yes, I will say that it's not. Now, see, if it is a very, very small feature, very, very small, okay, then probably you might use it, because I feel that it can be part of your main system, but it cannot be the main system. I hope you get my point.
rkamal: Understood.
rkamal: Yeah, thank you, Sue.
PAUL: Alright.
PAUL: Next, Krishanu.
Krishanu Santra: Hello, sir.
Krishanu Santra: I don't have any questions, but I'm here to just tell you a thank you so much, sir. You, to my side, to Krista. The way you make the courses affordable is pretty amazing, and I'm here to just, say you thank you to all, and, is Krista here?
Krishanu Santra: present in the…
Krish Naik: Yeah, I'm here, I'm here, please.
Krishanu Santra: Thank you, sir, thank you so much, and you don't know how much you helped me in my career. I bought all your Udemy courses, and just, although I just completed the four courses as Basic to Advanced Mathematics.
Krishanu Santra: Python with RSI and, Data Analyst Bootcamp, and data science bootcamp. My question is, do I need to, go through, any more thing to understand this code much better?
Krish Naik: Yeah, today I've given you some free courses, no? You take that also.
Krishanu Santra: I also, I bought that also in previous. Thank you, sir, thank you so much.
Krish Naik: No worries, then, see, in the future, anything that we are coming up, we usually share all the, in our live batches, okay? For free.
Krishanu Santra: Thank you, thank you. Just here to talk to you, and, thank you, sir. And I am very excited to, just live, in this live program.
Krishanu Santra: And we're excited to work with you in future. Thank you, sir.
Krish Naik: Thank you.
PAUL: Alright, let's move to our next participant. There is Avijit Day.
PAUL: Then, Sanjayesh Shagur, then comes Kirish.
PAUL: 3 people I have unmuted.
Abhijit Dey: Yeah, hi, Paul. Can you hear me?
PAUL: Yeah, yeah.
Abhijit Dey: Hi, good morning, Paul, Mayank, and Krish. Yeah, first of all, thank you so much. I've been an Arden follower, though. So, my primary question is that, you know, as you were
Abhijit Dey: taking us through the syllabus, you would… we are… we definitely learned that we are going to do a lot of things through AWS, and then there will be certain models, say, OpenAI will be involved. So I just wanted to understand how much of the other extra things that we have to buy in, say, in terms of services with respect to AWS usage.
Abhijit Dey: Or even OpenAI, just wanted to get an idea.
PAUL: OpenAI, probably, like, we will try to stick to Gemini. Okay, it's free, with a certain limit.
PAUL: In some cases, we might go with OpenAI. Probably a $5 refill is more than enough for this entire course.
PAUL: Okay, now probably see, if I am taking A document of 1,000 pages.
PAUL: For example, okay, now, if you use OpenAI embeddings, the $5 credit will be exhausted.
PAUL: totally exhausted. Okay, so you have to be smart. You don't do it. I can execute it from my end. You have to take that decision. Okay, so really, it is not important. You can crop that PDF into 10 pages, and then you can do it. A simple example I am giving, because it totally depends upon the data sources.
PAUL: Okay, try to always stick to smaller ones for your learning. You get the idea, I'll be taking a bigger amount of data, but you don't do it. So I feel that a $5 is more than enough.
PAUL: Okay. And you have to be a little bit smart, because yes, I will be telling you, okay, don't do this, don't do this, so please follow that in the class.
Abhijit Dey: Sure, so primarily to execute the concept is the primary idea. It's not the quantifying of the content. And with respect to the AWS service.
PAUL: Yes.
Abhijit Dey: I have not used AWS, I have only worked on GCP, and I'm a bit on the.
PAUL: Okay, so, like, that is fine, like, here also, like, with respect to instances very specifically. If I'm working with GPU instances, it will be much costly, but majorly we'll be using EC2.
PAUL: Okay, so EC2 probably with a 2GB RAM or a 4GB RAM. So, probably, like, your monthly bill won't cross 100 rupees, that I can say. Probably 4 months, 400 rupees that you can take it. Okay, like, every month we won't be working with deployments, probably the last 3 months we'll be working.
PAUL: So, 100 rupees, 100 rupees, you can keep it. That also, I'm telling it in the higher point of view. It can be 200 also, in total.
PAUL: So, don't worry about that. But, like, if I share, like, majorly all the services are there. The idea is that you start the service, and then you close it instantly. Once the app is working, you do the testing, then you close all the services. That's the major thing. If you forget somehow, for example, if you're working with AppRunner.
PAUL: Not AppRana, I think, Fusel, for example, like, you have worked with GCP. In GCP, you have, that, cloud,
PAUL: GCP run cloud, or which service is there, like, directly, it works, okay? Now, if you keep on running it, it becomes costly. So, always close the services. Like, I'll be destroying all the major services that I'll be launching in a certain class, and I'll be telling you, please, okay, so don't start and then forget.
PAUL: Because after 7 days, you will come and then say, Paul, I got a bill of 3,000 rupees. It already happened with few students in other batches. So just be active. If you are proactive in class, there won't be any problem.
Abhijit Dey: Thank you so much, Paul, for that idea. Thank you.
PAUL: All right.
PAUL: Let's move to our next. So, I think anyone, Garish or Sanjay, you guys can go ahead.
Sanjay Sagore: Hello, Park.
PAUL: Definitely.
Sanjay Sagore: Yeah, yeah. So, just one question is here, whether we'll be building the conversational AI chatbot, because sometimes, you know, in interviews, they have asked me regarding this.
PAUL: We will be building chatbots, but again, the idea is building GenAI chatbots.
PAUL: we won't be using, because you can build chatbots in more than, I can say, 100 ways.
PAUL: But we'll be sticking to the GenAI part, very specifically. Okay, because there are other very specific frameworks, like, everybody has that, like Amazon, there is Lex, from Google, there is Dialogflow. Okay, so that's why. I hope you get my point. The idea is sticking to Gen AI-based access, like, GenAI-based chatbot.
PAUL: Okay, and that's Available for it.
Sanjay Sagore: Okay, but building for some specific domain, something like that, suppose I have someone else.
PAUL: domain, the data will only change. You know, again, the idea is I'll be teaching you generic. You can bring your own domain-specific data.
Sanjay Sagore: Okay, okay. Second thing, whether we will be working on the Google pull-up, because it will require the Gmail, sorry, that, Google Drive.
Sanjay Sagore: Sorry, but, right now, Alex…
PAUL: So we say, like, I'll be working with Jupyter Notebooks, now the question comes, you can execute it in Google Collab?
Sanjay Sagore: Okay.
PAUL: or in your local system. I'll be using Major League local system. I switch to Google Local App if I need a GP.
PAUL: Okay, because that's the only thing. Otherwise, if something runs in my local, then why I will switch to… I will provide you the IPYNV. Okay, so simply, like, if your local system is not so much good, okay, you can upload that notebook to collab, and you can do the execution. I hope you get my point.
Sanjay Sagore: Actually, I have my office system right now, this office laptop, so here the Google Drive not work. It is disabled, so that's my one.
PAUL: Right? So don't worry, it will be majorly local things, okay? So right now, majorly in a course where I use a lot of GPUs, then only I switch to color. That's why. So don't worry, it will be much more local-based implementations.
Sanjay Sagore: Okay, thank you, Paul, for the time.
Girish Ghode: Hey, Paul. Greet you.
PAUL: finish.
Girish Ghode: So my question is, will there be any use case based where we will be working with the relational database?
PAUL: Mmm… a relational database…
PAUL: I… don't think… because the data source really doesn't matter to me. It can be any data source, but…
Girish Ghode: Because…
PAUL: No.
Girish Ghode: the project which I will be working, very soon in my org, we have a large relational database, on top of which we want to build a rack.
PAUL: Okay, because very specifically, working with, like, SQL-based, I don't think there… in the project, we have such. But, like, in the class, I can discuss about how to work with that, probably by taking an example with Vana and others.
PAUL: That I can showcase. Okay?
Girish Ghode: Yeah, okay, thank you.
PAUL: Alright, so next, we have people who have already pleased to lower your hands. Okay, so there is Sai Rahul, Chandan Kumar Meshra.
PAUL: Noggish?
PAUL: 3 people, yeah.
PAUL: Chandan, I think you have.
Chandan Kumar Mishra: Yes.
PAUL: You can go add anyone, Sai or Chamber.
Chandan Kumar Mishra: Yeah, am I audible, Paul?
PAUL: the agenda.
Chandan Kumar Mishra: Yeah, yeah. So, first of all, the most important
Chandan Kumar Mishra: part of the question is, I will ask later, but first of all, I would like to give a big thanks to you and Kresh.
Chandan Kumar Mishra: And, Mayank, for giving back to the society, I mean, this is really… I would like to appreciate. And I know that what kind of efforts are going in designing the course and making it affordable. So you guys are really doing a great job, so big kudos to you.
Chandan Kumar Mishra: And coming to the question part, do I need to have a cloud subscription to try out things here at my.
PAUL: Yes, an AWS account.
Chandan Kumar Mishra: Okay, so you would suggest that subscription there, okay. And, what level of…
PAUL: It's not a subscription fee. The idea is you create a new account, you keep your card attached, or through EPA, at least something. Like, if something paid comes up, because in some cases, there will be certain services that will be paid. Everything doesn't come under free tire.
PAUL: Okay, you have to understand. So, that's the only thing. That's why I told you, a monthly, you can take that entire estimation, it will be less than, like, 200, 300.
Chandan Kumar Mishra: Yeah, so the free tier I can take, right? I mean, that will…
PAUL: Yes.
Chandan Kumar Mishra: It's mission-efficient, at least, to try out the.
PAUL: Yes, majorly we'll be doing the things in free tire, but in some cases, so probably just think of how I have an application which cannot run in a 2GB system. Probably in that case, I need to switch from a free tire to a paid tire instance.
PAUL: Okay, totally depends upon the application. We will try to stick, but in some ways.
Chandan Kumar Mishra: Okay, and I think you have covered it, but I just want to go a little deep into that. What level of Gen AI knowledge is expected as a prerequisite here? Like, is it at the theoretical level, or even at some level of understanding of the underlying details as well?
PAUL: We will start from scratch, from the RAG perspective. So, the main, like, see, two things, RAG and elements. This course is focused much more from the RAG perspective. So, we will start from scratch. I told you I'll be taking a journey starting from 2021.
PAUL: So, things should… will be from scratch, and what are the things right now in 2025?
PAUL: So, you really don't need to go somewhere or look into. I will cover majorly all the major concepts.
Chandan Kumar Mishra: Okay, yeah, that's… thanks for this, Paul. And… and, one last question, is that, will you be more focusing on the open source or the enterprise solutions, tool?
PAUL: I will always start with the open source, then I will move to the proprietary ones.
Chandan Kumar Mishra: Okay, yeah.
Chandan Kumar Mishra: Yeah, thanks, thanks, Paul, and Christian Bank, if you're listening, yeah.
PAUL: Yep.
Chandan Kumar Mishra: Thanks a lot, guys.
PAUL: Super.
Krish Naik: Thank you, sir. I'm here only, sir. I'm back.
Chandan Kumar Mishra: Yeah, yeah.
Krish Naik: Thank you.
Chandan Kumar Mishra: Christian.
Krish Naik: Yep.
PAUL: Next.
sai rahul: I thought.
PAUL: item.
sai rahul: So, my question is more on the prerequisites part that is there, right? So, again, I'm coming more from a management background with
sai rahul: basic understanding of Python, like, we've worked with some of the developers and so on and so forth, but, like, I have an understanding I could do some of minimal coding and all, but I just wanted to understand, is there something
sai rahul: do we have a list of links, or list of courses that we could do, or we could practice that… I know this is a long, long process, right? Like, we have almost, like, 4 months of course. Is there something that we could practice myself, along with these, so that I could improve and understand it better as and when the course progresses?
sai rahul: reality.
PAUL: Yeah, it's already Chris and Meg already, I think they have shared. So, in every UDME course, there is a prerequisite part with respect to Python. If you're comfortable with Python, there won't be any problem, because, see, I told you, like, till modulate, things will be easier.
PAUL: So, like, the initial two months, if you are coping up with the things, if you are comfortable with the basic Python, then slowly, slowly, because I'll be not teaching you object-oriented programming completely, but I'll be showing you the application. So, if you're familiar, at least, you know the concept, you understand, okay, this is how it is working.
PAUL: Then you can easily go back.
sai rahul: Got it, got it. Yeah, I think, those courses I'll definitely go through, and I'll continue to practice.
PAUL: Alright, fine.
PAUL: Next, I'll… let me unmute… Viraj is there. Hey, Viraj. Modasar… Then comes, Abhijit Proshti.
PAUL: Yes, 3 people.
PAUL: Yes, anyone can go ahead.
PAUL: You're not.
Mudassar.Hakim: Good morning. Good stuff so far. I'm really looking forward to it, and the content-wise things look very promising. I was just looking for more structure around,
Mudassar.Hakim: the assignments and projects. So basically, I have got a good idea of what all we are going to be covering in the course, right? I think we have a module-wise breakup. What I was looking forward to is considering 4 to 5 months of period, of duration that we have.
Mudassar.Hakim: Right? On the Saturday, Sundays we are going to meet. If you could, structure those modules according to those sessions.
Mudassar.Hakim: That would be really great, and more productively around the kind of assignments and projects we are targeting for each of those sessions, so that, you know, I have a foresight that, you know, by
Mudassar.Hakim: Month one, I would be getting ready with these sort of things, and I have something more, concrete and tangible at my hand, presentable manner. You know, it gives me better to plan things. If you could… if you guys can, you know, put that thing, that would be really, really a huge benefit.
PAUL: Alright, now, see, really, like, I cannot plan exactly, like, in the next month or in the 10th class, exactly what will go on. But, like, a rough estimation, if I say, like,
PAUL: Like, we know, like, in this week, we'll be covering that. So, exactly on Saturday and Sunday, like, what is going on that, I cannot say, but I know in this week, probably, because some topic might take two weeks.
Mudassar.Hakim: target, even a weekly outcome.
PAUL: target, I can plan a very specific sheet, then I will create, and probably my next.
Mudassar.Hakim: A ballpark.
PAUL: I can share.
PAUL: Okay. I don't want to hold anyone accountable here to their neck. It is just that… It will be a rough estimation that I'll be doing, and based on that, okay? Assignments or something like, after every class, I'll be telling you the things that I have applied, the idea is that you always replicate it with a different data source.
PAUL: Okay, you can use the core concept, because generally, initially, it will be a lot of Jupyter notebooks. The idea is that if you can replicate it into an object-oriented programming application, okay, attach Fast API with them, that will be my thing. If you're not comfortable, fine, because after one month, again, I'm going to talk about those things.
Mudassar.Hakim: No, that's a fair point. That's a fair point. It's mostly around the kind of projects I can create, because I think so my primary intention during this course is that how much hands-on can I do?
Mudassar.Hakim: With every session. Knowledge-wise, I think I've picked up bits and pieces from everywhere. I did some courses also. So, knowledge-wise, I think I'm there, but from a practical…
Mudassar.Hakim: project-wise, you know, I think I'm not there yet, especially from a productionized, project perspective. I'm still lacking that understanding. Although I'm working as a senior engineering manager, I am not that hands-on today, but I definitely work with the team so that I can govern things better. So that perspective, I was looking at, and yeah.
PAUL: Yes.
Mudassar.Hakim: And from an aside.
PAUL: I will be talking from that perspective a lot, actually, from decision making. That's why, like, I'll be talking about research. Rarely anybody talks about research, if you know. Okay, so, like, the idea is that you do your research, you can tell your team, okay, now this is the research, try to at least build a simple POC, okay, to test it out.
PAUL: But the others, simply.
Mudassar.Hakim: I want to lead the talk, you know, that's the thing. I want to lead by showing by example, right? Okay, this is what is different, and I expect others to follow on and replicate that behavior, because I would be a little unfair for me to expect others to do something which I was not able to do things in the first place, right?
PAUL: Yes, like, even I do it, see, just think about there are so many new things that comes around, everything I cannot do. But I always, like, look into the research, probably I list out the things for my team.
PAUL: Okay, so that they can actually implement the things, and then I can actually take a better decision. Yep. Okay, so, yeah, it happens, like, with everyone, because everything I cannot do by myself, that's…
Mudassar.Hakim: Absolutely. So, just to summarize my points, one is, if you could have some kind of a breakup, tentatively, I'm not… I'm looking at a ballpark, but just from a perspective, that will help. Secondly, the research papers, right? If you could put it somewhere, that would be really.
PAUL: I will always put the archive links of those papers, like, class-wise, in every class, whenever I show you a paper, I'll be talking, okay? But, like, initially in the same exercise sheet, I can create another page, and I can list out all the papers that will be doing it in the course, okay?
Mudassar.Hakim: If we can make it more collaborative, maybe just, you know, spitballing here, maybe if we could add some kind of a place within your site, right, where we have the feed, workshop, courses, messages, a section over there that basically is like a library of papers for people.
PAUL: I don't think it is possible from that side, back-end side. Okay, really? Like, I can put it in the sheet-wise, and then the lecture-wise, in the resources section, you'll be getting, like, the class PDF. Okay, then the research paper link. That way, we can do it. That way, from the backend, really, it is not possible.
Mudassar.Hakim: No worries, I just thought of sharing things, yeah. Thanks, thanks, Doc. Forward to good stuff. Thanks.
PAUL: Alright, Madhasa, next.
Abhijit_Prusty: Hey, Paul, Abhijit here.
PAUL: Yeah, Vijit.
Abhijit_Prusty: Paul, first of all, I would like to thank you, Chris, and Mayang.
Abhijit_Prusty: For creating such amazing courses.
Abhijit_Prusty: Which is basically a soft and crisp content, and which is…
Abhijit_Prusty: actually highlighting the important aspects of the current AI industry with agentics and all what is going on. And I'm personally very much excited to meet Chris, because from the day one, I think from 2004, I've been following him.
Abhijit_Prusty: Not 4, I think basically for the last two years. I've been following him for his courses and learning AI, and I'm very excited to see him live on the call.
Abhijit_Prusty: So, Chris, thanks for creating such amazing content, and the philosophy you have is to keep learning AI, which is a very good thing for everyone. Your message is very good.
Abhijit_Prusty: And, I really like the course, and basically the amount for which you are giving such a huge
Abhijit_Prusty: and learning. It is really amazing.
Abhijit_Prusty: And second thing, Paul, which I wanted to say is, like, in terms of the course, right, I just wanted to understand is, like, I am a engineering lead, and my background is mainly in the development, and I'm currently working on this AI and all in my office.
Abhijit_Prusty: My interest towards this core was more in the RAG, because your course is mostly on the RAG, and it is designing the RAG world, which I'm more interested to learn. So what I wanted to know is, like, my skills in Python is very basic, so what I wanted to know is, like, if I want to meet the pace of the course.
Abhijit_Prusty: what all the things I should be focusing more on the Python, so that I can learn this, and whenever you guys are having the
Abhijit_Prusty: systems.
Abhijit_Prusty: my learning with the Python and whatever you teach, it meets, so that I can go and learn those concepts in Python, so that I can, whenever you teach the session, I can match it up. So I just wanted to understand, like, what are the areas I should focus more on the Python side?
PAUL: if you… if your fundamentals of Python are pretty much clear, okay, then it's more than fine, because here, syntactically, if I'm talking about, it will be much more about the new frameworks that we'll be talking in this course.
Abhijit_Prusty: Okay.
PAUL: Okay, and the object-oriented programming is very, very important, because that also comes under Python fundamentals only. Okay, like, I will be using functions for sure, but later on, like, probably when I'm building a full-scale application.
PAUL: At that particular point of time, it will be just like a complete Python package. Okay, so object-oriented programming is required in that particular respect. If you are not familiar, you can actually look into that particular oops, but other than that, if you are just comfortable with Python, it won't be such a big deal, because easily.
Abhijit_Prusty: So my, my background is basically into Java with object-oriented programming.
PAUL: Dude.
Abhijit_Prusty: visual.
PAUL: Then, yes, not a single issue. If you're from a Java background, really, because you know object-oriented programming much better as compared to Python in Kaizine.
Abhijit_Prusty: Yeah, so I've been in 15 years in Java only, so I just wanted to.
PAUL: Nothing to worry about.
Abhijit_Prusty: is, like.
PAUL: Nothing too old.
Abhijit_Prusty: Okay, then I'll focus more on that.
Abhijit_Prusty: And one last thing is, like, if…
Abhijit_Prusty: In the course which, in the course, right, when, we have this, the web, the pre-academy.
Abhijit_Prusty: Is there a possibility that,
Abhijit_Prusty: You also put the… these things, like the links which we were talking, right, in the previous question.
Abhijit_Prusty: They're somewhere, documented, or maybe in the chat when you do.
PAUL: Yes, yes, yes, that will be part, like, whatever the things that I'll be discussing, probably in a certain class, or as a resource, it will be always available in your dashboard. Okay. So don't worry about that, because I know, because, see, probably what happens,
PAUL: like, when I take doubts, that happens immediately, like, 10 people… 10 people will ask 10 different questions. Now, all those 10… so, doubt part, I don't keep it in the part, because that is very specific to a certain student.
PAUL: Okay, probably I might have shown 10 different links, but that is not related to the class, so the context is totally different. So that part, we never keep it in the dashboard. I'll be directly sharing it to you in the class.
PAUL: Okay, but the core part that will be discussed in the class, with that context, whatever the things that I am sharing, it will be part of your dashboard under the resources section.
Abhijit_Prusty: Sure. Thanks, Paul. That is what I wanted to know. Thanks, Chris. Thanks, Paul. Thanks, Mayan.
Krish Naik: Thank you, sir.
PAUL: Next, Viraj is there. Hey, Viraj.
Viraj: And article.
PAUL: Yes.
Viraj: Yes. So, yeah, my basic doubt was, I'm… I'm coming from DevOps background, and, the, currently the project in which I'm working, we are using all these technologies, like, like Agent EKI, and, mainly developers are working on that part. So, my basic question is, I'm excited to learn this, tech stack.
Viraj: But, when I look for job opportunities after this, how I can integrate my previous DevOps experience with this tech stack?
PAUL: Alright, Baraj.
Viraj: Yep.
PAUL: Okay, now it's something like… this question has been asked very specifically from the DevOps background. Okay, now for two types of roles, SRE and DevOps that I'll be talking about.
PAUL: Now, in the market, starting from 2024, there is a very specific, like, I can say one, thing that has been looking, like, the integration of AI with DevOps. Okay, and how many years of experience do you have?
Viraj: I have 7 years of experience.
PAUL: Okay, alright, so generally, like, anyone more than 6 or 7 years of experience, okay, so people are looking for an AI platform engine.
PAUL: Okay, now this is a new buzzword, like, AI plus the mixture of DevOps entirely with SRE. Okay, where you'll be handling the entire infra.
PAUL: Okay, so you have to look for that part. So, for that, what you need to learn, very specifically, the AI services which are available in a certain time. So, probably with respect to AWS, or with respect to Azure.
PAUL: Okay. Okay. And then the integration of those services to build your complete, like, whatever the platform that you were building.
Viraj: Okay, so that's why the term platform AI engineer.
PAUL: I know few people who have done this switch very specifically, okay, from SRE role to that AI platform engineer. So, very specifically, I told you about this, because entirely, like, you'll be working with Kubernetes and all those things that you have done in SRE. Okay, now with that, the integration of AI services, as simple as that.
Viraj: So, in that role, we'll be responsible for building these solutions as well, right?
PAUL: Yes, like, you'll be working with the engineers, because majorly what happens, like, I can say that every data scientist or everybody is not working in the ops team, that ops, like MLOps. Probably, like, if you're working now, if you're learning AI and others, you can be handling that.
PAUL: So, like, probably the team has done the containerization. Now, it's your job to pull that particular image, and from there, move it to certain staging, then probably to production, those things that will be controlled.
Viraj: And, for that specific role, will the data science foundations, fundamentals also be needed, like, machine learning.
PAUL: You should know the basics, the idea is not to go into a deep dive, because really, what matters to you is the container running successfully on Market.
PAUL: So that is part of the other team, like, whoever is working, because Aloni can't do everything, you have to understand. You have to always think from a perspective of teams.
PAUL: Okay, so yes, if you know the concept, it's good. Then you know exactly how the application is working, the entire flow of the application, okay? Like, from the starting point of the app.
PAUL: how it is doing, how it is agglating, so those things you will know. If you don't know a few concepts, really, it doesn't matter, because at the end of the day, you know that, okay, you will sit with the engineer, you will ask, okay, now, how the things are exposed here, you can simply look into the Docker script, you will get an overall idea, okay? But if you want to go deep dive, you can simply interact with the.
Viraj: And if you know the concepts, it becomes much easier.
Viraj: Okay.
Viraj: Sure, sure, Paul. Thanks. That helped great.
PAUL: Alright, Viraj.
PAUL: Next, there is Ajay Singh.
PAUL: Amit, Jan, Okay, then there's Kritika… Okay, Sonali…
Amit Jain: Can I speak? Amit until Friday?
PAUL: Yeah, I mean, it's go ahead.
Amit Jain: Okay, so, I have around 16 to 17 years of WorkX,
Amit Jain: And right now, I lead the Agentech AI product management for… in Accenture.
Amit Jain: So, the thing is that I'm not into coding anymore,
Amit Jain: Although I have an engineering counterpart.
Amit Jain: who's leading the team. I've been a developer in the beginning of my career, I mean, I started as an engineer.
Amit Jain: into data sciences, then did my MBA.
Amit Jain: Post my MBA, I've been in product roles.
Amit Jain: I mean, I've been reading, about these, GenAI, LLMs, RAG, context engineering, everything. So, conceptually, I learn… love to learn, because I'm… I love to learn maths and…
Amit Jain: All the mathematics behind what is happening in these algorithms.
Amit Jain: So, I just wanted to understand from your perspective, also, because
Amit Jain: the problems which I see now in production when we are building, products is that when you
Amit Jain: start to use these libraries, GitHubs.
Amit Jain: just as a boilerplate, right? Because when you start applying these.
Amit Jain: codes, whatever you get from internet or GitHubs, there are a lot of algorithms which are getting rolled out every day.
Amit Jain: new GitHub's coming up, they don't work.
Amit Jain: Because your data is different.
Amit Jain: Right, so the crux lies in understanding the fundamentals, behind these small things like context engineering.
Amit Jain: mostly in drag.
Amit Jain: It is about being able to chunk your data properly, have the right retrieval, Strategy, and then…
Amit Jain: Curating the prompt in such a way, or the context in such a way, that
Amit Jain: It fetches the right answer.
Amit Jain: Right, so that is where I feel that fundamentally, engineering team
Amit Jain: at least in my case, I've seen that engineering teams try to do things very fast, and then they…
Amit Jain: It doesn't work the way, as a product manager, I want, or my client won't.
Amit Jain: So…
Amit Jain: from your perspective, how would… how should I take learning, or how should I maximize my learning in this course, considering the fact that I'll not be coding anymore in my career, right? I mean, I'll not get to… I might do a project or I've done, project or two, I've built my small language model on weekends.
Amit Jain: I've done those drag engines also I've built, on weekends, like, a pet project, right?
Amit Jain: but now the expectations for me at an organizational level are very different.
Amit Jain: So, yeah, I just wanted to pick your brains on that.
PAUL: Okay, now, from your perspective, if I'm talking about, like, if you're handling an engineering thing, then also, like, this can be, but if you're competing to business, really, like.
Amit Jain: into business, I have to get into those discussions where I'm designing.
PAUL: Okay, if you are designing and architecting any type of engineering system with respect to AI, if I talk about, then things will be helpful, because I'll be talking about a lot of amount of research, like, for any leaders, any architect.
Amit Jain: Fresh paper every week, one, at least one.
Amit Jain: Yup.
PAUL: If you are into that, okay, then you will, because the idea is that you can take better decisions.
Amit Jain: For me, that will be the main thing.
PAUL: Yes, I will tell you, yeah, so that's why I told you, you know, like, starting from 2021 till 2025.
Amit Jain: All the major papers.
PAUL: with respect to RAG. So, at least I told how many types of RAG, that I'll be talking about, more than 20 types of RAG.
PAUL: Now you can think about from this, like.
PAUL: any team, if I'm talking about, they can build their ad within 7 days.
PAUL: But it is not always possible.
PAUL: Okay, you can build a bare minimum, I can say. If you really want to build a rack system with all the research that you have, okay, probably it might take 3 months, or even 6 months.
PAUL: If you have time, it totally depends upon the delivery, because at the end of the day, the really technical thing doesn't matter. For any projected two things, time and revenue.
PAUL: Okay, time and revision at the end of the day, because I also work sometimes with respect to the business part. So, really, what the technical team is doing, it really doesn't matter to me. Sometimes I need it fast, sometimes I can go through. So, like, in this particular course, I'll be talking about, like, how to make better decisions. So, based on the algorithms, like, each time, okay, after 6 months, this came, this came, this came. So, what are the pros and the cons?
PAUL: In that way, you know that, okay, so if somebody is implementing this later on, probably after one year, how to upgrade those systems, how to make them better.
PAUL: So, yes, I think in some case, if you know that, okay, so the pros and cons, you can take a better decision.
Amit Jain: I mean, see,
Amit Jain: The problem is that with GenAI coming in, people started thinking that data engineering, I mean.
Amit Jain: See, the garbage in, garbage out still holds true, right? With GenAI, we thought that we can just put in a data dump at the back end.
PAUL: No, no, no, it's not like that.
Amit Jain: It doesn't work.
PAUL: to do a lot of data preprocessing. That's why, very specifically, if you look into the curriculum, I've kept the module up.
Amit Jain: Oh, bye.
PAUL: Parthas.
PAUL: Okay, because to build a good rag, you have to do the data preprocessing first. You need good parsing. If your parser is bad, you can never build a good rag.
Amit Jain: And also, kind of, if you'll touch upon the fact that how do you… Use,
Amit Jain: memory effectively and… and the context effectively of the LLM, while sending out the final query to the LLM.
Amit Jain: Also, I've seen, affects the output of RAG.
PAUL: Yes, so there comes, like, a few concepts, like, query decomposition and expansion comes into the picture. Yes, we'll be talking about that very specifically with respect to retrievable waste systems.
Amit Jain: Sure, sure, thank you.
PAUL: Okay? Yeah. Alright. But you have to understand, it's much more technical. Like, business prospect will come with it.
Amit Jain: For me, I mean, it's okay that if I don't get to code, but then at the end of the day, even if I…
Amit Jain: see all of you, or I'll also try myself, right? It's not that I'm not gonna try. Like I said that I do coding on weekends for my pet projects, but I'll do that, but it is better for me, because I want to guide engineering teams properly whenever… Yes, that's the main…
PAUL: Even we want you to make better decisions at the end of the day, because right now, I know in the market, there are many people who know about RAC, but really in-depth RAC.
PAUL: Because if I talk about, like, we have been working with RAG for more than, like, 2.5 years, so we have seen that, how things are coming, and how things are going and changing. It means that you adopt something, just after 6 months, it becomes deprecated.
PAUL: And people who have done, like, 6 months back, their implementation, they won't be upgrading so much quickly. Okay, now the idea is that whether you want to take the decision, the system might work fine, but you can make it better.
PAUL: Okay, so what will be the probable upgrades that you can do? Okay, or plans after a year? So those things, yes, it will help you.
PAUL: Because this will be an incremental process, you know, that in one shot, nobody can make a fine product. Okay, it takes time. So, incremental process, so that's why I'll be talking about that incremental journey of rent.
PAUL: Alright, Amit.
Amit Jain: Thank you.
Singh, Ajay: Yeah, you called it?
Singh, Ajay: Good money.
PAUL: Yes, Ajay, alright.
Singh, Ajay: Yeah, thanks. First of all, thank you, Krish, Paul, and Mike, for putting this wonderful course, and then so much effort over.
Singh, Ajay: So, most of the questions are already asked by people, and that is already answered for me.
Singh, Ajay: Only thing I would like to ask, like, I'm working on my current project, I'm working on the evaluation of features like hallucination guardrails, factual checks, etc, with tools like Galileo, Arthur AI, and Allies Phoenix.
Singh, Ajay: So, how will this, we already built a POC for… we've done a POC for RAG application. So, how will this course gonna help me in this, if you,
Singh, Ajay: Can answer.
PAUL: Now, fee.
Singh, Ajay: From background, I'm a data engineer, I was a data engineer, but from past 2 months, 2-3 months.
PAUL: It's fine, it's fine, really. See, you have already built a POC on track. Now, really, I don't know how much time and research you have given on building that RAG. It works, it may fine, but really, do you know that? Can you make it better? Now the question comes.
PAUL: Okay, now, probably the things that I'll be discussing from that ride perspective, it might… like, you might feel that, okay, now, yes, this we can do, this we can implement.
PAUL: The idea is that, if you have already built a rack, it's fine, it's working. I know many people have built a rack, but how to make it better? What are the core components of a rack? How you can make your embedding much more efficient, much better? How can you make your retrievers? So, those things, the idea is that in a rack, there are so many components.
PAUL: Okay, now how to make and refine all those components step by step?
PAUL: Those things I'll be coming in depth. Now, even with respect to evaluation metrics, now, real evaluation people talk about, but to do an evaluation, you have to always create your own test set, based on your data.
PAUL: And this is where many people, they won't do only. They will tell me, Paul, you do it. Really, how can I do it for anyone? Because it's your data, you have to create an evaluation set, and based on that, you have to do the checks. There's nothing I can do. I can just show you a use case, so this is how the evaluation is being done.
Singh, Ajay: Okay, so… Because, yeah, this is what I did that, but, don't have the full understanding. I took some help online, some ChatGPT help also.
Singh, Ajay: But, the full understanding I don't have, and I'm pretty very new to this AI field, so that is why, I mean, I clearly…
PAUL: like, I'll be talking about the major metrics all, and even few major concepts that have been famous around 2024, like LLM as a church. Okay, so those things, yes, we'll be talking about in this course. So, I will say that, yes, if you have done something, okay, the idea is that from this course, you will get the idea how to improve that thing.
Singh, Ajay: With respect to time.
PAUL: Okay?
Singh, Ajay: Okay, okay, great, great, yeah. Thank you.
PAUL: Okay, so, Shanali or Kritika, Hi, okay, great.
Kritika Kumar: dope.
Kritika Kumar: Actually, I'm about how my laptop.
PAUL: automate that problem.
Kritika Kumar: Using my wife's.
PAUL: No issues, no issues, go ahead.
Kritika Kumar: Sorry for that confusion. So, yeah, first of all, I want to thank all of you for setting up such a wonderful course, and for sharing these wonderful Udemy courses, which have wonderful high rating. Thanks a lot for that. My first question is very simple.
Kritika Kumar: Is there any recommended sequence in which we should try to go through these courses which would help us ramp up faster and be ready for the next class?
Kritika Kumar: That is question number one. And, second question I have is, see, in, I'm basically a data engineer, work mostly on SQL, Power BI, setting up ETL pipelines, etc. In my team, we get asked a lot of questions if this data point is correct, if this is not correct, and we have to do…
Kritika Kumar: Similar type of repeated steps to do the analysis and say, yes, the data is correct, or no, there is a bug in my code, and I have to go and fix it.
Kritika Kumar: So, after going through this course, would it be possible for me to automate that analysis process, which is a lot of repeated steps? Would I be able to gain the skillset using which I would be able to automate these type of things? This was.
PAUL: When we'll be talking about the… okay, so your first question was about?
Kritika Kumar: The sequence in which you would recommend that we should do the…
PAUL: Okay, one by one, let's go. Okay, the first couple, the sequence, it will be based on that module, curriculum-based. Okay, now, as I told that somebody even asked for that weekly. I can give you a weekly estimation, but it's not always fixed that, okay, by this time only this will be done.
PAUL: Because I cannot say that within 4 months, so that's why we always take a rough estimation, like, 4 to 5 months.
PAUL: Okay, so I can tell you, module-wise, it will be the same. There won't be any changes. But some classes can go, like, two class, I might think, but really, like, when I'm teaching, it went for 3 classes. So that always happens into the picture. So, a rough estimation, I'll be creating a sheet, basically, and in that sheet, I'll be keeping all those things. So, probably by your next class, when we'll be talking about the basic installation stuff. So, yes, I will be sharing, so you will get the idea from there.
PAUL: Okay?
PAUL: Now to your second question.
Kritika Kumar: So, my second question is this. We get asked a lot of our big customer base, they keep asking, hey, the data in your reports, is that correct, not correct? And there are certain set of steps that we perform to check the data, and then we check.
PAUL: Oh, together.
Kritika Kumar: some business.
PAUL: Got your point. Okay. Now, those set of steps, the idea is to evaluate them.
PAUL: Okay, now, how you are doing the evaluation? Like, somehow here, we'll be talking about that. So, yes, that part can be automated through an agent. For example, you have 10 steps, okay? Now, for each of those 10 steps, what you can do simply, you can build, like, 10 steps. I can say 8 agents. Like, sorry, 10 steps, 10 agents, simple, like, how many steps? The idea is that then you can add on
PAUL: a human evaluation in the loop, it means that after every step, at least you do an evaluation from your side. Okay, quickly, because it's just one shot, because sometimes when you are sending your data, okay, through LLMs and others, it's a good thing that you at least do a quick verification of at least one second or two seconds. Majorly, all the tasks will be done.
PAUL: Okay, but you do evaluate it by yourself, so human in the loop.
PAUL: That's why that particular concept that we'll be talking about, yes, you can do that. So, 10 steps, you can add 10 agents, and you can do that stuff. Okay, it is possible.
Kritika Kumar: Thank you, thank you. So that type of things we'll cover in the course.
PAUL: Yes, when we'll be working with autonomous agents, yes.
Kritika Kumar: Wonderful. Thanks a lot, sir. Thank you. That's it from my end at this moment.
PAUL: All right, Webb.
PAUL: Next, I think, scenario is there.
Sonali: Yeah, hi. So, I have a question, like, I'm having more than 15 years of experience in Azure and .NET.
Sonali: So, I know that in this course, you won't be covering Azure, but still, I want to learn the concepts and would like to implement the… whatever assignments that you would be sharing, would like to implement that in Azure.
Sonali: Basically.
PAUL: Beautiful.
Sonali: So…
PAUL: impact to that.
Sonali: would it be possible for you to share the, respective Azure services that, service names only?
PAUL: Yes, that I will share.
PAUL: like a service limbs, like in GCP water…
Sonali: Share the service names.
PAUL: That identity.
Sonali: Explore, yeah.
PAUL: case. So, probably, like, if I'm working with here EKS, okay, so there it becomes GKS, in JCP, when it goes to Azure, it becomes AKS. A simple example I'm giving for Kubernetes service. At the end of the day, it's the same. It's not like, so yes, with respect to the name of the service…
PAUL: Implement.
PAUL: Alright, fine. That I can do. Telling the name of the services is not a big deal for me, okay? That I can.
Sonali: Yeah.
Sonali: And second thing, I have a specific use case for building an MCP server for one of our applications, which is in .NET. So it's a very complex code, which is using just some Excel to generate some dynamic code generation is happening.
Sonali: So I want to build an MCP server, to… so that other developers can use the code to generate new kind of playbooks.
Sonali: So, I know that there is a topic on MCP server in this course as well. So, will this be… will I be able to build this kind of use case after learning this?
PAUL: Alright, now, simply, for any type of application, do you have an API, yes or no?
Sonali: Sorry? Yes? Do you have an API. API.
PAUL: For the application. How you are exposing the application, that matters to me.
PAUL: Yes?
Sonali: I mean, I want to build this as an integration to VS Code so that I can generate the
PAUL: Okay, see, I'm talking about the application, I'm not talking about MCP. The application that you have, how it is exposed, whether through API, GRPC, how it is exposed.
PAUL: APIs are there, APIs are there, you have to understand, behind the scenes, MCP also uses APIs. Okay, so when we'll be talking with respect to MCP very specifically, then we'll be talking about
PAUL: what are the different protocols are there? So, yes, like, if you have APIs, it's very easy to expose. You have to just follow the HTTPS protocol, okay, inside that. So, it's easy. It's not a big deal.
PAUL: within 30 minutes, you can mix something up. So that's why, if you look into Postman MCP Creator, within one click, through using APIs, you can create an MCP. Okay, so it's really, really easy, so don't worry.
PAUL: If you have APIs, nothing to worry about.
Sonali: It's not about running the application, or using the application functionality, it's about writing the code for that particular… let's say you already have 10.
PAUL: All right.
Sonali: Okay.
PAUL: We can.
Sonali: Kind of dynamic form generation. For example, dynamic form generation, right?
PAUL: This is exactly your office use case. Now, I have to really look into what are the things, and based on that only I can see. Right now, directly, I cannot say, but I know that, yes, to a certain level, automation can be done.
PAUL: Always, in any point of view. I cannot say 100%, because at the end of the day, there has to be some type of evaluation in between. So, to a certain extent, yes, it is possible, I feel.
Sonali: So is there, like, if I have to discuss this use case in more.
PAUL: I think, right now.
Sonali: Would you be able to provide guidance?
PAUL: guidance, generally, we don't take office questions. Really, like, if I start taking, I know there will be more than 100 students discussing their office work. The idea is that you'll present me a POC. If there is a POC available with you, okay, that you can share with us, okay, through GitHub or something like that, then we are really interested.
PAUL: It's not that we are interested in Europe.
Sonali: POC only.
PAUL: If there is a POC available, you can… Yes, if it is a POC, you can share your screen and you can exactly showcase, like, to other students and everybody. Yeah. Okay, and then, yes, in that part, we are really interested. Like, if you have something really that you have built and you can showcase, there I can give you the guidance.
PAUL: But really, like, if you say in high level, this, this, this, you tell me this, so that is not possible. Like, it becomes very hard. If I say something wrong, then…
Sonali: I want to start building a POC.
PAUL: Oh, that's fine.
Sonali: start building a POC on this particular use case.
PAUL: Alright, so now, like, if you have that, no issues, no issues. Okay, like, you can showcase your POC, and then from there, we can actually really look into stuff, and then we can say, like, yes, in this way, and make it better. Yes.
PAUL: So at least build, it means that you take a step. From that step, we can say we can go to step 2, then from step 2 to step 3, that is the idea.
PAUL: All right.
Sonali: And, yeah, just one, like, I know that you have already talked about, that we, people having object-oriented or development background will be able to understand, like, Python. I know I don't have syntactical knowledge of Python, but I know the oops concept, so I would be.
PAUL: Yes.
Sonali: And I've also done your crash course on Python, so I know pretty much about it.
Sonali: The question is, like, would it be possible for you to share prerequisite for, like, there are concepts about deep learning also in your syllabus, right? So, then, if you can say that, yeah, next week we are going to cover this, then we can be just prepared. Like, I think one more person talked about this.
PAUL: I really, like, deep learning in this course I will be talking about. If there is something with respect to deep learning, probably I might use an API or something like that, just to show you.
PAUL: Because to teach deep learning, it takes 3 months.
Sonali: Thanks, so…
PAUL: Okay, so, like, really, I cannot go into deep learning, but yes, in… during the class, when I teach a concept, I can let you know that, okay, now, this is something like that can come into the picture, because really, I don't think deep learning is required.
PAUL: Okay, now it's a very specific use case that you might have in your case, but from this particular course point of view, I don't think… okay, some things that might come from deep learning, but it will be very, very less.
PAUL: That's why. Like, I can say, like, when I teach that thing in that particular lecture, I can tell you, yes, these are the concepts. Probably you might need to know about optimizers and other stuff, but that really… deep learning, that's not Gen AI. Okay, the idea is that we might use those.
Sonali: So, yeah, we may come prepared, that's the idea, nothing else, so if you… we can… we may come prepared.
PAUL: Yes, at any point of time, like, the core fundamentals for everything, there is a Udemy course. If you go into, like, in Udemy, all the recent courses, we share the link. So, similarly, there are other courses also that you can explore, if you want to really get into the fundamentals of every stuff.
PAUL: Okay?
PAUL: I hope I have made my point clear.
Sonali: Right, because the courses are pretty comprehensive, so my objective was to know before this session, these are the topics, so yeah, during the week, then we can explore. Otherwise, exploring each and every course while working, it's too much to just…
PAUL: Just do one thing.
Sonali: nature.
PAUL: Just wait for the classes.
PAUL: Okay? Wait for the classes. In class, if I say that, if this concept belongs to this, then only go through that.
PAUL: Because beforehand, I cannot exactly say, this is the concept that you got.
Sonali: Pardon.
PAUL: It comes with the.
Sonali: No, no, I'm thinking…
PAUL: We're in the class.
Sonali: Yeah.
PAUL: Yes, during the classes, I will be telling. And really, like, we will try to keep it, like, I don't want to mix machine learning, time series, and other stuff in this course. This course is very specific to that.
Sonali: Yes.
PAUL: That's why Ultimate Ray. So, we'll be talking majorly with Ray.
PAUL: Okay, so if something comes from multimodal perspective, their computer vision comes into the picture. But really, like, I don't want to go deep into computer vision. It might take 5 months for me, just to teach computer vision.
PAUL: So that is not possible. All I can say that, okay, this is the concept, you can go through this. This is the input, this is the output. In between that, there is an algorithm. If you want to export that algorithm, you can go and you can look into that. I hope you get my point now.
PAUL: I will always say, what is the input and output? In between that, there will be some type of algorithm or a black box. That is not part of this course. That part, you can always explore. I hope you get my point now.
Sonali: Yeah, sure.
PAUL: Alright.
Sonali: Okay, thank you.
PAUL: Alright, then comes Vijay.
Vijay Garudeswar: Hey, Paul. So, I come from an enterprise content management background. It's basically managing and automating large volume of enterprise documents and workflows.
Vijay Garudeswar: So, basically, I deal with the courts, you know, where these features are offered. So, my requirement,
Vijay Garudeswar: For, I am very specific in learning RAG, RAG-based, developing RAG-based systems.
Vijay Garudeswar: to be able to, you know, log into these systems and perform document management operations. Now, I'm not expecting how to do these operations, but basically in trying to understand how to leverage their RAG
Vijay Garudeswar: apps to be able to consume REST APIs, to be able to perform these, operations, like…
PAUL: Exactly. So, like, the main part is we'll be talking about the AI and the Gem AI part. Then you have to think about how you can integrate that particular thing in your existing system.
Vijay Garudeswar: Right, right. Basically, that is an expectation. But, so, my question is, if I learn how to build a RAG agent, you know, and how to consume REST APIs to be able to talk to these, third-party systems.
Vijay Garudeswar: That should be fair enough to develop my own implementation, right?
PAUL: Yes, yes, yes.
Vijay Garudeswar: No, that's.
PAUL: The good idea is that, at the end of the day, there will be an API. Probably a GET call, POST call, anything like that, but there will be an API. Because for any type of application that will be, that's why you will be using Fast API framework a lot in this course.
Vijay Garudeswar: So when you say fast APA, it's basically nothing to do with data engineering, right? Because I don't…
PAUL: with data engineering is just building APIs, because at the end of the day, if you have built something, you need to expose it to the external world. Okay, so for that purpose, we'll be using Fast API.
Vijay Garudeswar: It can be an AI-powered tool, which… and I can leverage.
PAUL: It's not an AI-powered, a simple Python concept. Every programming language has an own API framework, so it's just.
Vijay Garudeswar: Nothing specific to any particular domain area. It's just a generic RAG thing I can.
PAUL: Generic Python concept. Fast API is nothing related to AI or other stuff. It's simpler Python framework.
PAUL: For building APIs. Okay.
Vijay Garudeswar: That should be true. And those two courses you offered as part of the chat, are those mandatory before I joined this batch?
PAUL: mandatory, really, not mandatory. It's something, like, we do offer the students, okay, for free. The idea is that if you want to have time, please do explore.
PAUL: Otherwise, like, majorly, all those things that are available in these courses. Like, Autogen part, like, really, in this course, we won't be talking about AutoGen, but really, like, in your organization, if you're working something related to autogen, then you can actually go through that course. It will help you.
Vijay Garudeswar: The main challenge for me is learning RAG, how it works, and I have my own product knowledge, how to bridge them together, integrate them together, to be able to build something which is useful for my customer.
Vijay Garudeswar: So, if I can learn about how RAG works, I can visualize how I can make it work.
PAUL: And for 4 months, we'll be talking about only that one question. How that works.
Vijay Garudeswar: Yeah.
PAUL: Because I told you, like, I'll be talking about more than 20 to 25 types of ragoni.
PAUL: Yeah. Okay, like, including all rags, like, I'm mixing normal rag with aging tick rag, okay, AS rag, Adaptive Rag, HEPOR rag, Blend RAG, Metagen, the list goes on. So, really, I don't want to go right now, step by step, that's why that, I told you, a journey is there from 2021 to 2021.
Vijay Garudeswar: Yeah, totally.
PAUL: We will take that journey, and then things will become easier for you. You will completely understand.
Vijay Garudeswar: your point, actually. What I'm saying is, I learned something from you, and I go back and apply it for my own…
PAUL: Yes, and probably, like, one thing always happens that, okay, you already know that, but the idea is how to make it better.
Vijay Garudeswar: Exactly.
PAUL: respect to time. Those things, yes, we'll be covering.
Vijay Garudeswar: And one last question. I work mostly directly with RDBMS. Like, these are… my product is completely tied up with an RDBMS in an organization.
Vijay Garudeswar: And the APs are also driven, you know, within RDBMS, you know, calls are made to this engine, content engine, and eventually to pull the relevant information from RDBMS metadata information.
Vijay Garudeswar: Now, as part of RAG, I have seen that it usually uses a vector database or something like that, right? So,
Vijay Garudeswar: is it mandatory when I learn on RAG, how it works, that I should be using, I should be trying to find a way to
Vijay Garudeswar: port all my data from my core RDBMS to a vector RDB, or should I… can I directly try to understand how our rack works directly by talking to a RDBMS? Like, just one quick.
PAUL: Now, directly, there has to be some type of intermediate layer. Okay, there has to be a connection, at least there have to be some information with respect to what are the different type of tables that are available. Okay, so a lot of things that comes into the picture. When I'll be talking with respect to, like, SQL-based systems on top of RAC, then I'll be talking about those things.
Vijay Garudeswar: Okay, thank you so much.
Vijay Garudeswar: Alright, Vijay.
PAUL: Next… I think there is Rohan. Rohan, you can go ahead.
PAUL: Okay, so Rohan is there, Shakili… okay, so Sheikh Shakhili. Okay, so guys, there are 50 handrails, so, like, you have to wait. Nothing that I can do.
PAUL: Okay, so right now it's 11.47. The session will go till, I think, 2PM, so you will get your chance, don't worry. Just be patient.
PAUL: Alright, pressure, I think whoever, like, Ruhan or Sheikh…
Rohan: Am I audible now?
PAUL: Yes.
Rohan: Yeah, hey everyone. Thank you for the course, and I really like the curriculum and the live sessions. I have a question regarding the projects.
Rohan: So I see it's, mostly at the end of the modules. So is it, like, after all the course, we'll be going through the… No, it's not necessary. Like, probably after Module 2, 3, I discuss one project.
PAUL: Okay, but the last two ones will be discussed in the last two, four and five, remember that.
PAUL: Others in between that will be covered.
Rohan: Okay, and, regarding the interviews, so, two things is, do we have, like, mock interviews?
Rohan: And after what module do you think we can start being ready for, interviews?
Rohan: Like, what is the basic minimum that we need to have before we can start interviewing?
PAUL: I think at least you need to cover up till Module 10 or 11.
PAUL: Okay, because the advanced… now, it totally depends upon your experience. If you have 0 years of experience, like, till module 8 or module 10, everything will be fine. You are good to go. But if you are at least more than 4 to 5 years of experience, I feel the other modules are required.
Rohan: Okay.
Rohan: And regarding the, interview preparation, is there, like.
PAUL: Interview preparation, very specifically, like, mock, I'll be telling you certain things from certain topics, and be giving you a list of questions to you.
PAUL: Okay.
Rohan: Yeah, thank you.
PAUL: Alright, let's move to our next. There is, Mohit Agarwal.
PAUL: I've done it.
PAUL: Other Shake Shackle was there, no? Shake? I think you can go ahead.
Mohit Agarwal: Hey, can you hear me?
PAUL: moihid.
PAUL: Yeah, I'm gonna go first. Yes, I can.
Mohit Agarwal: Yeah, so I have a few questions, so…
Mohit Agarwal: Anything beyond Python, which is a prerequisite for this course?
PAUL: Initially, everything is Python. Nothing. Other things we will always teach from scratch only the frameworks.
Mohit Agarwal: Okay, and apart from this, from the shared courses on
Mohit Agarwal: I mean, the JNEI one, and as well as the Ultimate Boot Camp. Any… anything which we need to see, any specific section from those courses which will help us augment in our understanding of the… of the content that will be get delivered as part of this course, or shall we…
Mohit Agarwal: Shall we kind of put it on the side for now, and watch it in parallel as the session?
PAUL: progresses for this particular.
Mohit Agarwal: particular boot.
PAUL: Are you comfortable with Python? This is the only thing Carissa also told. Are you comfortable with Python?
Mohit Agarwal: So, I am from a Java bird, I understand Python, but I am not someone who has coded in Python, but I have spent a…
PAUL: You have to be just familiar with Python. If you have 15 years in Java, then don't think around it, because certain point, like, with object-oriented programming, it's much more robust in Java as compared to Python. So, nothing to worry about. If there are certain concepts that will come, okay, I will tell you during the class.
PAUL: Okay, so you can explode that. I told you what is the input, what is the output. In between that, what is the black box, or the algorithm that I'll be talking about in that during class, okay? That you can explore, if it is not part of Write.
PAUL: Okay, I hope you guys.
Mohit Agarwal: I don't…
Mohit Agarwal: Another question that I have is, any, any real-life use cases or case studies that you have, encountered?
PAUL: We'll be talking about fees.
Mohit Agarwal: I mean, we're working on these racks, or…
PAUL: Right now, like, one of the use cases, even one of the product.
Mohit Agarwal: It will help us understand and comprehend the problem statement better, is where I was.
PAUL: you and I'll be talking with respect to projects, then we'll be talking about those use cases. That's why there are projects.
PAUL: Otherwise, what is the purpose of keeping projects, ma'am?
PAUL: I hope you get it. In the projects part Ali were talking about, see, I never present a use case, because use case, it can be anything. My idea is to build such a generic system, which can be later easily changed into domain-specific stuff.
PAUL: Okay, because I am not from, like, pharma or in healthcare domain. Probably I might have worked only in retail for many years. So that's why I really don't know what is the domain, because at the end of the day, there are certain, like, subject matter experts comes into the picture whenever you are working with AI.
PAUL: Okay, and without them, you cannot really build the system. So I cannot really go deep into a certain domain only.
PAUL: So that's why I will always try to keep it generic.
PAUL: Okay, you bring your own domain expertise, and then you can add on top of that generic system. That will be the idea.
Mohit Agarwal: Okay, okay. Thanks, Paul. Thanks to you, my…
Mohit Agarwal: Thank you and Krish for coming up with.
PAUL: Yeah.
Mohit Agarwal: I'm eagerly looking forward for the classes in the… Jenny, Gabriel.
PAUL: Alright, Moit.
PAUL: Next, Sheikh Shatil…
Shaik Sahil: Good.
PAUL: Sheikh Shahil, I think. Yeah, Sheikh Shahil, yeah, go on.
Shaik Sahil: Good morning, sir. I'm completely from data science background, and I have good knowledge in Python, and my doubt is I don't have specific knowledge about Fentanyl backend and cloud. Then, implementing RAC, do we need to know front-end backend.
PAUL: No, no, not required. Front-end, not required. Back-end part, if you're working with Python, it's more than enough. Like, if you know a little bit about Flask or FastAPI, it is more than enough for you.
Shaik Sahil: Because, my job is to write RAG, and implementing, front-end backend is other, other department, right?
PAUL: Yeah, yeah, yeah. Other teams are there. Nobody, as a data scientist, nobody is expecting you to build an event. That's totally the job of some others. In our case, like, if we are building a simple event, we will try to use frameworks like Streamlit and others.
PAUL: It's just for basic part. But the real-world UI, nobody was using Streamlit. So, for simple learning purpose, we'll be using Streamlit, and other frameworks are there. I hope you get my point. So it will be totally back-end.
PAUL: No front rate, okay?
Shaik Sahil: Okay, thank you, sir.
PAUL: Next, let's go ahead with Salman.
PAUL: Okay, so Jetan… Then there is Amul.
PAUL: Ishan Pandey, poor people that I have now. So right now, more than 50 hands are exercised. So really, others, please do wait.
PAUL: Okay, so can I go first? Yeah, Sullivan, please go ahead.
Salman: Okay, so, in the beginning, Mayan gave introduction of some other course, language. So, what was that course about? You know, is it a different course?
PAUL: That is also, like, one of the frameworks, because there are so many frameworks in the Gen AI world. Okay, so one of the frameworks, like LanChain, I think Chris has shared, then Mang shared about AutoGen. Okay, so these are different frameworks.
PAUL: So right now, in this course, we'll be talking about a few other frameworks also, that are not part of that course, very specifically for RAG that we do use.
Salman: So, but if we go through that course, that will be good, you know? Because next week you are going to start.
PAUL: Next week, I will start with the installment.
Salman: Listen?
PAUL: probably next. So, really, like, it's not required, okay? If you want to learn Munci, at the end of the day, there is endless learning. If you want to learn, go ahead. I highly encourage you. But really, for the next class, it is not required.
Salman: It's a free course, it is, if we can attend it? Yes, good.
PAUL: If you have time, give time, like, I will be also discussing language in, the same thing is there in the Udemy course also.
PAUL: It means that if you learn that in class, then quickly you can grab those things, so somehow. Otherwise, if you, like, in the initial one month, things won't be tough, I told you. After Module 8, things will become tougher. So, initial two things, you really don't need to worry. Like, if you are looking, it's good, I will encourage, but if you don't have time, simply directly come to the live classes.
PAUL: Otherwise, I cannot say that I'm teaching there, I won't teach here. It's not like that.
Salman: Okay.
PAUL: Here, things will be covered in depth, okay?
Salman: Okay, okay, great enough. Another one. I have good numbers of experience, you know, 20 years of experience, all in data domain. Starting my career with data engineering, and then architect, and then now I'm a practice head.
Salman: What other… I'm a hands-on, as well.
Salman: What other course I can combine? Because this will go on for, let's say, 4 or 5 months. What other course I can combine in parallel with this course?
Salman: Nuh-
Salman: I've explained.
PAUL: linking. That is linking.
Salman: Model, statical models.
PAUL: Okay.
Salman: Gen AI is… I'm beginning with this course, but what other course I can combine with this?
PAUL: Really, like, what is the requirement?
Salman: will be very packed. My question is this, will this course will be very packed, or will I have a room to enroll in another one?
PAUL: No, I can say, let's see, there are other comp… I told you, in Gen AI, there is, like, 100%. In this course, we'll be focusing majorly, like, one of the major things, like, if I try to break it. RAG, LLMs, and ops.
PAUL: Okay, so we'll be focusing on the RAG component. For ops, there is very specifically LLM, ops, and other things. Okay, then similarly. So, I cannot say that 100% everything. It's a part of Gen AI that we'll be discussing in depth, and it is being adopted in the market. Like, do you… like, every organization cannot build their own LLMs.
PAUL: Right. It is not possible. They can only build SLMs to a certain extent.
PAUL: Okay, so that's why. The idea is, majorly, like, I can say more than 90% of the organizations are building RAG. So, we are focusing highly on that. After that, you can explore other things.
Salman: We'll be covering the part, the deployment part, and, you know, moving.
PAUL: RAG-level deployment? Yes, I'll be covering that.
Salman: But not the ops part.
PAUL: That is ops, no. DevOps. It means what are the services that are used in.
Salman: But there is some type of.
PAUL: I'll get those.
PAUL: Yes, options there. That's why AWS comes into the picture. Otherwise, why AWS I am talking about.
Salman: Yeah, yeah. No, you mentioned, like, LLM ops, if you want to learn ops, you can roll it…
PAUL: That is different. So, right now, here I will be talking about how to handle LLMs.
Salman: Oh, okay.
PAUL: I will tell you how to handle RAT.
PAUL: I hope you get my point. LLM is different, RAG is different.
Salman: Yes. Second?
Salman: Will you be taking up the tools like, you know, Nate and PhiData.
PAUL: No, M10 is not part of this course, that is part of the agent tick AI course very specifically. There, we talk about no-code tools like Langflow, MATEM, because that is only Agentic.
Salman: Agent.
PAUL: Here, we don't discuss about RAC. So you have to understand, like, the courses are separate. Here, we focus much more on RAC. Here, agents are there, but very specifically, we'll be using Langra.
PAUL: There, in the Agent TKI course, we discussed more than, I think, probably how many frameworks? Langdrop is there, Krivia is there, Ragonoo is there, okay, Langflow, NATAM, like, all agent frameworks that we discussed there.
PAUL: Okay, so there the list is pretty long.
PAUL: But there we don't talk about RAD. Here we talk about RAG. Okay, so… and there is an amalgamation of agents with RAT. That is there in this code. Agent incorrect, that we call it. Okay, so that is part of this code.
Salman: Okay, and will you be taking… you mentioned VectorDB you will cover, but you'll be covering GraphDB as well?
PAUL: Yeah, it's Neo4j.
Salman: GraphDB will be there.
Salman: Okay, and you mentioned we'll be doing a lot of projects, so building the front end would also be the part of.
PAUL: Not a priority, not a priority.
Salman: Right. So we'll just provide.
PAUL: I am a backend engineer, I know zero front-end, I don't work with React and other frameworks. You can think about, really, for me, APIs matter. Then I give it to the UI team and others reacted.
Salman: So we'll build until FastAPI. We'll build.
PAUL: We'll until Streamlit, like, little bit of Streamlit, because you can… Yeah, Streamlit is a basic wife. Yeah, that, okay, so that will be true.
Salman: But we'll be building, until any API, fast API.
PAUL: Yes, like, majorly the backend will be based on FastAPIs, okay. Otherwise, like, streamlit in some cases. I prefer FastAPI much more.
Salman: Okay, and we are not covering the architectures like transformer, encoder, decoder, we are not going into.
PAUL: No, those things is not part. Really, like, you can look into the courses, which have been shared, okay, in those courses, you will be getting those topics.
Salman: what are the courses, if you can help me, or I can, you know, provide.
PAUL: The link was shared in the chat by Chris.
Salman: So, okay, has the details.
PAUL: Yes, in Udemy, you can look into other courses also. It's not only two courses. There are so many courses in Udemy.
Salman: Not including courses, on your website, Learn With Krish Academy.
PAUL: Okay, learn there very specifically, right now for live batch. Like, Transformers, there is a specific batch, I think the Ultimate Data Science batch. There, those things will be covered in the upcoming months. Right now, I think deep learning will start just.
PAUL: Okay, so in that batch, you can look into the Ultimate Data Science Bootcamp.
PAUL: Oh. So there, that entire… there, we teach very little bit of Gen AI, but the entire data science starting from 2006 till 2020.
Salman: So I think…
PAUL: Listen.
Salman: It can be combined for me, actually.
PAUL: Yes, that batch is at night, and this is at the morning. You can come.
Salman: You can be combined. Okay. Many thanks, yeah.
PAUL: Alright, son.
Jithin Paul: Yeah, I apologize.
Jithin Paul: the site?
PAUL: Yeah, Jatin, Igor, then Among.
Jithin Paul: Yeah, so basically, I'm working as a data architect, and then now I need to build a solution wherein… I mean, it's basically ETL as a service.
Jithin Paul: So, I'm trying to build a platform on top of Databricks which would enable, you know, kind of migrations. So, it could be different services, at the source and at the sync side. So, it has to auto… it has to generate a code, which would, you know, should cater to different kind of systems.
Jithin Paul: So, this was the kind of, you know, the expectation that was set up, friend, like, it has to be a generic solution, so there could be, you know, places wherein a lot of auto-code generation that has to take place. So, how can this course help me in that? I'm pretty much new to.
PAUL: When I'll be talking about agentic frameworks very specifically, there I'll be talking about. Probably code generation can be done, but later on, that code needs to be executed in a sandbox. Okay, now that part, really, working with sandboxes, I won't be covering in this particular course, but I'll be talking about the code generation part.
Jithin Paul: Okay.
PAUL: What I'm working with…
Jithin Paul: Yeah, go ahead.
PAUL: That is part of autonomous agents when I'll be talking about, probably after 2.5 months or 3 months.
PAUL: Code generation is possible. Like, people are building complete, automated, profiles for Terraform. It means already, like, Terraform scripts are being generated based on the current infra. Okay, like, so those type of things, yes, everybody is doing.
Jithin Paul: So, basically, that's going to be a RAG implementation for this, like, that's how… because it has to understand the system.
PAUL: That will be much more agent-type rather than RAG, I can say. Because now, yeah, RAG comes into the picture if you have your own data. If the data comes, then you can plug it as a memory module, and then you can actually use it in your application.
Jithin Paul: Hmm, okay.
PAUL: If you think that your current data is responsible to bring better context, yes, then RAC comes into the picture. But if you think that, yes, current is not required.
PAUL: Okay, then you can skip that memory.
Jithin Paul: what I'm trying to say is, like, you know, this is going to be, like, you're trying to move data from a mainframe to mainframe through Databricks, and it could be, like, from, Oracle to a different, Oracle database system through Database, so… through Databricks.
PAUL: Really, let's say, it's your office work. Now, when you say in that particular perspective, I have to really do… look deep dive. Or you built a POC, you come and show to me.
PAUL: Like, when you directly… because, see, at the end of the day, I don't want to discuss anybody's office work here. It's simply, like, you build a POC, you show it to me and the other students, they can also learn something new, and then from there, I can take it, because really, I need to see exactly what is going on. What is the input and output? Without saying input, and what is the expected output, it's very hard for…
PAUL: I get it, yeah.
PAUL: Yeah, okay, because if I say something, then you try to apply, then you say, Paul, you said something wrong, I really, I don't want to do that.
Jithin Paul: No, no, I just want to know, like, there could be, like, this course would help me, in, you know.
PAUL: With respect to automated code generation, yes, this course will help you in that.
Jithin Paul: Okay.
PAUL: Okay, now that particular with code which is generated, it needs to be validated in some type of sandbox, with some type of test cases added on top of that. I hope you get. It means that on top of that, a lot of things that needs to be done.
PAUL: According to your requirement.
PAUL: Okay?
PAUL: Alright.
Amol Ahire: Yeah. I mean.
PAUL: Yes, someone.
Amol Ahire: First of all, very good afternoon to you, Paul, Mayanka, and Trish. I'm more of an outlier in this course, I have.
PAUL: More than 20 classes?
Amol Ahire: I'm not… I'm more of an AI, more of an IT leader, rather than a hardcore, developer, or from
Amol Ahire: management company. Goldman was, mainly a manufacturing setup, and I came, more as a… more of a IT, business IT guy who knows, business and just IT strategy.
Amol Ahire: First of all, I want to, thank
Amol Ahire: Krish, sir, and everyone, because Krish was the one reason who forced me to come out of my retirement in 2023. I said it's… I… I was about to quit, and I started seeing his courses, and again, then I really intended professional career.
Amol Ahire: So, thank you so much, Krish, for this, and… and the level of efforts and level of content you are… you are, giving it, to the Indian audience is… is… is great, man.
Amol Ahire: Though we do not have any LLM, but Krish and you guys are making our young Indian force, the way they will be…
Amol Ahire: utilizing this technology, I am sure we will have a very bright future. So, thanks. I really, I want to express my gratitude towards you guys, young minds. Absolutely brilliant job.
Krish Naik: Yeah, you said initially, you know, like, coming out of your retirement, so that is a good thing or bad thing from my side, I don't know.
Amol Ahire: I don't know, I was, like, you, you start… I think 2023, where your channel started picking up.
Amol Ahire: So from that point, I said, let me just… RAG. And at that time also, I thought RAG is the one thing which corporates can start utilizing it. That is what… RAG was very new, I think, and we used to talk about agents, and then suddenly in the last two years, a lot of development happened.
Amol Ahire: So my whole aim is that… see, now I'm also learning different management courses, mainly from IMs and ISBs, and… so there we see 80-90% of JNA projects are failing.
Krish Naik: Most of them are prototype, but the failure rate is very high.
Krish Naik: Hmm.
Amol Ahire: So, like, I don't want to sit in that ACK cabin and give some fundas. I wanted something hands-on. I have, experience of something, like, I've learned a lot of things in coding, but I want to understand how the execution happens, so what are the gaps? So, I know the business side of it, I know the financial side of it.
Amol Ahire: but at execution level, what the gaps comes, so this course will help me. I want to understand a lot of use cases which racks can be utilized in a different domain. Like, right now, I'm in the telecom domain, but I'll definitely go back to the manufacturing domain, where I see a lot of huge potential of racks and this Jane AI.
Amol Ahire: automation. So, this is… this is where I expect, more, like, use cases knowledge, where I'll be implementing something, but I want to understand RAC, which… which can be exploited by, by Indian, Indian industries.
Amol Ahire: Thank you, Drif.
Krish Naik: No one's.
Krish Naik: Yeah, you're continuing with the question, right? So, this is only…
Amol Ahire: question is that, like, I just want, like, if possible, Paul, try to, give a lot of use cases if we are doing… we are doing some pro… something, but this can be applied to… we can have more discussion where things can be applied. So, different domains, so… so that way, a practicality will come… come to that.
PAUL: Yeah, see, the main problem is, if I take an example of a medical domain, okay, then one student says, bring telecom, bring healthcare.
Amol Ahire: Give me best… bye.
PAUL: I've never done it.
Amol Ahire: Let them think about it.
PAUL: That's why we always try to keep things generic. The idea is that you have a domain-specific data, you can bring it, because really, I cannot bring the domain expertise.
PAUL: Okay, like, I cannot bring it, because there are so many domains. I can probably discuss 2 or 3 domains that I have really worked on, and I can give you such examples based on that. That's fine.
Amol Ahire: What is expected is successful projects at the end of the… at the end of the day. The project should be successful. The investment should be justified. That is what is the expectation.
PAUL: Yes.
Amol Ahire: Thanks, guys, thanks a lot.
PAUL: Alright, now let's move to our next participant, who is Ishan.
PAUL: I think Ishan is there.
PAUL: Or, okay, Remisha… Ishan Pandey was there, okay, then…
Ishan Pande: Hey, Paul, I'm still here, sorry. Can you hear me?
PAUL: Yeah, Ishan, please go ahead.
Ishan Pande: Okay, yeah, so first of all, thank you so much for giving me the opportunity to ask the question. So, in my company, we have got a lot of in-house frameworks, okay, for API development, for test automation development.
Ishan Pande: So now, we have got one use case.
Ishan Pande: Where we want to leverage these in-house frameworks to develop new frameworks, actually, or new applications. We don't want to develop these applications from scratch, actually.
PAUL: So, like, if you have existing frameworks for those frameworks, you might be having some type of detailed API documentation and other stuff?
Ishan Pande: Yes, yes. Do you have those?
PAUL: That's the same thing. Like, you can build a RAG. If you have code snippets, some examples with detailed documentation, yes. Like, those documentation, you can take it as an input to a RAG, and there, based on those particular frameworks, you can create the code snippets. Yes, that is possible.
Ishan Pande: Yeah, but for brand new application, I totally understand, but let's say when we are in week 4 or week 5, and if the application is 50% developed.
Ishan Pande: Now, I want to use this rack concept to learn the existing implementation, and then on top of that, only add the required code, which is needed as a part of enhancement.
Ishan Pande: So, in such kind of use cases, does the tokenization cost will be too high, and these are not the right use cases? Just thought to understand.
PAUL: Really, see, it's a custom framework. Okay, now, at any point of time, if you want to upgrade a certain part of that, okay, now your existing framework will come into the picture with that. So, really, like, the tokenization cost will be high for sure. Because for your program, I can say that easily.
PAUL: And that a lot of data, like, more than, like, 1GB, 2GB of documentations will be there. So, yes, documentation cost will be high, for sure.
PAUL: That I can say. But yes, now see, if you want to do any upgrades, okay, then the LLM will suggest.
PAUL: But really, that it is required or not, that decision you have to take. Then only you do the upgrade.
PAUL: Because I feel that sometimes if you directly go with the questions to the LLM, it might say 10 different suggestions. But really, do you need those 10 different suggestions? That you need to do some evaluation from your end. And then you take the decision that, okay, now this part that needs to be upgraded to a certain purpose.
Ishan Pande: Okay, alright, alright. Okay, thank you so much, Paul.
PAUL: All right, Tashawn.
PAUL: Next… I think Rimshaw… Okay, let's go with others also. Prasad Red D.
PAUL: Abdul Prattamgarh.
PAUL: Okay, sit.
PAUL: Yes, few people are unmuted, one by one. Hey, Prasad.
Prasad Reddi: Yeah, hi, Paul.
Prasad Reddi: First of all, thank you all.
Prasad Reddi: For this course, so I just wanted to introduce about myself and my expectations from this course.
Prasad Reddi: So, I'm a mechanical engineer and working in the automotive domain for the past 20 years.
Prasad Reddi: So, I am a layman in the entire, whatever the…
Prasad Reddi: the request prerequisites are there, but still, you know, I'm very excited to understand how these things work and how I can leverage all these things. So, right now, I'm not a, like, a core developer, or a, like, you know, I don't have any extensive coding background. However, I know some basics of,
Prasad Reddi: Python, I'm developing some… some tools for my work.
Prasad Reddi: Using Python, I'm working on some machine learning, some basics where I can integrate to my core mechanical job.
Prasad Reddi: And right now, I would like to, understand how I can leverage these skills to work on rack building, where I can do some… something more into my core domain.
Prasad Reddi: Okay, so… the thing is, how I'm doing is how, like, I can leverage AI again in working rag development. So, whatever the tools I'm developing, or whatever the tools I have developed so far, are using
Prasad Reddi: Chatgpt.
Prasad Reddi: I have my own framework, I'm using that framework to understand and to develop those tools. So far, the tools are working fantastically, like, you know, those are deployed in my organization as well.
Prasad Reddi: So, I hope maybe this framework will help me, because with my age and the current experience, I don't have time to learn many things, you know. But however, I am planning to leverage all these tools to get success, you know?
PAUL: In the framework, what I'm planning to do. All right. Now, as you are from automotive Domain, okay, so let's talk about, like, I know a few people, very specifically, like, from Robert Bosch and others, they have been working with multimedia systems.
PAUL: In automotive.
PAUL: Domain. Okay, now, for those, for example, if I want to build a RAG, now the existing systems, okay, now, if there are some type of fault-tolerance systems that they want to build, in that particular point of time for decision making, yes, they do use RAG. For certain type of sensors, you can keep all of your sensor data in one vector DB, then they perform a similarity search.
PAUL: other thing comes into the picture. So, yes, you can think about, okay, or with respect to image processing, because right now, you know, there are cameras, okay, so everywhere. Now, taking the camera feed, and based on that.
PAUL: Okay, you want to pick some type of annually, some type of force, and other things, yes, for that, also people in suicide.
PAUL: Okay, it means that the mixture of vision that comes into the picture, mixture of the sensor readings that comes into the picture, yes. In automotive Roman, I know. Like, in Robert Wash, very specifically, I know a few students have been working, they discussed a use case with me.
PAUL: Okay, and now, with respect to ChatGPT, as you…
PAUL: told that your applications are working fine right now. But really, do you need a memory layer for those applications? Do you feel that certain things are repetitive? If you feel that repetitive, okay, now, at any point of time, if you want to do the evaluation for those things, so here, like, RAC will come into the picture.
Prasad Reddi: Yeah, yeah. So, yeah, this course is going to enlighten more things into my learning, so I will be looking forward for that, Paul and Krish.
PAUL: Yes, for sure, like, the idea, say, like, if you have something, like, a good use case, okay, you can always let me know. Like, the idea is…
PAUL: like, little bit of POC, because when directly somebody says in high level, this, this, this, okay, it really becomes hard for me, at least when there is a very specific input and output, okay, the contract is defined, then it becomes easier for me to tell you that, okay, in this direction, you can go ahead to take better decisions and to make your system much more better.
Prasad Reddi: Right, right. Sure, sure, sure, sure, Paul. I have some use cases which eventually, during the course of time, I will, discuss with you all, so that we can, we can make it more powerful. Thank you all.
PAUL: Alright, Raza, yeah.
Rimsha: Okay, hi.
PAUL: Next, yes, Remsha, next. Then Abdul, and then Seth. Yes.
Rimsha: Sure, so my question is more, about, so I am a data consultant, I mean, senior consultant, and my role involves, pitching the Gen AI solution to clients, and then also designing
Rimsha: modules that would be implemented for creating a RAG-based, GenAI tool. So, I just wanted to know, will this course be, more useful for me, or should I take up the one which is AI for leaders and professionals?
Rimsha: Which would be more relevant in my case.
PAUL: much more technical course, okay, that is much more from, like, business point of view. Here, if you say that, like, as a consultant, okay, you need to have that business point of view.
PAUL: So that point of view comes from that course. From here, you will get a technicality with respect to RAG only, very specifically. Because as an AI consultant or a senior, there are other things also. Because if you want to pitch something, you have to tell them how it is beneficial.
PAUL: And for beneficiaries, only two parameters are the most important, time and revenue.
PAUL: If they can reduce the workforce.
PAUL: where AI can bring them some type of automations.
PAUL: Okay, cost reduction, okay, now you have to do those type of analysis. So, from this course, you will get certain idea, because everywhere, in every organization there, some team is doing. Because I work with HR teams, I work with finance teams, how to make their systems much more better.
PAUL: how to introduce AI into their systems.
PAUL: Okay, and how, at the end of the day, the time and revenue game goes on.
PAUL: If these two things you can explain anywhere, okay, and you can pitch, okay, then everything works good.
PAUL: Okay. So, from this course, it's the technical point of view, rather than the business, because from the technicality, you can get certain numbers. Now, those numbers can be represented to your business decisions.
Rimsha: Got it. Thanks, Paul. And one last question. So, I was trying practicing RAG on my office laptop, but it was preventing me from downloading Anaconda. So, will that be a…
PAUL: Really, Anaconda is not required. Next class, we'll be talking… one dedicated class is only for installation, that is next Saturday. All the major tools that you require for this course, all the major installation, everything we'll be doing next.
PAUL: So don't worry about the installation part. And in your local system, if Anaconda is not working, we will do a workaround, probably with pure Python or with UV. A lot of workarounds are there. I know in many office systems, Anaconda is restricted.
PAUL: So it's complex.
Rimsha: But also, it would be helpful if you could just provide configurations for laptop, on which we can run our…
PAUL: In 2025, the basic one, I told, 16GB of RAM.
PAUL: Okay, if you have an 8GB, it's fine, but I feel 8GB is really not 2025 standard. You should have at least a 16GB. Bare minimum, I can say, at least an i5. i3 is really slow, so having an i5 does the job, or a Ryzen 7 or a Ryzen 9 is much better, for sure.
PAUL: For AI-related tasks, okay? But the bare minimum, at least if you have an i5 with a 60GB of RAM, things should work. You don't need a GPU for this course.
Rimsha: Okay, okay, okay. Thank you so much, Paul. That is it.
PAUL: How great.
PAUL: Next, I think, Abdul, after that said.
Sid: Okay.
PAUL: Okay, so no response.
Sid: Can I go ahead?
PAUL: Yeah, said go.
Sid: Hi, Paul. Thanks for giving me the opportunity.
Sid: And, before asking my question, I'd like to thank you, Chris, sir, because of whom I got into a structured course from YouTube.
Sid: And also I have taken the Gen AI course from Ademi in my organization.
Sid: So my question is, like, I'm into this, SQL Server, Microsoft BI, and data engineering space from past 17 plus years of experience.
Sid: So now, we don't have any opportunity in pipeline to work on AI, but I'm into the learning mode.
Sid: So, with this data engineering background, could you please advise me how I can apply this RAG knowledge to leverage in my career, and if I can get some opportunity for the switch?
Sid: And would you be…
PAUL: See, if you are a data engineer, at the end of the day, if you're building any product, you need an engineering team. Data engineering, it means that there has to be some specific type of ETL pipelines, how the data is coming, batch data, stream data, you guys only handle, and then finally come the RAT systems.
PAUL: That is traditional, it's nothing. It means that if somebody is a search engine AI engineer, if you have that data engineering skill building ETL pipelines, okay, that is really good, because at the end of the day, when you work with huge scale of data, it is required.
PAUL: And then it means similar pipelines. Like, for example, like, ETL, if I'm building, like, 3 different types of pipelines, okay, like a gold, silver, and bronze in that category, yes, those things, and then finally I put that data into some type of data warehousing solution, then my rag team comes, and they directly pull it from the warehousing part.
PAUL: So, those things will be the same. It's nothing like those things will… data engineering team will always be there. I feel that GenAI job is unstable. Data engineering is much a stable job.
Sid: Okay.
Sid: Actually, I'm mostly into the Databricks, creating pipelines in ADF and all, so then I can apply this skill set also for, like, if I'm, moving out from the current role and want to switch to the rack, right? So that will be convenient.
PAUL: Yes, because, see, it's something like an overlap. It means that there is a huge amount of overlap in that skill and this skill. If you learn these technologies with respect to Gen AI, because at the end of the day, any Gen AI or AI product team need a data source. For data source, you need a data engineer. So, that's why there will be always an overlap.
PAUL: Okay, so that complete data architect part, when we say, like, data science, data engineering, data ops, like, MLOps comes into the picture. So, yes, you are always in that particular part. So, like, always, like, people look for… I've seen many students who do the switch from engineering to that data science part, or the TI part.
PAUL: It's pretty common in the market.
Sid: Okay, thanks a lot. And, one last question. So, not sure, if you're having any, career counseling, from the, like, Grishnag Academy perspective, so could you advise.
PAUL: Career counseling, it means if you have anything, like, probably during the classes or at that particular point of time, you can ask me.
PAUL: Okay, so regarding anything, or if you want something…
PAUL: Like, see, generally, like, one-to-one connect, personally.
Abdul Bari: You guys!
PAUL: If you feel that it is important, we do it, because otherwise, like, my entire team, we are a very small team. If 500 people say I want to do one-to-one, it's really not possible for us. Okay, so anything in the class, if you feel that you want to discuss, or others have gone at the end, we can do that. If anything important is there, you can write a mail to her.
PAUL: To me, at least. Okay, I will share you the email, like, going forward. Okay, so, like, in… you can write your detailed thing. If I feel that if I need to connect you in detail, because everything, I cannot write it in the mail. It's better to catch up for 5 minutes, and then let you.
Sid: Okay, makes sense. Thanks a lot, Phil. Thank you, too.
PAUL: right now.
PAUL: Alright, so next.
PAUL: Abdul Bhari.
Abdul Bari: Hi, Paul, am I audible?
PAUL: Yes, you are audible.
Abdul Bari: Yeah, thank you, thanks. First of all, thanks to you, Pris, and other members of the team. It's a nice course, and it's a very good beginning as well. I'm really excited to go through. First of all, I'm not, I mean.
Abdul Bari: Total tech background, I am a bit of IT management background, with some background in machine learning.
Abdul Bari: So…
PAUL: Alright.
Abdul Bari: But I have some working knowledge in Python. I can do modular coding, but probably in the prerequisite that you have mentioned about asynchronous function and that kind of stuff. Are you going to cover that, or we should learn ourselves?
Abdul Bari: for this course.
PAUL: I will be showing you, because, for example, 5 functions are there. If I want to use async at some particular place, I'll be talking about it, so don't worry. In class, it's not really required if you don't have that async part.
PAUL: Okay, so in class, when I'll be doing the implementations, I'll be talking about that.
Abdul Bari: Okay, cool. And Arak, if I have missed it, please pardon me.
Abdul Bari: You have… for the multimodal rag, you have mentioned about, data types, like, of course, text data you're going to cover, you have also mentioned about emails, but how about audio data? Are you going to cover that as well, or…
PAUL: Audio is here in the syllabus, please have a look.
Abdul Bari: Okay, yeah, that's true.
PAUL: Always look into the curriculum. See, it means that anything that is written in the curriculum, I can commit that 100% I will teach you.
PAUL: Now, if you say that, okay, this also needs to be done, this, all those things will be just, like, in the bucket list.
Abdul Bari: Okay, yeah. I got it.
PAUL: Wow, that's…
Abdul Bari: I got it. But one last question is regarding ops part. I understand it's… your fundamental emphasis is on RAC,
Abdul Bari: So, you are not going to cover every bit of LLM Ops, but your aim is to go to the… to reach the production level, right? So, do I have to cover some part of LLM Ops
Abdul Bari: By ourselves, or are you going to cover.
PAUL: that LLM…
Abdul Bari: Honda.
PAUL: But you have to cover by yourself. Really, in this course, I won't be talking about LLMs. Wherever I need an LLM, okay, I will use an API most of the times. If sometime a local use case comes, probably I'll be showing you about OLAMA. Okay, but really, I'm not going into handling that LLM ops part.
PAUL: Handling LLMs is really a costly infra. Okay, it means that to run an LLM inside an instance, okay, now, really, like, if you want to scale that app, it's really a very costly part, so nothing related to that. We'll be sticking to APIs majorly.
PAUL: Okay. Alright, Prashant.
Rahul Parihar: Okay.
PAUL: Okay.
Rahul Parihar: Can I… can I ask my question?
PAUL: No, no, Abdul, I think his… Abdul, you are done? Please listen.
Abdul Bari: Yeah, I'm done, I'm done, all good, thank you.
PAUL: Alright, alright, Anthony, yes.
Pratham Garg: Can I ask, sir? .
PAUL: First, Rahul, then… okay, Pratham, you have been waiting, I think. Yeah, Pratham, you go ahead, then Rahul.
Pratham Garg: Okay, so… Hi, Paul, I hope you are doing good. So, my…
Pratham Garg: doubt is, so I've just started my…
Pratham Garg: career, so it's just 10 months of experience for me, but I am from the analytics and benchmarking background, where we benchmark companies and organizations.
PAUL: Alright.
Pratham Garg: tell them how they stand among their peers. So, this is specifically on the basis of some, 200 to 300 KPIs and metrics that we get from clients.
Pratham Garg: So, it is like, I don't want to stick to this field, and I want to switch into ML and
Pratham Garg: data science field, machine learning and…
PAUL: Alright, I got it. You were looking for a switch from an analyst to a science, or much more towards an ML engineer stuff, those type of growth, much towards the AI side.
PAUL: to explore.
Pratham Garg: Yes, yes, so my doubt is that I have working knowledge of Python, because in my work, there are some complex
Pratham Garg: processes that, needs to be automated. So I have, the experience of automation, so it's like automating huge PPT decks, it's like 100 slides, 200 slides, and also, you know.
PAUL: break on it.
Pratham Garg: extracting the text from a survey using Playwright, web scraping.
Pratham Garg: Specifically, so I have the working knowledge of automation and scripting in Python, and because of Chris's
Pratham Garg: channel, I have started, exploring, deep learning and NP and, ML.
PAUL: Yes, a CPU, like, for you, I will suggest…
Pratham Garg: Should be the roadmap.
PAUL: Basically, huh, that was my… I got your point, see.
Pratham Garg: Yup.
PAUL: Like, if you are looking for a data science or an ML role, simply, I can say that cover the basics. At the end of the day, need it.
PAUL: Okay, the concepts of ML are something around that can be used again with respect to Gen AI also. So, ML, deep learning, these are the fundamental concepts.
PAUL: Okay, and now, based on your experience, really, like, you cannot be good in everything you have to understand.
PAUL: Now, you have to select. Now, for example, if you have enrolled in this course, one part of GenAI told you that 40% tech stack, you will be good with respect to rack-based systems.
PAUL: Now, you pick up, like, in the other time, you can go through machine learning, the basics of NLP. Those are important, because right now, in any interview, they ask you about transformers. That is the most basic, fundamental thing.
PAUL: So, yes, you need to have good fundamentals of NLP data, I feel. You can skip computer vision. Computer vision is not so much required, but at least ML, NLP, these two things, and then directly the things that we are teaching it here.
PAUL: Okay.
Pratham Garg: And, also, when I searched some openings on the job platforms, the thing is that companies are only wanting experience
Pratham Garg: professionals in this field. So, since I don't have any formal experience, what I'm…
Pratham Garg: trying to build a POC at my company, And build a few things.
PAUL: once, like, 10 months is there, probably, like, after 12 months, you have broke that. So, generally, some people look, but if you have that skill, they do have. Okay, so, like, in some cases, it's a 10, like, minimum 3 years of experience. Then you do not apply. It's something, like, nothing that you can do, because you have only 12 months.
PAUL: Okay, so they're nothing, but at least the skills that we are teaching is, like, state-of-the-art. I know that if there is a medium-scale or a small-scale organization, yes, they can hire a one-year guy. Because, like, even we do hire college graduates, because they know the real stuff that we are actually looking for. Probably, I don't need an ML engineer.
PAUL: I just need an engineer who does that specific task, or my… based on my requirement. If he's good at that, yes, I will hire him. As simple as that.
Pratham Garg: Okay, so, will you…
Pratham Garg: advice that if I can do some ML work in my company, right now, in my, role, and then pitch
Pratham Garg: To other companies when I make a switch, so… so, is that, good?
Pratham Garg: advice, or should I build a portfolio of
Pratham Garg: projects where, where there is some…
PAUL: see, yes, at least one ML project that you can start working. Okay, you can look into, like, one of the Udemy courses. Okay, so there, I think, ML projects are there. From there, you will get an overall idea. You can say that in an interview because you are only 12 months experience. Okay, you can say that I have worked on a POC.
PAUL: Something like that, you can build up a story. Okay, little bit storytelling is important, if you are, doing that. So, a little bit explore. At least two or three, projects. Pick one domain only for you, because with one year's of experience, you don't need to jump into 10 different domains.
PAUL: Okay, stick to one domain that you are currently working. Based on that, try to prepare a use case. Okay, and then little bit of NLP fundamentals are really important. For a one-year guy, if I'm hiring, I will ask him some common questions about transformers.
PAUL: read.
Pratham Garg: hookers.
PAUL: Like, it's a… it has become a national, like, international standards. If you really don't know about transformers, then how do you know about aliens? That's why.
PAUL: Because every LLM or SLM, they are using the underlying, concept.
PAUL: Of the transformers, like attention, self-attention, so these are very common. That's, like, those things you need to cover if you want to really crack the technical intel.
Pratham Garg: Okay, so, and this… Course can be a…
Pratham Garg: cherry on the top if I.
PAUL: Yes, that is on the top. Like, if you know, because this is right now the state of the art. In 2025, these are the standards. Okay, like, transformers, these are, like, I can say, like, 2 to 3 years back, old standards. Okay, but yes, everybody is expecting that you should know the fundamentals.
PAUL: then you can say, if you know the fundamentals, then your instincts become much more clear. It means that you can take better decisions, that, okay, I should take this path.
PAUL: If your instincts are wrong, it means that if they are not good, then you will go in the wrong direction. So that's why having strong fundamentals
PAUL: It's pretty much important.
Pratham Garg: All right, all right, understood. Thanks, Paul. Thank you, team. Thank you.
PAUL: All right, Ratham, yes. Now, Rahul.
Rahul Parihar: Hey, thanks, Paul.
Rahul Parihar: First of all, Accumulating, such a beautiful, you know, layout course.
Rahul Parihar: So, I have two questions. First…
Rahul Parihar: is, as you are excited to building up a new platform, I'm also trying to…
Rahul Parihar: portray and architect a use case, specifically in my domain, using FastAPI, using Gen AI platform, components which use…
Rahul Parihar: OpenAI SDK, LangChan, and Audit Logger, configurations to DBs, rate limiters, and those kind of scrubs.
Rahul Parihar: My question is…
Rahul Parihar: in terms of doing the POC and moving it to production is a completely different ballgame altogether, you know? Yes. When you're talking about large sorts of…
PAUL: Yes, yes, exactly. Like, POC, you can build it within, like, 3 weeks to 4 weeks, easily.
Rahul Parihar: Correct.
PAUL: Then to move it in production, it might take 4 to 5 months.
PAUL: That happens with, like, every team, I can say.
PAUL: Because it does.
PAUL: It comes into the picture, actually, when you make it into production.
Rahul Parihar: Like, yeah, exactly. So, in terms of, sharing and technicality topics like, Nexus event services, for example, like taking large payloads and produce and consume those payloads.
Rahul Parihar: You know, using… extracting from Audit Logger, taking into metadata and payload from NS3.
Rahul Parihar: So, talking about the… from an architectural perspective, are you going ahead in the right direction of thinking process? Are you developing that thinking process with the technicality depth?
Rahul Parihar: That architect can sit, lay out the 30,000 feet information, 10,000 feet information, and also go to 100,000
Rahul Parihar: feed information.
Rahul Parihar: in designing a platform, you know? So, like, how you guys are right now, you know, you know what use case you're trying to solve.
PAUL: Alright, now see, the journey that you are telling, like, from 30,000 to… it's an incremental process. Okay, now that.
Rahul Parihar: endlessly.
PAUL: I cannot teach you.
Rahul Parihar: that.
PAUL: specific to unique, like, every system will be somehow a little bit, like, I can say, there can be similarity 70%, but 30% uniqueness will be there. So, really unique. I can tell you, okay, now, this is the way you can build the system.
PAUL: But how to make it better? I can give you suggestions and improvements, okay? Now, this is how you can do it.
PAUL: But really, like, you have to apply, and then you have to come up.
PAUL: With your own benchmarks that, okay, now, yes, whether this is working or not. So that becomes an incremental process. So, really, I cannot say that, yes, this is going to it. Because there are certain things that I can say that, yes, for sure you can do it. Because these are the common standards, like an SDLC, period. Because once you have built the rack, then your main SDLC comes into the picture. And that is pretty much the common standards, but with respect to the AI
PAUL: But there are a lot of…
PAUL: privacy, ethical considerations that comes into the picture. Really, if you are trying to add those things, okay? So, it becomes a little bit incremental. So, directly, I cannot say that journey from 30,200 feet, okay, it becomes very hard.
PAUL: Okay.
Rahul Parihar: Very hard.
PAUL: Because I know that it might take 6 months to 7 months for each system. I cannot directly say. My team will do it, when I will get more bugs in my system, then I know that, okay, now this is the bottleneck, then I need to resolve this one. So…
PAUL: Somehow, like, really, in one shot, I cannot think. It's totally dependent on that AI system that you are working on.
Rahul Parihar: Okay, got it. And my second question, is about, this
Rahul Parihar: AWS Generative AI certification course is coming up, opening up in November 2018, right?
Rahul Parihar: How this course, from a technical standpoint, will help to solve some of the real-time project
Rahul Parihar: technical AWS Bedrock-related questions, so are we.
PAUL: Not like…
Rahul Parihar: bedrock in a scale…
PAUL: AWS Bedrock agents are not mentioned in your syllabus, but I'll be talking about that. So, generally, that part is covered in the agents class.
PAUL: Okay, much more. But I'll be talking about Bedrock. It means that in Bedrock, how you can add guides, how you can add a knowledge base. Okay, so those things, like, in one class, I can cover it, by taking a simple use case. So from there, you will get the idea of working with Bedrock agents.
PAUL: Because, you know, here we'll be talking about AWS in detail, so I think that is, like, in one class, I can cover the core, things there.
Rahul Parihar: And specifically, if I want to develop or work on my own product in one of the projects, can I ask specific questions or technical questions that… the challenges that I'm facing, which I'm building up my own?
PAUL: If it is open source, then you can ask me. If it is completely closed, like, only for that, okay, then, like, you can drop me a mail, I can just look. The idea is that, if it is open source, other students can also give their inputs
PAUL: Like, I have seen, like, in previous batches, like, even one guy hired two simply, like, two interns. Okay, because their work was good. So simply, like, yes, those technical questions, for sure, you can ask, if it is open source. If you have a POC, you can let me know, yes, this is not working, how to improve this.
PAUL: Okay, how to upgrade a certain component, those type of inputs I can provide from my site.
Rahul Parihar: Awesome, Paul. Looking forward for that. Okay, thank you very much.
PAUL: Oh, great job.
Amarsrinivas Eli: Paul, can I ask?
PAUL: Yes, go ahead.
Amarsrinivas Eli: Yeah.
Amarsrinivas Eli: Hi, Paul. First of all, thanks to Krish, you, and, Mayank as well, for doing an excellent job. So, I will come straight away to the point. My main point is, currently, I'm going through, CP videos, presented by Krish, and I have done… gone through those videos as well. And as part of that, I took Cursor Pro, subscription.
Amarsrinivas Eli: So… but what I'm doing is, after doing that POC, I try to replicate it, to linking to the… my organization has given me one AWS playground, but I don't want to use my cursor
Amarsrinivas Eli: API key to the organization, because obviously, right, we should not use it. So what I have done is,
Amarsrinivas Eli: I want… is there a way we can, also get how do we link AWS services, like, calling from…
Amarsrinivas Eli: cursor ID or cloud desktop using plugins or SDK, that is one question I have. Second question is, when we run the code, instead of using our own open API or this key, what I have alternate, I have done is, I have created a API in Lambda, and in that Lambda, I'm calling Bedrock, and that API Lambda function I exposed as an API,
Amarsrinivas Eli: And that API calling in the cursor desktop to go through my organization API key to avoid data security, rather than using open source or…
PAUL: Yes, like, probably, like, you… you are using… your LLM provider is basically, like, AWS in some places, if I said. Yes, exactly. Alright, that is fine, like, everybody does that.
Amarsrinivas Eli: Yeah, basically.
PAUL: not only…
Amarsrinivas Eli: Is this the right approach, or… or is my question.
PAUL: That is the right approach for organizations, very specifically, because the same thing is being done, like, Azure OpenAI also, you pay somebody's using Azure in that case. That approach is correct. It's something, like, it means that you are using a certain ID, but in that ID, you want your own custom LLM.
PAUL: Okay, the LLM provider, you were manually selecting it, and you were using it his…
PAUL: That is pretty much the correct approach. There is no issue with that approach that you are working with.
Amarsrinivas Eli: Yeah, but, that setup, I have asked MCP to do the setup, and it was set up, but I'm… how do I validate, whether it is… every time I'm going to AWS and checking the CloudWatch, okay, my query is coming here, then good, we are getting data. So I'm validating manually. That is one point. Of course, I added a step as well. My second question is, basically.
Amarsrinivas Eli: when coming to Langraph or specific, that question I have, being an integration architect or enterprise integration architect, every month we… I used to assess some software products, and while assessing the software products.
Amarsrinivas Eli: We do have a lot of, you know, API Swagger files of that product.
Amarsrinivas Eli: So, for example, if a product, or if even a SAP S4 HANA also has a lot of
Amarsrinivas Eli: Hell a lot of APIs, right? If I give a complete Swagger file of specific API link, will Langraph will automatically identify the relationships between, for example, purchase order, header, line items, schedule lines.
Amarsrinivas Eli: Rather than asking it quickly…
PAUL: It's not about Langraf here, you have to understand.
PAUL: Okay, land graphs are used to build agents. The same thing, like, there has to be some type of data, if I'm talking about the Swagger files here.
PAUL: Now, how that file, for example, with respect to RAG that you can build, so that the LLM can understand that particular relationship, there it comes, so it is really not Langrav. Using Langrav, you can integrate it with a LangChan or any other framework.
PAUL: That you have to understand. Langraph is used for orchestration of the agents. Within the agents, you might be using anything. It can be LangChain, it can be Llama Index, to read your data sources and then try to find the relationship. Okay, so that is possible. So it's not…
Amarsrinivas Eli: Is it possible, Paul? Is it possible, Paul, if we upload a Swagger file, is there any specific technique to identify the relationship between one API and another API? Because nowadays, database also, they are training on implementing RAG and getting reports, analytics, it is.
PAUL: I didn't bang number.
Amarsrinivas Eli: model relation.
PAUL: What tech-based solutions are there?
PAUL: So, similarly…
Amarsrinivas Eli: But APDs can implement this?
PAUL: in… with respect to APIs, really, like, we need to look into that particular Swagger file information that you have. Now, how you are doing the parsing, and after that parsing, like, how, that context is presented to the LL with respect to that relationships, finding.
PAUL: I can say, yes, it is possible, but really, the type of data and others that we need to look into.
Amarsrinivas Eli: Yeah, because after Krish, video, MCP, I have built my own MCP server, and I have trained one of the Swagger files, and it is giving purchase order reports and everything, but…
Amarsrinivas Eli: On top of trained query, if I ask new query, again, it is taking time to generate that logic in… it's keep on creating Python workbooks in the left side. Okay. Yeah, that is where I'm facing, and it is taking a long time. And the original code is disturbing, that is where I'm…
Amarsrinivas Eli: Struggling, actually, currently.
PAUL: If it is completely dynamic at every point of time, if the response is dynamic, if you know that there are certain steps, okay, that needs to be followed, and if they are static, okay, it becomes much easier. If it is dynamic, then it becomes tougher, because the main problem with, like, simply agent-based solutions and others, the response time.
PAUL: The response time increases very, very high.
PAUL: Just because of a decision. It means that what is your LLM that you are taking into account, that also matters.
PAUL: Whether you are going for something approved model or a thinking-based model, it will take more time. Like, if you are going with MOE-based models, okay, it will take more time. It means that it might take more than, 200 seconds, okay? So…
PAUL: Yes, so, like, really, we need to analyze the components, whether they can be static, if it is dynamic, for sure, it will be high. So, somehow, you need to define some rules based on that rules. The agent need to take a step-by-step decision.
PAUL: Okay, so, yes, like, it really depends upon the data and how we are doing the parsing, so that… that context, through the context, how we can define the relationship.
PAUL: Because the better the context, then we can get a better relationship. That part, really, like…
Amarsrinivas Eli: Yeah, last 2 minutes, actually, or 1 minute. So, basically, in this course, that relational, any use cases being covered, Paul?
PAUL: Yes, I think I will be taking an example through Bana, and I'll be showing you, like, from SQL to text, that part.
Amarsrinivas Eli: Okay, and… and one more last question is costing perspective, because at the architect's level, when we… it's not only identifying the solution or designing the architecture. Also, when vendor is presenting, also, we need to identify the costing of the… how… for example, any algorithm will take input of embedding tokens and output tokens, right?
PAUL: Correct.
Amarsrinivas Eli: So, when we use the cursor or anything, it is keep on giving a lot of text. All these are costing to the customers, right? Is there a session for us, basically, how a project costing has to be, for example, in the PWS… based on PVOS, I'm not asking…
PAUL: See, I am… I won't be talking with respect to a project when I'm, for example, discussing embeddings. I'll be simply saying, okay, Gemini. Gemini, this is the cost for 1 million tokens. Now, you count the number of tokens from your data, and then you do the… an estimation cost.
Amarsrinivas Eli: Okay.
PAUL: Okay, because, see, I cannot say. Now, see, embedding is one cost, then comes your vector DB cost.
PAUL: Okay, like, a lot of component comes, that I will say, like, this calls this, if it is open source, this, because at the end of the day, if you're using an open source, then you have to host it somewhere.
PAUL: Okay, now that particular cost inference, so a lot of things comes under the picture, I'll be telling you that, but really, it's up to you, then that's why somebody might use a simply unhosted product like PineConnet or any stuff like that, or Quadrant. It becomes much easier.
PAUL: Okay, so I'll be letting you know that, okay, now this particular product has this cost. Now, again, when you are hosting it in your own platform, then yes, what is the type of instance that you are selecting? It totally depends upon that.
PAUL: what is the amount of data that is coming? So, those things, really, I cannot say. I can take a rough estimation of few proprietary products and let you know that, yes, this is a rough estimated costing, which are right now the industry standards.
Amarsrinivas Eli: So, since you are covering AWS, Watt Studio, in AWS also, can we use, any other option? Because, problem is, I cannot, use, local
Amarsrinivas Eli: cursor or Cloud IDEA desktops in my office laptop, but AWS Playground we have. Is there a way we can use, instead of cursor in the AWS Any Studio? Will that be covered?
PAUL: In SageMaker Studio, there is VS Code. If you have an Office laptop in that, you can simply take up. For example, if I share any code, it will be in GitHub. From GitHub, we can simply clone it.
Amarsrinivas Eli: Oh, okay.
PAUL: Okay.
Amarsrinivas Eli: That installation also will be covered, or you.
PAUL: But really, like, there is no installation. You have to.
Amarsrinivas Eli: No, not, not inflation, the setup, setup of the,
Amarsrinivas Eli: connecting to AWS or connecting to, API?
PAUL: There is no such connection, you have to just click on the surface, open that VS code, and you just need to click on clone option, and the GitHub link that I'll be sharing, you just need to use that.
Amarsrinivas Eli: Okay, because, in Kharai, we…
PAUL: just look into AWS SageMaker Studio, from there you will get the idea. It's pretty much one click, one click. Otherwise, I will share it, because initially, I don't want to start with AWS. Right now, the core part is the fundamentals. Probably with AWS part, I think it will come after one month or two months, at least when we start Project 1, okay?
Amarsrinivas Eli: Thanks, thanks, Craig. Thanks, Mike.
PAUL: So, now let's move to our next participant.
PAUL: Shub, I think. Shub doveil?
PAUL: Sure, are you there?
PAUL: Okay, issue is not there. Let's go with Mustan.
PAUL: Muhammad… Okay, Gossic Shaha.
PAUL: Raj Shakhar, Kirankee…
PAUL: Yes, anyone can go ahead, please.
PAUL: Any particular order, no Krishna, there is no particular order. There are two Krishnas. After that, I will unmute both Krishna, okay? Yeah, please go ahead.
mohammad Abujaradeh: Hello? Hello? Can you hear me?
PAUL: Yeah, Mama, I can't hear you.
mohammad Abujaradeh: Yes, first of all, really thank you guys for taking the time, for making this course.
mohammad Abujaradeh: And thanks to you, Paul, for your patience going over all those questions.
mohammad Abujaradeh: Actually, I have a few questions, but most of them, actually, they've been covered, but…
mohammad Abujaradeh: I got a couple of comments, and one of the people asked about Anaconda that being blocked from some company. I ran to that, and matter of fact, I was managed to get Jupyter and VS Code and get that to work, actually, so that's… that's an option.
mohammad Abujaradeh: And one of the other things, also, to add a comment on your data science basics.
mohammad Abujaradeh: I totally agree with you about the transformer, because I took a course 8, 9 months ago.
mohammad Abujaradeh: the most important part is the transformer, I totally agree with you. By the way, I came from,
mohammad Abujaradeh: experienced, senior software engineer, more like a back-end and front-end. I'm working for cloud, 15 plus years.
mohammad Abujaradeh: So, I do have a couple of questions. One of them is…
mohammad Abujaradeh: I know you guys, congratulations for getting a product launch.
mohammad Abujaradeh: The one that Krish showed us.
PAUL: Yeah, you know.
mohammad Abujaradeh: It doesn't have to be right now, but for later on, can you guys share with us, basically.
mohammad Abujaradeh: the lessons.
PAUL: Yes, yes, yes, yes, we'll be sharing with every student the idea.
mohammad Abujaradeh: challenges, the ideas, why and how things… it doesn't have to be in detail, because I totally understand it's a product you guys own, but it's nice to hear from you, like, a real experience on how things are going.
PAUL: Alright, from the RAT perspective, I will give you a rough idea.
mohammad Abujaradeh: Sure.
PAUL: In the class, so that's part of, like, a project, so it's something, like, little bit, I will give you an idea, but only the rack part. Other than that, it's something like their own wind, that's fine.
mohammad Abujaradeh: And I'll be honest with you, I know AI becoming like an ocean of knowledge.
mohammad Abujaradeh: I do feel, and I agree with you, like, based on what I'm seeing, at least in different YouTube videos, RAG, it's becoming now a must-have
mohammad Abujaradeh: skill that everyone should have. So, I totally appreciate you guys going over all that.
mohammad Abujaradeh: The last question I do have, and as I mentioned, most of it got answered from other guys, I know Krishi's starting a new agentic series. Is it gonna cross paths with this bootcamp, or is it gonna be a totally different path?
mohammad Abujaradeh: And that's…
Krish Naik: No, no, no, it's almost similar, but that will be in YouTube. It'll be a basic types of RAG that we'll be discussing, yeah?
mohammad Abujaradeh: Okay, thank you very much, and I think that covered my question, and thank you again, guys.
PAUL: Alright, Mama.
PAUL: Okay, next, I think Mastan or Kaushik.
masthan: Hey, hi, this is Mastam, can you hear me?
PAUL: Yes, I guess.
masthan: Yes, I can. Okay, yeah, thank you very much. I… I'm just very new to this, Gen AI, and
masthan: or RAG and MCP, I keep hearing so many questions. Great, I mean, at least for me, it's the first night. I heard this, all this, but still, I'm just trying to catch up. And thank you, Krish. I just messaged you, and last week, I saw your video in YouTube, then
masthan: It took me, like, really interesting on this, and just looking forward to learn more things. Thank you.
Krish Naik: Thank you.
masthan: Thank you.
PAUL: Alright, next, I think there is caution.
KaushikSaha: Aye, yeah.
KaushikSaha: Hello, hello, Paul, Chris, and Meng, and thank you so much for this wonderful session, and special thanks to, Chris, because I've been following Chris and his video. Though I'm not from data science or developer background, I'm from cybersecurity background, but
KaushikSaha: while I was getting the fundamental concept of the AI, and I was thinking, how can I use that, or probably, what will the future in cybersecurity in coming years, so that I can, you know, be in that domain, and what knowledge I can gain.
KaushikSaha: So, while I see the rag, probably I have Thought of to…
KaushikSaha: Because when we use ChatGPT or some other LLMs, we are not getting enough, you know, answer in terms of
KaushikSaha: cybersecurity perspective, in terms of, let's say, KQL perspective, I'm more on the Azure security.
KaushikSaha: So… so probably we can create, more on a rack perspective, giving more knowledge on cybersecurity on any of the LLM, and get some data.
KaushikSaha: And, sir, that is my, expectation.
PAUL: Alright, Kajiksi. Now, is it your domain again? Like, this is a domain-specific question, based on that. So, for example, like, one of the most common ones is, like,
PAUL: in using machine learning, like, going through the logs and looking for fraud detection or any type of… like, phishing, for example. Going through multiple URLs and then really understanding, okay.
PAUL: Now, the question comes based on the data. So, similarly, like, you will be having some type of data and other source, okay, from those audit logs or anything that you'll be looking into, okay, now that particular information, like, based on ML model or some probabilistic model, statistical model, you can take that decision.
KaushikSaha: To a certain extent, it helps you.
PAUL: So, that part with respect to RAG, a little bit about integrations, I can talk. But really, with respect to the practical implementations in the schools, I don't think, like, we'll be doing that. But if you want something, I can let you know. And really, like, for you, okay, based on your domain, okay.
PAUL: You can look into the European Union AI laws.
PAUL: Okay, now those laws are very, very important when you are building any type of AI product, and most of the laws are actually coming from the cybersecurity, okay, fundamentals. It means that I, simply if I talk about even the AC Council.
PAUL: Okay, team, they have been working, few other organizations, okay, who have been working very specifically, they have been building these laws, the ideas to make AI much more sovereign, okay? Now, those laws are really not followed in India, I can say, okay? There are certain, I can say.
PAUL: things, really, people have not adopted it, but I feel that going forward, there will be certain laws, like AI laws, like, for every country. Probably after 10 years, it can be. Not right now implemented, but yes, there has to be some type of rules.
PAUL: That will come. So, right now, really, based on your use case that you do work, you can let me know, like, after a session, we can have a talk regarding that, and I can let you know.
PAUL: that how RAG can help you, but really, like, what is the data source and other stuff? Little bit info that I need from your end, okay? And then I can let you know exactly how those things that can be done.
KaushikSaha: Sure, sure. Just to give a glimpse that I'm already working on the SOAR automations for a couple of use cases, and…
KaushikSaha: already we are almost doing, you know, automating the A1 task of the SOC analyst, right?
KaushikSaha: But there are a couple of things which can be done. Like, currently, if I ask for ChatGPT to create a KQL query, which can be used in Sentinel, so it cannot give in a proper optimized way. So, probably, on top of the LLM, if we can give more data on the…
PAUL: Yes, exactly correct. So, probably see. Now, that cybersecurity, very specifically, I'm talking about, there are less LLMs who really have in-depth knowledge of cybersecurity.
PAUL: Okay, actually, regarding it can be anything. Okay, so if you simply ask how to hack it, and give me a cross-site scripting script, okay, or probably some type of shell that I need to bring into
PAUL: they cannot grip it, okay, because most of them will be using guardrails. They will block such type of queries, and they will give you much more generic answers, which is really not your requirement.
PAUL: Okay, because everyone, whoever is in the market, they will be using one layer of gartels. If you try to ask something sensitive or anything related to that, it becomes a problematic. So, in that case, you have to actually look for open areas, where there are no gartels. It means you can ask it anything.
PAUL: no blocks are there. Now, those things will be very important. Now, you bring your own data on top of that, you use those open LLMs, like anything from Mestral, they have good open LLMs, and that will give you good response.
KaushikSaha: Okay, and one more thing, I have always this question, because we have seen on this 2 to 3 years, there are different kind of LLMs there. So, if I work on, let's say, on particular use case or project that we are using, Llama.
KaushikSaha: And on top of that, we are using RAG. So, in future, if we see that there is a new LLM came.
KaushikSaha: So we can utilize that, right? Keeping that track what we have built.
PAUL: Yes, you can do that at any point of time. It means that that is a playable component. It means you can change the LLM at any point of time.
KaushikSaha: Okay.
PAUL: Okay, now, there are a few things. It means that every LLM has a certain way of taking the context into pictures. Now, that particular thing you need to keep in mind.
PAUL: Okay, so, like, probably, like, every LLM will be having a fixed context window, those things. Now, those specifications and configurations of the LLM, you need to take care of.
PAUL: Now, if the context window is 32K, and if you send us 64K, okay, now that becomes a problem. Now, those things you need to take care at any point. You can change your vector databases, not a big deal. You can change your embedding model, not a big deal. You can change your LLM, not a big deal, but yes, you really need to know the configurations.
PAUL: So, probably, again, the production cost, right? I thought that I built a… Yes, exactly.
KaushikSaha: tag for my asset, which can I utilize in multiple LLM, but it… maybe I need to reuse the database embedding and the vector thing.
PAUL: Starting from embedding, like, you can go everything for open source, but again, that open source, you need to host it somewhere. So, hosting costs, or take a proprietary, something like that. These things we'll be talking in this course in detail.
KaushikSaha: Thank you so much. Thank you so much for explaining patiently. The last question, I'm using the Mac 1, Mac M1.
PAUL: I'm also in the back M1 Pro, so…
KaushikSaha: AGV, that is an 8GB.
PAUL: Okay, 8GB. 8GB, in some cases, you might feel a lag in your system, in some cases.
KaushikSaha: Do we have…
PAUL: Are they looking?
KaushikSaha: different options, like any services which can be utilized, or many…
PAUL: be taking in the next class some browser-based ideas that I'll be talking about.
KaushikSaha: Opal.
PAUL: Okay.
KaushikSaha: Thank you so much for your time. Thank you so much, Chris, as well.
PAUL: Now let's move to next, and there is Jay Moore.
PAUL: change, or Raja Shaker, yeah, you can also do it.
Rajashekhar Sheelvant: Hi, Paul. It was…
PAUL: Then Krishna, both Krishna have done, yeah, please.
Rajashekhar Sheelvant: Yeah, this is Rasha Karir.
PAUL: Yes.
Rajashekhar Sheelvant: Thank you, everyone, Paul, Krisha, and Mayank. It is for a…
Rajashekhar Sheelvant: Providing this, horse at such a whatever price.
Rajashekhar Sheelvant: So I've been, following the… your…
Rajashekhar Sheelvant: all the courses through the… I mean, most of the courses through YouTube and all.
Rajashekhar Sheelvant: And, been implementing as well.
Rajashekhar Sheelvant: So, but it's all been kind of POC.
Rajashekhar Sheelvant: kind of things that I… using open sources and all. But to implement, in the production, I know this course is about, implementing in the production as well, to the end of this course, right? So…
Rajashekhar Sheelvant: Since I have been doing this, Pocs as well.
Rajashekhar Sheelvant: I was looking at some course where we can directly jump into that.
Rajashekhar Sheelvant: the… The production-based, application.
PAUL: Really, there is no course in the market who teaches you production. Nobody can teach you production. Okay, the idea is to make it close to production. At least I can let you know these are the services, this is how you can do user-based profiling, okay, because, there are a lot of things. We'll be only talking about the AI perspective.
PAUL: We won't be talking about the SDLC prospect.
PAUL: You have to understand that. Right now, if you ask me, I can tell you the core concepts, but really, how you want to take your logs, totally up to you. That part I won't be telling you. You can save your logs in GCP, AWS, so many others. Now, how to do application monitoring? You can use Datadog, you can use Sentry, but really, that is not the point here. Okay, so here we'll be focusing much more towards the AI part, and I will tell you that, okay, now, these are the services that can be
PAUL: Integrated for application monitoring, or for logging.
PAUL: I hope you get my point.
Rajashekhar Sheelvant: Okay, okay.
Rajashekhar Sheelvant: So, one more question is, I come from Microsoft and Azure background.
Rajashekhar Sheelvant: And, yeah, so we have taken a pair… so, I mean, we are, early adaptations into the, AI now, agentic AI and, RAG-based applications and all. So, where, we would like… we were…
Rajashekhar Sheelvant: Working on an idea of, building a solution for,
Rajashekhar Sheelvant: compliance, Azure Compliance Security, and, DLP, related activities, and,
Rajashekhar Sheelvant: build some dashboard and all. And also.
Rajashekhar Sheelvant: To capture the prompts, and add the guardrails at the org level, and all those things.
Rajashekhar Sheelvant: So, the recommendations from Microsoft is basically…
Rajashekhar Sheelvant: to use Symantec Kernel or Azure Foundry and all…
PAUL: if…
Rajashekhar Sheelvant: Yeah, so…
Rajashekhar Sheelvant: So, the challenge we face here is that whenever we go into the, any of the general courses and everywhere, it's all over, it is,
Rajashekhar Sheelvant: Langchain and all those things, which is…
PAUL: That's why, because your requirement is niche, very niche. It means that, you have a very specific requirement, but I know 90% of the world doesn't need it.
PAUL: Okay, there are rather better ways of doing that, like, very specifically for Microsoft and EAM, Semantic Kernel and Autogen, both of those frameworks have been changing a lot. If you look into every three things, a lot of major things that come. And again, at the end of the day, they become deprecated, and Microsoft integrated both of those into… and Microsoft Agentic framework. That's the new name.
Rajashekhar Sheelvant: And funny thing is that, they themselves say that atrojan you can use, it's not for the production purpose, it's for the POC kind of activity.
Rajashekhar Sheelvant: And semantic kernel is what we have to use for a production-based application.
Rajashekhar Sheelvant: So that's where it's, like, a house.
PAUL: Now, both of those things are deprecated, and the new thing is Microsoft Agent Tech Framework. I know, that's why, really, we don't deal into a lot. That's why we teach AutoGen in our Agentech Framework class very specifically, and Mike has created that, Udemy course, but, like, we have seen
PAUL: there has been a lot of major changes. Like, if I just tracked 6 months of autogen journey into GitHub, okay, if you look into the issues, okay, a lot of issues are there, though it has been widely accepted by the community. The community is using, but I feel that other frameworks, like Langrav and others, they are pretty much stable.
PAUL: Okay, like, not very huge major changes, like, the entire APIs are changed. Okay, so a few things we have seen, but, like, it's totally up to you what you want to adopt, and according to you, like, if you want to stick to that, okay, you can stick. Because really, the thing that you are looking for, it's niche, so that's why people teach it less. We know.
Rajashekhar Sheelvant: Okay, okay. And thank you again, everyone, for this.
PAUL: Oh, right.
Shubh Dubey: No.
PAUL: Yes, Krishna, who is there next?
Krishna: Okay.
PAUL: Jay, okay, huh, Jay Goh, then Krishna.
Jay More: Hello, hello sir. I am a recent 2025 graduate, and I am working as a cloud administrator at GEO.
Jay More: I am exploring various fields right now, but I have been very keen and curious on agentic AI and LLM, so I have been recently exploring a lot of content of Krishna itself.
Jay More: So just I want to ask, as a fresher now, because it's been, 4 to 5 months that I'm working as a cloud administrator at Geo, so if I want to switch into Agentic AI,
Jay More: And, LLM field. So, what should be my roadmap now in RAG and all that?
PAUL: the same or seen. Like, if you want to move into that, the fundamentals of Python comes into the picture. You have to be good in at least one database that I feel you have to be good in one cloud, okay? And then, really, if you're looking for all Gen AI rules, okay, so…
PAUL: the things that we'll be teaching in this particular course, all those things are important. On top of that, the fundamentals of, like, NLP,
PAUL: and machine learning. Very, very important, if you want to really crack a job.
Jay More: So, sir, right now, if I want to work in your startup, so what is your… what should be my path?
Jay More: to prepare.
PAUL: If I am looking for someone, he should be good with cloud services, that is the first thing, he should be good with at least one database. Okay, he should be, very good with working with APIs.
PAUL: Okay, then, comes the Gen AI part.
PAUL: Okay, like, very specifically based on my requirement, I need someone who is good in RAG, or working with LLMs, or quantization of LLMs. That becomes very, specific requirement of AI. You… so, based on that, in the JD, I'll be mentioning that, and then, like, if you have the skills, you will
PAUL: So, the core fundamental, if I'd say simply, be good in Python, one database, one cloud, and then comes the… at least the fundamentals of ML and Gen AI, and the things that I'll be teaching you in this course.
PAUL: I made my point here.
Jay More: will be…
Jay More: Yes, yes, sir, yes, sir. The most of the topics will be covered in this course, so if I…
PAUL: From Gen AI perspective, yes.
Jay More: Okay, okay, sir, okay. Yes, sir.
PAUL: Okay, but you have to know the fundamentals. I'm… we won't be covering the fundamentals, so the fundamentals of machine learning and NLP, very, very important. That you have to cover.
PAUL: Okay?
Jay More: Yes, sir, sure, sir.
PAUL: Well reached.
PAUL: Next.
kiran k: typo… Am I able to lose?
PAUL: Yes, yes.
kiran k: Hi Paul, this is Kiran. I am from the DevOps and the cloud field for the past 7 plus years, so having a good exposure on the, like, Docker, Kubernetes, Terraform, AWS, and the Azure cloud thing.
kiran k: So, though I didn't get, like, hands-on in my current organization, I started exploring and on the learning mode. Like, I have a basic knowledge on the Python.
kiran k: NLP and the machine learning. So, I'm just, like, I just wanted to pursue, like, switch to platform Jenai things. So, what are the other tools I should be well-versed, or having an answer on for that?
kiran k: Can you please.
PAUL: what are the other tools, majorly now being… your part is much more towards the ops. Okay, now you have to, like, bring the idea of machine learning, like MLOps, LLM ops, into your…
PAUL: Okay, now the idea is you really don't need to jump, because you are highly specialized in ops part, so I will always suggest trying to learn, like, how to deploy machine learning services, how to deploy LLMs. Now, there are things that you need to explore much more. If you want to get into the technicalities of the data part.
PAUL: you can explore that always, but I feel that,
PAUL: Like, majorly, when you look into roles, like, once you have worked for 7 to 8 years of SRE and others, you'll be looking into, like, an AI platform engineer who handles all the AI-related stuff. So, in that particular case.
PAUL: you really don't need. If you know it, it's good. Otherwise, you can always have a conversation with the AI team that exactly how the application is working, and how to make it up at the end of the day.
PAUL: Okay, so it's…
PAUL: better that you look for that LLM of Spart, you work on that, because that becomes your main forte, I feel. But on top of that, the things that we are learning, it always helps you to understand the AI application flow, or basically how the application is working, how the application is starting, and those things, everything, you will understand the entire app flow.
kiran k: Yes, correct, Paul. Like, I'll keep my DevOps and the cloud as my base. Upon that, I need to work on this, like, as you said, LLM, LLM Ops, or… yeah, I got it, yeah.
PAUL: Alright, good.
Krishna: Okay, hey.
Krishna: Yeah, it's name.
PAUL: First of all, thank you for answering all the.
Krishna: Students, courses, questions.
Krishna: Thank you for being patient as well.
Krishna: And,
Krishna: Paul, like, first basic question that comes to my mind is, do you, like, means, as a team, do you offer any paid consulting services as such? Like, when I say consulting services, it's not, like, for development or, implementation or anything like that, it's, like, for…
Krishna: giving the best architecture, like, putting forth some best architecture in place, or something like that. Do you offer any services like that at all?
PAUL: Previously, I used to do, but not right now, because we are pretty much busy with building our own product, that's why.
Krishna: Okay.
PAUL: Okay. We have done it, but for the past 1.5 years, really, we have focused much more on the product, because really, like, if scenario changes, like, it becomes hectic for us. If something, that's why. So, right now, we are much more focused for building our own products.
Krishna: Understood.
PAUL: Okay, but you can take, like, you can take a suggestion, for example, if you feel that, okay, now this component and these things, if you feel that some part is open source, yes, we are, like, you're welcome to discuss that in the class, and you can take your inputs from me, other students from the batch, for sure.
Krishna: Sure, sure, thank you. So the… I mean, just the follow-up question on that means, I'm not using the open source. I already have, a production-based, Azure-based, solution.
Krishna: already implemented. I don't think that is RAC, but some of my colleagues think it is RAG, but
Krishna: So…
Krishna: No, no, I can review the architecture that was in place, which I don't want to give, take others' time as…
PAUL: In high… yes, yes, in high.
Krishna: At a very high level, I will say, like, I have… I have a Snowflake database, I have some… built some big prompts, like, big-sized prompts, getting some SQL generated, based on the… all the tables, and getting the…
Krishna: SQL executed, and then, again, summarizing the… again, prompting it to summarize the output of the SQL, right? That's all is there. I don't think that is ragged, in my opinion.
PAUL: Okay.
Krishna: Yeah, that is… for me, it's, like, simply prompt-based,
Krishna: So that's exactly, where, is there any possibility, like, a 10… I mean, I'm not saying, like, a detailed, like… I mean, I know all the issues that I am facing because of this approach.
Krishna: And what all issues. So, and most of the people I hear, right, like, I have been hearing all… most of the people have been asking about RDBMS and that kind of use cases. So, is there any possibility that
Krishna: we can have, at least one-on-one, because this is very… I cannot… this is not open source, and this is built for a second company as such, so I cannot…
PAUL: That's why I told you. If it is open source, then we can discuss. Otherwise, you can drop me a mail.
PAUL: Based on that, whatever the thoughts, I can let you know. Because really, that's why we named.
Krishna: It's just the thoughts, I'm not looking for, say, it's not completely…
PAUL: I got your point.
Krishna: I totally understand.
PAUL: If you are looking for an approach or a guide, something like that, okay. So, yes, you can drop me a mail. Okay, so that part, I can respond to you back. So, it's not like an open discussion.
Krishna: Yeah, yeah, definitely. Thank you very much. And just a couple of things that I wanted to have. Do we also deal with some kind of fine-tuning in this implementation?
PAUL: A little bit of fine-tuning as well, but it's not in detail.
Krishna: Because fine-tuning can be 9-month course.
Krishna: Oh, yeah.
PAUL: And it will cost you more than $100K.
PAUL: If you want to learn fine-tuning, so if you don't have the resource, nobody can teach you.
Krishna: Okay, excellent. It means I am aware, like, I'm a.
PAUL: I'll be telling you the basics, because even in the class, you can… guys.
PAUL: might think, should I click? If you click, $100 gone from your account.
Krishna: Okay, okay. But, like, at least, means, I would like to see, again, as I said, like, one of my use cases, right? So…
Krishna: I just wanted to understand, at least at that point of time, whenever we reach about fine-tuning, is that fine-tuning an applicable
Krishna: resource for me, or no, I can do… go ahead and use a different approach. So that's something that… I have something in my mind.
PAUL: most of the industry cannot find him. That's why we are launching a rank batch.
Krishna: Yeah.
PAUL: Okay, because to teach fine-tuning, You need infrastructure. It means that from day one, you need infrastructure.
Krishna: Yo.
PAUL: I'm not telling you we're building something good, even I don't know what will be the output.
PAUL: That's why. Okay, to make things good, it means that you need a lot of GPUs, that's why.
PAUL: That is the main problem.
PAUL: That's why we came up with Rack Patch, and every organization is trying to build a rack.
Krishna: Okay, just last thing then. Are we going to study anything about prompt cachings, and what does that mean, and what are the side effects, and when to do, or something like that?
PAUL: We'll be talking about rag-level caching, rather than prompt.
PAUL: Prompt-level caching we won't be talking about.
Krishna: Okay, okay.
Krishna: Is there a concept like prompt-level caching, which I just wanted to understand.
PAUL: DA is, like, if you're working with, dynamic prompts, at that particular point of time, prompt level catching is also done.
PAUL: And very specifically, using frameworks like DSPY for prompt optimization, as well as automation.
Krishna: I think that's all I have, and if you can share your email address, I would like to just spend some time with you, so that at least I can drop in an email, and we can have a discussion if need be.
PAUL: Alright.
Krishna: Yeah, thank you.
PAUL: Alright, in the chat, somebody is asking Dhoshi Naran or Rahavendra at the rate. Chris, sir, could you please bring DSN Python course? It's already available in Udemy, it was created by Mank in detail, there are a lot of lectures, you can have a look into that.
PAUL: K then comes around, K… yes.
Shubh Dubey: Sure.
PAUL: Next questionna, I think.
Shubh Dubey: Yes, sorry, I was gonna jump.
PAUL: Yes, yes, yes.
Shubh Dubey: To go for it.
Shubh Dubey: E apoloso.
Shubh Dubey: So, thanks for this session. So myself, I have 7 plus years of experience in senior, pattern backend development. Currently, I'm going with the, like, bootcamp data science course with Krishna Excel, which is where I'mlish teaching majorly. I have, basic sounds experience on Gen AI. I have done a couple of PR.
PAUL: Don't worry, don't worry. Like, if you're from that batch, all the basics will be covered. So, like, you can follow both this
PAUL: Morning, that night. There will be… because even I will be going probably in that batch at some particular point of time.
PAUL: So don't worry. So, like, there will be a sync, like, if you are coming, it means that you have the basics all covered after that basics directly, because in that batch also, there is a little component about GenAI at the end of the curriculum, if you have looked into.
Shubh Dubey: Yes, yes, yes.
PAUL: So, yes, so, like, it's a proper thing, there won't be any problem.
PAUL: So, like, a good sink, I feel.
Shubh Dubey: Yeah, because actually, I was, at the time, a couple of months back, I was doing, serving a notice period, and I have a discussion model to see that he suggested to do some UDME courses on, agentic AI, which is, like, Krishna XR.
Shubh Dubey: really helped me a lot. I've, like, tried to, like, level up myself on that case. So hopefully that course, like, that ongoing course will help me to enhance my more expertise on this field.
PAUL: Yes, for sure it will help me. Okay, like, I know that in your… in that particular batch, coupons have been provided for Langrap course also. Okay, so yes, like, if you go through that course, it will be helpful. For sure.
Shubh Dubey: Yes, I have almost completed it. I, like, did some, interviews on that. I, like, I was pretty much close to that to get some offers, but at the end, some things not happened.
PAUL: No, it's fine.
Shubh Dubey: Yeah.
Shubh Dubey: So… You give 3, 4, 5, 6, then you become more and more. But I may be… my, like, roadmap is I want to, like, continue to be AI ML engineer, so, like, have some Python, Mongo, Flask framework, and all this, like, basic, backend things which is required, and…
PAUL: Right now, don't worry, from that course, you will learn majorly all the basics. From this course, what are the recent things that have been going on with respect to Gen AI? Because in that course, the GenAI part is just a basic.
PAUL: Okay, just like, and not even level 1, I will say it's level 0. And here it's level 1, 2, 3, 4. Okay, so, yes, like, you will be having that entire knowledge, I can say.
Shubh Dubey: Okay, that's fine. Thank you, thank you both.
PAUL: Alright, sure.
Krishna: Hi, Paul. This is Krishna.
PAUL: Yeah, Krishna, please go ahead.
PAUL: Okay, Krishna… Okay, Krishna?
Krishna: Hi, hi, Bob.
PAUL: Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah, I'm audible.
Krishna: Yeah, yeah, thank you so much for your time and patience. Most of my questions have been answered. I have only one question. You mentioned that in our syllabus, we'll be covering Dockers using containerization. So, are we going to touch base on Kubernetes as well?
PAUL: Kubernetes services directly available. It means that I won't be doing the setup. If I plan… okay, because, see, EK, Kubernetes is costlier to understand. Really, for this course, do I need Kubernetes? Because at the end of the day, the same thing that I'll be Dockerizing, you can run it in a pod. Okay.
PAUL: So, that's why, like, I don't feel I need to teach Kubernetes, it's a costly service, probably I can just show you a demo. That is the main thing. Because, again, for that Kubernetes dashboard, you need to pay a lot in AWS, EKS for that. Similarly, like, all the Kubernetes-hosted services are costly, I think. It's not cheap.
Krishna: That's.
PAUL: That's why, like, I can show you a demo later on, like, at the end of the course, okay? But really, like, Kubernetes is not, right now this. We are much more focused towards Gen AI and RAM.
Krishna: All right, understand, understand. Thank you, Paul, that's all I have. Thank you so much.
PAUL: Alright, Krishna.
PAUL: Next, I think Rava Vendra V is there. Shubam, Arian Gupta.
PAUL: Krishna already done, so lower your hand, please.
PAUL: Only 5 people are left, please go ahead and grab Aventra. Yeah, Rav Aventra.
Raghavendra V: Yeah, yeah.
Raghavendra V: Thanks a lot, thanks for, being very patient with all the questions. Yeah, I wanted to show my, sincere request, or sincere gratitude towards, Krishna Xer, because…
Raghavendra V: I have landed upon, into corporate, only because of his courses on YouTube. Posts that, have followed his,
Raghavendra V: his previous, venture, One Neuron, where I've been, like, took up courses from there also. But, sincere, thanks there. I have, one particular question. Recently we are in our organization, we are working on, knowledge graphs, basically.
Raghavendra V: So, I have very basic question, like.
Raghavendra V: Building unified knowledge graphs and use GraphRAC approach to join and reason, all across the datasets are…
Raghavendra V: have separated vector databases, and have an agent sitting on the databases, and get a master agent to connect all these dots. Like, which one would you prefer, or why?
PAUL: have a master agent to take the major decision, but your major, I can say, whichever GraphDB, like, NeoForge, they can be connected through multiple agents to find unified relationship.
PAUL: That will be something. The master agent should only take the decision.
Raghavendra V: Okay. Okay, based on the outputs from the slave agents.
Raghavendra V: Okay, like, is it, like,
Raghavendra V: GraphRag I should use, or agentic rag, in the sense?
PAUL: That, see, if there is an orchestration of multiple agents, we do generally call it an agentic graph rag that you can think about, because behind the scenes, you are using a graph database, that's right.
PAUL: Okay, got it. Okay, so it is a graph rag only, but an agentic one, because you are doing an orchestration of multiple agents, like master, with multiple sweeps.
Raghavendra V: Yeah, I think, I wanted to more, learn towards, this, part going forward.
PAUL: We'll be discussing, GraphRag.
PAUL: Okay, so… but, with agents or not, or really, I'm not sure, so… but yeah, with respect to timing, we…
Raghavendra V: Okay, got it.
PAUL: Because so many things are there, this is day one, like, really, like, we'll be having so many sessions, like, more than 30, 42, exactly what is that? So, but yes, I know, Graft Rive will be covered.
Raghavendra V: Yeah, basically that was a selling point for me to join this course. But yeah, thank you so much.
PAUL: Alright.
PAUL: Next, I think Shubham is there, Arian Gupta.
PAUL: sugar bomb… Ariane. Oh, hello?
PAUL: Yes, Arian.
Aaryan Gupta: Hi, boy.
Aaryan Gupta: First of all, thank you all, and thanks to the panelists. So, I have 3 years of analytics background experience, and with analytics as the niche, I am now transitioning into ML.
Aaryan Gupta: So, following Chris's video, I have caught up to the modular programming in ML, and…
Aaryan Gupta: Now, since, I'm keeping up with what's going into in AI, I am also doing this RAC course, which you are teaching.
Aaryan Gupta: So now, my question is, like, what could be the open roles I can apply to in the field of data science, and will this RAG role, is it separate, or will the role I apply in the data science, will RAG be a part of it, or how does.
PAUL: You see, data science is a very generic term when you say it.
Aaryan Gupta: Okay.
PAUL: Okay, really, it's very hard to say. I've seen people
PAUL: called data scientific of working with Excel sheets. So, really, like, so now you have to understand what is your skill set.
PAUL: So, like, for example, like, Python, stats, machine learning, okay, now, as you have worked on machine learning projects, as you will be learning RAG, so you have to understand it based on the skill set. So, every JD will be having that, yes, these are the requirements. So, like, the profile can be deep learning, engineer. You know deep learning, yes, you can apply
PAUL: If the rule is simply AI engineer. AI engineer means you have to look into the JT and then, again, the skills that they are looking for. So really don't ask the rule, rather than look into the JT and try to understand the requirements.
PAUL: On paper.
Aaryan Gupta: Got your point, got your point. So these are, like, interrelated to each other, like.
PAUL: Very similar, like, Gen AI engineer, then the expectation is that you should be knowing a very good knowledge about rags and LLMs. That is. Now, that company might be built in somewhere. There are very less companies who are building LLM in India. Very less. Probably, like, less than 10, I can say.
Aaryan Gupta: Makes sense, makes sense. So, okay, secondly, I want to know if you're, teaching also about the tokenization and this,
PAUL: C.
Aaryan Gupta: Okay.
PAUL: Tokenization, I'll be talking from the GenAI perspective. I won't be talking, tokenization from the NLP part. Because in NLP, really, for tokenization, there are so many other techniques, because that becomes the NLP fundamentals. Those things are totally deprecated in 2025 right now, I am speaking.
PAUL: Okay, so that part comes the funder. So that part I'll… I will be talking, the tokenization and the embedding from this particular respect.
PAUL: Okay, otherwise, if you know about such concepts, like bag awards, concurrent metrics, okay, so really, that is not important. Probably in 2016 or 15 research, it was done.
PAUL: Okay, so that's why. Only the things which are applicable for your thing, that I'll be talking about. It's not about the history. Right now, the core part is how to build a rack.
PAUL: And how to make it better, and what are the different techniques that we'll be focusing on much more.
Aaryan Gupta: But this will cover the overall idea of the deployment, in terms of tokenization, understanding… understanding of the tokenization, right?
PAUL: Yes, tokenai is a very small component of our.
Aaryan Gupta: Okay, great.
PAUL: Okay, so don't worry about that, that will be covered.
Aaryan Gupta: Okay, so, thing… the third and last thing is that, I have no knowledge of NLP, and since you, Krish, and you have also provided the free course as the prerequisite, which is… I'm very grateful for that, thank you. And so, I wanted to understand how…
Aaryan Gupta: much in terms of NLP should I go through that course? Like, do I need to do the full of that course before this rag thing?
PAUL: Are you good in Python, first of all, tech?
Aaryan Gupta: Python, yeah. So, Python I'm good at. I've done modular programming and machine learning also.
PAUL: If you have done that, that is a very similar approach. Here also, like, based on packaging and others, few things have changed. But yes, then you're good to go. Really, you don't need to dive into those NLP concepts, but really, if you're going for an interview, you have to know about the few concepts of transformers and other stuff. Okay, now those things you can actually cover.
Aaryan Gupta: Okay, just the basic idea of what it does, right?
PAUL: See, it's not about basic, try to go in depth. If you're going for an interview, you have to think. If somebody's asking about transformers, you have to speak continuously for 30 to 40 minutes.
Aaryan Gupta: Okay, great.
PAUL: Okay, it means that that is the main game-changing thing, so don't tell me 2 minutes what is transformers, okay? Then, that's why. You have to understand the entire architecture, break it, keep it as notes to you, okay? Write that notes 3 times so that you remember for interview.
PAUL: Okay, so that's why. The better you explain, because everyone will be asking. Because if you're going for a GenAI role, Transformers is important. If you are going for a data science role, transformers are important.
Aaryan Gupta: Yeah, so in a nutshell, NLP and this data science goes hand-in-hand, it's kind of a part of it.
PAUL: Yes. Muhammad is telling, memorize attention, all you need, research current. There is one research paper that you have to always keep in your mind. Attention is all you need.
Aaryan Gupta: Yeah, the last thing, sorry, I said the third will be my last thing. Okay.
Aaryan Gupta: I want to know, how do you keep up with the research thing? Like, I understand you, have mentioned that you need to, go with the research paper, you read the research paper. But now, since small changes also keep up coming, and multiple research papers are there, so, like.
PAUL: Here's the activity.
Aaryan Gupta: You'll see…
PAUL: community.
Aaryan Gupta: Okay.
PAUL: every research paper, you won't be converting it into a piece.
Aaryan Gupta: Okay, so…
PAUL: A simple example I am giving.
PAUL: If you know about deep learning. Okay. Okay, in deep learning, there is a simple concept called as, activation function.
Aaryan Gupta: Okay.
PAUL: everybody uses, like, ReLU submarz and sigmoid, these, like, commons, 10H. Okay, but in activation functions, there are more than 200 in such papers.
PAUL: No, really. See, if you're following research, it's something like an old habit. If you start now, it's a hard thing, really.
Aaryan Gupta: Okay.
PAUL: It's a very hard thing, because according to research, we have seen that if something is implemented in one paper, it's not really that author is using that in the next paper. He might feel that the thing that he has done is bad, and probably some other author has done better, and he will implement his one.
PAUL: So, it's a common thing in research. So, really, like, you have to just look into the top papers only. Don't link into. So, for example, for every type, there is some type of conference, and every year from that conference, what are the top 5 papers, top 10 papers, just look into that.
PAUL: That is the high-level information. And otherwise, you can subscribe to a few, I think signals are there, alphasignal.io is there. They send you what is the recent research that is going. You can every day look into their mails. From there, you will get to know what is the current research.
Aaryan Gupta: Okay, thank you, thank you so much. And, since, with machine learning, do I also need to do deep learning as well, while applying for an
Aaryan Gupta: Is it really necessary?
PAUL: hey, if you can do it, do it. Because, again, like, it's an old stuff, so people might think that you shouldn't. That's why.
Aaryan Gupta: Okay, great.
PAUL: Because… If you think at the end of the day, the entire Transformers…
Aaryan Gupta: Okay.
PAUL: It is deep learning.
Aaryan Gupta: Oh, okay.
PAUL: Transformers is at… because when you really don't know the exact number of parameters, okay, and you need to train them, that is deep learning, that's why.
PAUL: So, entire Transformers comes under deep learning.
PAUL: Okay, so if you really think about a network that way.
PAUL: Okay, so, yes, I will say that's why the fundamentals are important at any point of time.
PAUL: Okay.
Aaryan Gupta: Thank you so much, Paul. Thank you.
PAUL: All right, Ari.
PAUL: Next, I think only we have 3 participants, so… Not even 3, I think.
PAUL: 2, so… per one…
Pavankanna Polavarapu: hype.
PAUL: Kana, okay, yeah, Pabankana and KD Vishnu.
PAUL: Yes.
Pavankanna Polavarapu: Hi, Paul, am I audible?
Pavankanna Polavarapu: Yeah, Paul, I just want to keep this really quick.
Pavankanna Polavarapu: As you have already covered the interview part, I am currently working as a dbt admin. I just want to switch to Jennai Adult work.
PAUL: Alright.
Pavankanna Polavarapu: Yeah, you have covered, in terms of one year experience, I have D plus ES experience, do I have to go anything deep?
Pavankanna Polavarapu: the topic.
PAUL: Like, with dbt, like, what are the other things that you were using in your day-to-day work? Like, from the main AI part, if I'm talking about anything with respect to.
Pavankanna Polavarapu: No, in terms of AI, we are not using anything.
PAUL: Only UK. Then you have to.
Pavankanna Polavarapu: Yeah, transformation, pipelines we are managing.
PAUL: I know, I know, dbt for ETL pipelines, they have been widely used.
Pavankanna Polavarapu: Hmm…
PAUL: Okay, so what you can do… but you have to know the fundamentals if you want to really switch into the AI one, that's why.
Pavankanna Polavarapu: Yeah.
PAUL: Python and other stuff, very, very important, because with.
Pavankanna Polavarapu: Yeah, Python, I do… I do Python.
PAUL: and then machine learning, the basics of NLP, and then the things that I'll be teaching you in this course.
Pavankanna Polavarapu: Okay.
Pavankanna Polavarapu: Will it be enough, like, the… that's.
PAUL: Listen, I cannot say it is enough. Enough is something I want, nobody can commit. I can say that this is the bare minimum.
Pavankanna Polavarapu: Yeah, yeah. No, no, no, in terms of topics, I am saying, so that I can explore more.
PAUL: Topics, I can say that yes, but there are other things also. Like, 3 years of experience, my idea will be you should know more. You should be good with APIs, you should be good with one cloud service at least. So, these are a few things.
PAUL: That comes. I told you the bare minimum, but yes, like, you need more skills. Three years, a lot of expectation, really, right now, in 2025 market.
Pavankanna Polavarapu: Okay. And one more question. Recently, I, I followed, Chris,
Pavankanna Polavarapu: RAG crash course, in that, he used one, embedding model. I tried to use some other open… open source model, I am facing some issues there.
Pavankanna Polavarapu: Will I be able, after completing the course, will I be able to judge a model?
Pavankanna Polavarapu: Which model is better.
PAUL: Can you really don't need to judge a modeling?
PAUL: Some people will be there in the research field who have already done it for you most of the times.
PAUL: Okay, so, I will be telling you how to select models, from there you will get a very good idea, like, which one. And probably, like, if you are working with local models, so sometimes what happens, that if you are selecting any model in your local machine, it might need a lot of RAM.
PAUL: Okay, so probably 28GB RAM, 32GB if you're working with 8 billion parameter models. So it becomes a little bit problematic. So at that particular point of time, if you don't have the system configuration, I will suggest try to stick to API-based, solutions, rather than directly executing it in your local.
Pavankanna Polavarapu: Okay.
PAUL: Okay, so in this course, all these things in detail we'll be talking about.
Pavankanna Polavarapu: Okay, okay. Okay. Thank you, Paul. That is… that is it from me. Thank you.
PAUL: Alright, then KV, Vishnu.
K V Vishnu Vardhana Chary: Yeah. Hi, Paul.
PAUL: Hmm.
K V Vishnu Vardhana Chary: Thanks for your time, and first of all, I'd like to thank you and Krish Mayank for the course. This seems to be really interesting.
K V Vishnu Vardhana Chary: My one and only question is, like, are we also going to discuss on the architecture standpoint? Like, since we are talking about AWS, right? We have SageMaker, Bidrock, so…
K V Vishnu Vardhana Chary: Are we going to discuss on the data transformation pipelines and Gen AI.
PAUL: No, no, no, no, no. See, I will be talking about the GenA architecture, but nothing with respect to data transformation pipelines.
PAUL: I will be having some amount of data. On top of that, I'll be doing preprocessing using data parsers, very specifically, because for RAG, really, now, some type of document came into the picture. Okay, now that will be enough. From where I got that document.
PAUL: How I'm bringing it, that is not part. Like, how the data engineering team is working, I own a bit. I have the data, I'll be picking up from some type of data sources, probably ASC or anywhere. Now, I'll be pulling that data, now from there my work starts.
K V Vishnu Vardhana Chary: Understood. And when we are talking about any use cases, when we are, working with some, companies, right, everybody have their own architecture. Probably.
K V Vishnu Vardhana Chary: So, to what extent? See, when we talk about, the architecture, it should also comply with the production environment as well. So, are we also discussing some production, enablements as well? What is the.
PAUL: It's the proof.
PAUL: Production architecture, and…
PAUL: Now, the application-level architecture, I can tell you. Production-level architecture, it takes changes with time. You cannot say this architecture, it's fixed. It's an incremental process. Okay, so from rack perspective, if you are putting your rack into production, that particular architecture I will be telling you. But see, I'll be focusing on the AI part.
PAUL: I'm only focusing on the STLC part, your product.
K V Vishnu Vardhana Chary: Understood.
PAUL: Okay, because in HDLC, there are other things also. Now, if you ask me how to integrate my database, that's not my job, really. I'll be telling you how to integrate your vector database.
PAUL: Okay, so that's why, you have to understand that part. I'll be focusing on the AI part, and the rest of the things, the things that you have been doing, those logic really don't change.
PAUL: Similarly for deployment, the logic really doesn't change a lot. It's just 10-15% change. REST, 80% are those rules which have been used in NCS, that's right.
K V Vishnu Vardhana Chary: That makes sense, yeah. That was the only question, Paul. Thank you so much, yeah.
PAUL: Alright, so it's done.
PAUL: So, it's already 1.38. When is the other batch? Is there a batch in this, ID, Chrissa or mine, do you know?
Krish Naik: You have time, from 3 o'clock, I guess it is.
PAUL: I'll get 3 o'clock, alright.
Mayank Aggarwal: I think… let me check one.
Krish Naik: Tua? Yeah, yeah, two, Paul, so let's…
PAUL: Okay, then, see, guys, we have only 15 minutes, so quickly I'll be taking the questions, okay? So, Naga, there is Rajesh. Quickly, guys, please let me know. We have very less time.
Naga: Yeah, I have a question, here, Paul, Delta Live Table, see, the latest, thing happening is the Delta Live Table.
Naga: And.
PAUL: satellite activism.
Mayank Aggarwal: Another data engineering concept, actually, so not valid here. I have taught that data table and everything in my data engineering bootcamp.
Mayank Aggarwal: So it is in Databricks and, like, others as well. Not valid with RAG and AI, actually.
Naga: So, in my architecture, right, so basically.
Naga: there are some, policy kind of documents, and we use the Databricks Autoloader to pull the data into a bronze layer, okay? And from there, some cleansing happens in the silver layer, and the vector metadata is pushed into gold layer, okay?
Naga: And, we have a Redis, vector store, Redis cache.
Naga: And then we create the HNSW index on embedding, and then, the… there is a chat GPT kind of a prompt from where, the OpenAI.
Mayank Aggarwal: Hopefully I can improve.
Naga: And from there, we pull this, data.
Naga: And, there are some chunks, like, you know, like 515, kind of, overlap chunks, based on that text embeddings, we pull the data. So, in those, there are some delta live tables, also, as.
Mayank Aggarwal: That is, that is understood, but the point is that, Dental activity, what you are saying, is part of VIN data bootcamp.
Mayank Aggarwal: So, not big data bootcamp, like, the big data concepts, right? So, of course, like, the idea is that AI helps you in some part of your software journey, so you are integrating AI, like, you are following the Medellin architecture, and in that, in the gold layer, you are calling the drag and AI, right?
Mayank Aggarwal: So that goal level part will become, of course, correct, but in this course or batch, we are not teaching about delta table or anything, because
Mayank Aggarwal: That's totally a big data concept. That has nothing to do with AI RAG or anything.
Mayank Aggarwal: So…
Naga: players.
Mayank Aggarwal: That, I guess, like, again, anytime I start a new course on big data, either you can take that up, or, like, of course, you can, like, read that on your own, and the silver to gold layer, when that is getting created, that concept will be not clear to you.
Mayank Aggarwal: So…
Naga: Go ahead.
Mayank Aggarwal: That is the idea, okay?
Naga: Yeah, agreed. So, Redis Vector Store, should, should we buy that also, like, as a,
Mayank Aggarwal: So you don't have to buy anything as of now, just wait for your mentor to tell. We try to have the free trial only. That is for caching, vector store, we have PineGo, like, we have way lot of things which we can get for free, so we try for that unnecessarily, because we don't want you to spend any money, any more money, right?
Mayank Aggarwal: So, anything which you will have to buy, the mentor will know before the class. Right now, don't do anything.
Naga: Yeah, I really want to be… I really appreciate the discussion and very happy. If I can be part of your team to the development, I'll be really.
Mayank Aggarwal: We will be hiring, so for sure we will do that, but first, I think once the batch commences and we see that, okay, someone is having the idea, he's understanding the product, because we have multiple products in the pipeline.
Mayank Aggarwal: Right? So, yeah, that's the case, and of course, we will be happy to, like, also hire from the batch only, so surely, no worries.
Naga: Yeah, thank you so much, Mank, and thank you.
PAUL: Alright, so next…
Rajesh S: Hey, hi guys, Radhusi.
Rajesh S: Yeah, thank you so much. Thanks, thanks for your patience of answering all these Q&As. Thank you so much. It's been a great, listening here. I mean, for me, like, I've been, like, last two, three, four hours, like, just listening, and I got…
Rajesh S: I got such good information by, with this conversation itself. I'll make it very short. So, first thing, like, I'm from a, enterprise revolutioning thing, so would you also offer any, far-right trainings, so that, just checking if there is any…
Mayank Aggarwal: Yeah, we do that. We do take corporate trainings, like.
Rajesh S: Pope.
Mayank Aggarwal: We have been, like, tighten all through this.
Rajesh S: Oh.
Mayank Aggarwal: I'll do everything.
Rajesh S: Okay. Okay, can someone help me in reaching out to the…
Krish Naik: Yeah, Rajesh, I will drop you an email, email…
Rajesh S: Thank you, Kendall. Thank you so much.
Mayank Aggarwal: Or you can just, yeah, I think, I forget the Christ's email. So just you, if you have a requirement, you can just reach out to us. I'm sharing my email, and I think you must have Chrisser or the team's email as well. Just reach out to us on that, yeah.
Rajesh S: Yeah, yeah, thank you. And the other question was, like, so I've been seeing the courses here and there, right? The courses that we are sharing on Udemy and Udemy, like, many courses I see. So, would the concepts covered there will be, will be deferred from here, or it would be the…
Rajesh S: Similar kind of concepts that we cover here, or something like that.
Rajesh S: Bye!
Mayank Aggarwal: We… the topics, sorry, the concepts got taught in the live classes, they are a lot more in-depth, plus it's a hands-on project, which are not there in the recorded courses via YouTube or Udemy.
Mayank Aggarwal: So, that's the case, and normally we have hackathons or some competitions as well, time to time in the live classes. So, that is the whole idea. Like, you will see the discussion and how we are helping you out in everything, right?
Mayank Aggarwal: So, yeah, that's the whole idea in the live class, majorly.
Rajesh S: So, two more questions, I'll be very short. So, we are actually working on the agentic thing and ride. I had some POCs on racks, and because I saw the two hours video that Chris had uploaded, and it was very good, it helped me a lot, basically.
Rajesh S: So, clearing my doubts and, good one, but, so is there any session where, it's like kind of a review session, like, where the POCs that we build could be a review, like, okay, would it be a standard one, or are the guardrails applied, or some kind of a tech review session?
Rajesh S: I mean, would it be anywhere in the coastline? And this.
Mayank Aggarwal: don't have it as of now, though we do reach, like, in the end, we make sure that we answer your question and guide you based on the same.
Mayank Aggarwal: But, specific those sessions we don't have, specifically because, A, you must be seeing how we are answering the doubt, so we want to make sure that everyone gets full attention, and when we have that kind of a…
Mayank Aggarwal: session, like, there are lots of entries, so people are not able to get. So, but yeah, we will, of course, we will try to incorporate that in future. We will love to see that if somehow we can help more and more students. So we are preparing, and we are in the works of preparing the pipeline for that.
Rajesh S: Oh, okay, okay. I think one last one, like, I see majority of these videos or documentation, I see RAG as in a vector store, in a kind of a, in-memory kind of things. So,
Rajesh S: Would it be, like, in… when we say production-ready, haystack production ready? So, so would it be, covered in our session to process this, index, the vectored, vectored, databases also, like.
Mayank Aggarwal: If you're asking about where FP will be teaching you, like, again, not all will be in memory.
Mayank Aggarwal: Surely they will be persistent, and we will be using it like a proper DB, like…
Mayank Aggarwal: So, that's the whole idea, and yes, they will be production ready, like, we ourselves are using it, we are guiding and training people in that, so that will be the case.
Rajesh S: Thank you, thank you, Mang. Thanks, team, thank you so much. Thank you. That's it, I have. Thank you, bye.
Mayank Aggarwal: No, I agree.
nikhi: I just have one last question.
Mayank Aggarwal: You know?
nikhi: Hi, this I put my question in the chat as well. This is my last question is.
nikhi: If.
Mayank Aggarwal: Can you ask it quickly?
nikhi: Yeah, so for the LLM path, so we'll be using a lot of LLMs. Is there…
nikhi: a session where we'll talk about downloading an LLM, and then working on it, and productionizing that downloaded version. Because I'm doing a POC as of now. I'm building a small language model for an enterprise.
nikhi: I've done all the bootcamps, all the courses for deep learning, machine learning, and all of it, thanks to Krish. So…
nikhi: I'm just doing a POC, doing a versus comparison of building an SLM for a company, or using a downloaded LLM because of the data security or data perspective.
PAUL: Yes, through Olama, we'll be doing it. We'll be downloading a few local LLMs or from Hugging Fist, that is, yes, that we can do.
PAUL: Okay, but, really, like, it won't be elements. It will be.
Mayank Aggarwal: Creating a SLM, I think, is something which is not part, and it doesn't go with that.
nikhi: I'm not part of this course, I'm just doing it on my own. I'm just trying to see, you know, also do this downloaded version of LLM and then productionalizing it. So that is what I'm expecting from the course. SLM, I'm doing it on my own.
Mayank Aggarwal: Yeah, so we will show you how to use local LLM, and, like, for example, GPT OSS, Llama 3.2, all of these things, so that you get a taste that, okay, what exactly and how they work. So, on top of that, then you can do your fine-tuning, create your own SLM. You will get an idea, like, that's our main aim here.
Mayank Aggarwal: So, that we will be covering, but yes, training an SLM directly, or, like, working a lot on the local LLM, that won't be the part, because, again, we try to make sure that it is valid for majority, and majority is using LLMs which are provided first, right?
nikhi: Definitely, definitely. Just explaining that part would help me compare That'll be really helpful.
Mayank Aggarwal: Sure, sure, you can ask the questions once we will be covering that topic, and we will be happy to answer based off of our knowledge.
nikhi: Again, as everyone mentioned, again, I'm echoing it again. You guys are doing a great job. Thank you, Krish. Thank you, Mike.
Mayank Aggarwal: Thank you.
Krish Naik: Okay, guys, so hard stop, we have to close the session,
Krish Naik: In the next session, we have something else coming up, because LLMOps batch is going to happen from 2 o'clock. So, thank you, I hope you liked the induction session. Please make sure to post your learnings in LinkedIn. That will help us organically reach many people, because we are focusing more on affordability. We don't do any digital marketing and all.
Krish Naik: So as more as you suggest to other people, it'll be very much beneficial for us. And I hope people will get the right quality of education.
Krish Naik: You know, instead of wasting $10,000, $5,000 like that, you'll be able to just get it in hardly within less than $100. So, thank you, everyone, and thank you, Meng. Thank you, Paul. I think Paul has taken the entire session, so, appreciate Paul taking all the doubt clearing session in induction.
Krish Naik: But thank you, guys. This was from our team. Bye-bye. I will see you all in the next session. Thank you, guys. Bye-bye. Take care.
PAUL: Yeah, thank you.